<feats stores='system' systems=''>
<Feat ID="1" Author="" Copyright="COPYRIGHT 2000, Brendan Quinn" Reference="Net Book of Feats">
  <Name>Accurate Attack</Name>
  <Types Types="">
  </Types>
  <Prerequisites>Base attack bonus +3 or higher</Prerequisites>
  <Benefit>Choose a single weapon of any type.  When using this weapon, you may substitute your dexterity modifier in place of your strength modifier for the purpose of determining your ability based attack bonus.</Benefit>
  <Special>This feat can be taken multiple times, each time it applies to a new weapon. This feat can also be taken as a fighter's bonus feat.</Special>
  <Source ID="0"/>
</Feat>
<Feat ID="2" Author="" Copyright="COPYRIGHT 2001, Carl Cramér" Reference="Net Book of Feats">
  <Name>Additional Domain</Name>
  <Types Types="">
  </Types>
  <Prerequisites>Knowledge (religion) 8 ranks.</Prerequisites>
  <Benefit>You acquire one additional domain from your deity, including the domain power and access to all domain spells.</Benefit>
  <Special>This feat can be taken several times for additional domains. It does not stack; each time it is chosen, you get to pick a new domain from those available to your religion.</Special>
  <Notes>Remember that you do not gain any additional domain spells, so what you gain is more spells to share the single domain spell slot and a domain power.</Notes>
  <Source ID="0"/>
</Feat>
<Feat ID="3" Author="" Copyright="COPYRIGHT 2001, Rebecca Glenn (Becky)" Reference="Net Book of Feats">
  <Name>Aerobatics</Name>
  <Types Types="">
  </Types>
  <Benefit>You improve your maneuverability class by one step when using any ability to fly. This includes flying mounts if you have the ability to guide them (i.e., Ride). You also increase your base flying speed by +5.</Benefit>
  <Source ID="0"/>
</Feat>
<Feat ID="4" Author="" Copyright="COPYRIGHT 2001, Carl Cramér" Reference="Net Book of Feats">
  <Name>Aggressive Casting</Name>
  <Types Types="">
  </Types>
  <Prerequisites>Concentration skill.</Prerequisites>
  <Benefit>When you cast a spell using defensive casting and fail the concentration check, you may opt not to lose the spell but instead trigger an attack of opportunity just as if you had cast the spell in the ordinary fashion.</Benefit>
  <Notes>If you are hit by an attack of opportunity triggered because you failed the above concentration check, you must still make yet another concentration check or lose the spell because of the damage.</Notes>
  <Source ID="0"/>
</Feat>
<Feat ID="5" Author="" Copyright="COPYRIGHT 2000, System Reference Document" Reference="System Reference Document">
  <Name>Alertness</Name>
  <Types Types="">
  </Types>
  <Benefit>The character gets a +2 bonus on all Listen checks and Spot checks.</Benefit>
  <Special>The master of a familiar gains the Alertness feat whenever the familiar is within arm's reach.</Special>
  <Source ID="0"/>
</Feat>
<Feat ID="6" Author="" Copyright="COPYRIGHT 2001, Michael J. Kletch" Reference="Net Book of Feats">
  <Name>Alternate Attack</Name>
  <Types Types="">
  </Types>
  <Prerequisites>Base attack bonus 3+</Prerequisites>
  <Benefit>If you are wielding two weapons, you may forego your extra attack (or attacks, if you have Improved Two-Weapon Fighting) with the off-hand weapon.  If you do so, you may split your normal attack freely between the two weapons.  Attacks with the weapon in your primary hand have no penalty, and attacks with the weapon your off hand suffer the normal -4 penalty for off-hand attacks unless you also have Ambidexterity.  This feat can be used if one 'weapon' is an unarmed strike.</Benefit>
  <Normal>If you wield two weapons, you get all of the penalties for Fighting with Two Weapons as described on pages 124-5 in Core Rulebook I.  The specific wording is "If you wield a second weapon in your off hand, you can get an extra attack per round with that weapon".  You must use you primary weapon for all attacks other than the one extra attack.  It does not specifically say that you only get that penalty if you use the extra attack.  "Fighting in this way..." refers to wielding two weapons.</Normal>
  <Notes>Some DMs may interpret this rule from Core Rulebook I in a different fashion, and allow this ability freely to all characters without the need to spend a feat.  This feat merely outlines that there are two possible interpretations and documents the version that would require additional explanation.</Notes>
  <Source ID="0"/>
</Feat>
<Feat ID="7" Author="" Copyright="COPYRIGHT 2000, System Reference Document" Reference="System Reference Document">
  <Name>Ambidexterity</Name>
  <Types Types="">
  </Types>
  <Prerequisites>Dex 15+.</Prerequisites>
  <Benefit>The caracter ignores all penalties for using an off hand. The character is neither left-handed nor right-handed.</Benefit>
  <Normal>Without this feat, a character who uses his or her off hand suffers a -4 penalty to attack rolls, ability checks, and skill checks. For example, a right-handed character wielding a weapon with her left hand suffers a -4 penalty to attack rolls with that weapon.</Normal>
  <Special>This feat helps offset the penalty for fighting with two weapons.</Special>
  <Source ID="0"/>
</Feat>
<Feat ID="8" Author="" Copyright="COPYRIGHT 2000, Michael J. Kletch" Reference="Net Book of Feats">
  <Name>Ambitious Leader</Name>
  <Types Types="">
  </Types>
  <Prerequisites>Cha 13+, Leadership</Prerequisites>
  <Benefit>When a character selects this feat, he or she selects either the cohort option or the follower option.  Any followers or cohorts gained through this feat are cumulative with those gained for Leadership, this feat, or other feats that grant followers or cohorts.
If the player selects the cohort option, the character gains two cohorts.  One has a maximum level as determined by the character's Leadership score.  The second cohort has a maximum level two experience levels lower.
If the player selects the follower option, he or she gains 1.5 times the number of followers specified by his or her Leadership score.</Benefit>
  <Special>A character may gain this feat multiple times, and the effects are cumulative.</Special>
  <Source ID="0"/>
</Feat>
<Feat ID="9" Author="" Copyright="COPYRIGHT 2001, Anne Bernardo, Sigfried Trent" Reference="Net Book of Feats">
  <Name>Anything Goes Combat</Name>
  <Types Types="">
  </Types>
  <Prerequisites>Int 13+, Dex 13+</Prerequisites>
  <Benefit>You are the master of the improvised weapon. You treat any object, including weapons you are not proficient with, as a simple melee weapon using the stats listed in this feat instead of the stats usually used for that object or weapon.  You may still use weapons you have proficiency with using the stats listed in the PHB.  Determine the size of the object or weapon and use the stats listed here.

Size    Damage   Threat  Crit  Reach
Tiny    1D2      20      X2    5
Small   1D4      20      X2    5
Medium  1D6      20      X2    5
Large   1D8      20      X2    5
Huge    1D10     20      X2    5

If the DM determines that there is no way the object in question could do regular damage it instead deals subdual damage.  Additionally any object used as a weapon via this feat can deal subdual damage at your discretion without penalty</Benefit>
  <Special>You may not take weapon feats applied to these weapons.  For instance you cannot take (weapon focus anything goes combat) or (weapon focus beer mug).</Special>
  <Notes>the Anime, Ranma one half and the antics of Jackie Chan inspired this feat.  It represents to find a way of using almost any object as a combat weapon by being creative and talented in the arts of mayhem.</Notes>
  <Source ID="0"/>
</Feat>
<Feat ID="10" Author="" Copyright="COPYRIGHT 2001, Eric D. Harry" Reference="Net Book of Feats">
  <Name>Apothecary</Name>
  <Types Types="">
  </Types>
  <Benefit>You can create any poison following the craft rules using your Alchemy or Profession (herbalist) skills, with a DC equal to the save DC of the poison, except that each skill check represents one day's (rather than one week's) work.  Many poisons require more expensive or rare components, as decided by your DM.</Benefit>
  <Special>You must have an Alchemist's lab in order to create a poison.</Special>
  <Notes>Depending on your campaign, poison creation may be treated as a house rule based on your Alchemy or Profession (herbalist) skill, rather than a feat.  Alternatively, enterprising DMs could create a Craft (poison) skill that accomplishes the same effect.</Notes>
  <Source ID="0"/>
</Feat>
<Feat ID="11" Author="" Copyright="COPYRIGHT 2000, Bradley H. Bemis Jr." Reference="Net Book of Feats">
  <Name>Arcane Understanding</Name>
  <Types Types="">
  </Types>
  <Prerequisites>5 or more ranks in Knowledge (Arcana), Intelligence modifier of +3 or greater</Prerequisites>
  <Benefit>For each level gained, you can add a number of spells to your spellbook equal to your intelligence modifier.</Benefit>
  <Normal>At each level, the wizard gains two spells of any level that can be added to his or her spellbook.</Normal>
  <Source ID="0"/>
</Feat>
<Feat ID="12" Author="" Copyright="COPYRIGHT 2001, Carl Cramér" Reference="Net Book of Feats">
  <Name>Area Control</Name>
  <Types Types="">
  </Types>
  <Benefit>When you cast an area spell, you can select certain spaces under the area and declare that they are not to be affected. Creatures in this space avoid the spell's effect. An Area Control spell uses up a spell slot two level higher than the spell's actual level.</Benefit>
  <Source ID="0"/>
</Feat>
<Feat ID="13" Author="" Copyright="COPYRIGHT 2001, Carl Cramér, Eric D. Harry" Reference="Net Book of Feats">
  <Name>Armed Deflect Arrows</Name>
  <Types Types="">
  </Types>
  <Prerequisites>Weapon Focus, dexterity 13+.</Prerequisites>
  <Benefit>You gain the use of the Deflect Arrows feat, but can only use this ability when wielding a melee weapon that you have Weapon Focus with.</Benefit>
  <Notes>You can learn later feats for which Deflect Arrows is a prerequisites based on the 'virtual' feat learned with Armed Deflect Arrows, but you can then only use those feats when armed with a melee weapon that you have Weapon Focus with.</Notes>
  <Source ID="0"/>
</Feat>
<Feat ID="14" Author="" Copyright="COPYRIGHT 2001, Eric D. Harry" Reference="Net Book of Feats">
  <Name>Armed Flurry Of Blows</Name>
  <Types Types="">
  </Types>
  <Prerequisites>Monk level 3rd+.</Prerequisites>
  <Benefit>This feat expands on your Flurry of Blows ability, allowing you to flurry with any weapon that you are proficient in.  You must still use your base attack bonus (rather than your more favorable unarmed attack bonus) when using this feat.</Benefit>
  <Normal>Flurry of Blows can normally only be used in unarmed combat or when armed with a kama, nunchaku or siangham.</Normal>
  <Source ID="0"/>
</Feat>
<Feat ID="15" Author="" Copyright="COPYRIGHT 2001, B. Marcus Lindberg, Scott Metzger" Reference="Net Book of Feats">
  <Name>Armor Focus</Name>
  <Types Types="">
  </Types>
  <Prerequisites>Armor Proficiency (light)</Prerequisites>
  <Benefit>When a character wears a type of armor with which the character is proficient, the armor check penalty applies only to Balance, Climb, Escape Artist, Hide, Jump, Move Silently, Pick Pocket, and Tumble checks.</Benefit>
  <Normal>A character who is wearing armor with which she is not proficient suffers its armor check penalty on attack rolls and on all skill checks that involve moving, including Ride.</Normal>
  <Special>You can gain this feat multiple times. The effects does not stack. Each time you take the feat, it applies to a new type of armor.</Special>
  <Source ID="0"/>
</Feat>
<Feat ID="16" Author="" Copyright="COPYRIGHT 2001, B. Marcus Lindberg" Reference="Net Book of Feats">
  <Name>Armor Specialization</Name>
  <Types Types="">
  </Types>
  <Prerequisites>4 fighter levels. Armor Focus in the type of armor.</Prerequisites>
  <Benefit>When you are wearing the specified type of armor you get a +2 dodge bonus to your Armor Class.</Benefit>
  <Special>You can gain this feat multiple times. The effects does not stack. Each time you take the feat, it applies to a new type of armor.</Special>
  <Source ID="0"/>
</Feat>
<Feat ID="17" Author="" Copyright="COPYRIGHT 2001, Bradley H. Bemis Jr." Reference="Net Book of Feats">
  <Name>Armored Caster</Name>
  <Types Types="">
  </Types>
  <Prerequisites>Armor Proficiency (with the category of armor worn), Dex 13 +</Prerequisites>
  <Benefit>You can reduce your chance of arcane spell failure by 10%.</Benefit>
  <Special>You may take this feat multiple times, each time gaining an additional 10% reduction.</Special>
  <Source ID="0"/>
</Feat>
<Feat ID="18" Author="" Copyright="COPYRIGHT 2001, Eric D. Harry" Reference="Net Book of Feats">
  <Name>Armored Vigilance</Name>
  <Types Types="">
  </Types>
  <Prerequisites>Proficient in armor donned or removed.</Prerequisites>
  <Benefit>You can don, don hastily and remove armor in half the standard time.</Benefit>
  <Source ID="0"/>
</Feat>
<Feat ID="19" Author="" Copyright="COPYRIGHT 2000, Michael J. Kletch" Reference="Net Book of Feats">
  <Name>Battle Leader</Name>
  <Types Types="">
  </Types>
  <Prerequisites>Cha 13+, Leadership</Prerequisites>
  <Benefit>For this feat to have an effect, you must have a banner or standard that is recognizable to your followers and cohorts, and you must use this standard to urge, inspire or rally your troops.
All cohorts and followers that can directly see you or your banner gain a +1 morale bonus to attack and on saving throws versus all fear effects.
If either you or your banner falls, all followers and cohorts instead get a -2 penalty to attack and on saving throws versus all fear effects until you are restored, the standard is raised again or one minute elapses.</Benefit>
  <Source ID="0"/>
</Feat>
<Feat ID="20" Author="" Copyright="COPYRIGHT 2000, System Reference Document" Reference="System Reference Document">
  <Name>Blind-Fight</Name>
  <Types Types="">
  </Types>
  <Benefit>In melee, every time a character misses because of concealment, the character can reroll the miss chance percentile roll one time to see if the character actually hit.
An invisible attacker gets no bonus to hit the character in melee. That is, the character doesn't lose a Dexterity bonus to Armor Class, and the attacker doesn't get the usual +2 bonus. The invisible attacker's bonuses do still apply for ranged attacks, however.
The character suffers only half the usual penalty to speed for being unable to see. Darkness and poor visibility in general reduces the character's speed to three-quarters of normal, instead of one-half.</Benefit>
  <Source ID="0"/>
</Feat>
<Feat ID="37" Author="" Copyright="COPYRIGHT 2001, Eric D. Harry" Reference="Net Book of Feats">
  <Name>Blooded Killer</Name>
  <Types Types="">
  </Types>
  <Prerequisites>Death Attack (Assassin prestige class ability), base attack bonus +7 or higher.</Prerequisites>
  <Benefit>You add +2 to the DC of the Fortitude save made to resist your death attack.  Even if your opponent succeeds on his saving throw, you inflict +1d6 points of damage on your sneak attack.</Benefit>
  <Normal>The standard DC for an Assassin's death attack is 10 + assassin class level + Int bonus.</Normal>
  <Source ID="0"/>
</Feat>
<Feat ID="21" Author="" Copyright="COPYRIGHT 2001, Carl Cramér" Reference="Net Book of Feats">
  <Name>Body Combat</Name>
  <Types Types="">
  </Types>
  <Prerequisites>Improved Unarmed Strike, dexterity 15+.</Prerequisites>
  <Benefit>You gain the use of the Two-Weapon Fighting and Ambidexterity feats, but only when your off-hand weapon is an unarmed attack such as a kick, knee, elbow smash or head butt or an armored variant of an unarmed attack such as a gauntlet, steel boot, kneepad, elbow guard or helmet.</Benefit>
  <Special>You can learn later feats for which Ambidexterity or Two-Weapon fighting are prerequisites based on the 'virtual' feats learned with Body Combat, but you can then only use those feats when you fulfill the limitations of Body Combat.</Special>
  <Notes>Unarmed attacks are of a size code two less that the user, and so are always light weapons. With this feat, an armored boot, kneepad, elbow guard, helmeted head or similar object works like a gauntlet, with or without spikes, and they can all be used with this feat if you are proficient with them.</Notes>
  <Source ID="0"/>
</Feat>
<Feat ID="22" Author="" Copyright="COPYRIGHT 2001, Tyson Neumann" Reference="Net Book of Feats">
  <Name>Bonded Weapon</Name>
  <Types Types="">
  </Types>
  <Prerequisites>Base Attack Bonus +8, Improved Critical (with weapon), Proficient with Weapon, Weapon Focus (with weapon), Weapon Specialization (with weapon)</Prerequisites>
  <Benefit>Choose a single unique weapon.  For one month you train exclusively with that weapon, learning how to best wield that specific weapon most effectively.  During the training period, you may use no other weapons or you must repeat the process.  After the month of training, give the weapon a name to symbolize your intimate knowledge of the weapon. You gain an additional +2 to all attack rolls and +1 to damage with your  named weapon (this stacks with the weapon focus and weapon specialization bonuses).  You do not gain the bonuses or penalties of this feat when wielding a weapon of the same type, and suffer a -2 to all attack rolls with all other weapons.</Benefit>
  <Special>If ever your named weapon is destroyed or taken from your possession for more than a week, you must repeat the process of naming a weapon and continue to suffer the -2 to attack rolls with all weapons of a  different type. You may never have more than one bonded weapon.</Special>
  <Source ID="0"/>
</Feat>
<Feat ID="23" Author="" Copyright="COPYRIGHT 2001, Bradley H. Bemis Jr." Reference="Net Book of Feats">
  <Name>Bookworm</Name>
  <Types Types="">
  </Types>
  <Benefit>Gain a +2 modifier to any research based activities conducted in a library or laboratory.</Benefit>
  <Special>This feat stacks with all skill and research enhancements applicable</Special>
  <Source ID="0"/>
</Feat>
<Feat ID="24" Author="" Copyright="COPYRIGHT 2000, System Reference Document" Reference="System Reference Document">
  <Name>Brew Potion</Name>
  <Types Types="">
  </Types>
  <Prerequisites>Spellcaster level 3rd+.</Prerequisites>
  <Benefit>The character can create a potion of any spell of 3rd level or lower that the character knows and that targets a creature or creatures. Brewing a potion takes 1 day. When the character creates a potion, the character sets the caster level. The caster level must be sufficient to cast the spell in question and no higher than the character's own level. The base price of a potion is its spell level multiplied by its caster level multiplied by 50 gp. To brew a potion, the character must spend 1/25 of this base price in XP and use up raw materials costing half this base price.
When the character creates a potion, the character makes any choices that the character would normally make when casting the spell. Whoever drinks the potion is the target of the spell.
Any potion that stores a spell with a costly material component or an XP cost also carries a commensurate cost. In addition to the costs derived from the base price, the character must expend the material component or pay the XP when creating the potion.</Benefit>
  <Source ID="0"/>
</Feat>
<Feat ID="276" Author="" Copyright="COPYRIGHT 2000, System Reference Document" Reference="System Reference Document">
  <Name>By Attack</Name>
  <Types Types="">
  </Types>
  <Prerequisites>Ride skill, Mounted Combat.</Prerequisites>
  <Benefit>When the character is mounted and uses the charge action, the character may move and attack as with a standard charge and then move again (continuing the straight line of the charge). The character's total movement for the round can't exceed double the character's mounted speed. The character does not provoke an attack of opportunity from the opponent that the character attacks.</Benefit>
  <Source ID="0"/>
</Feat>
<Feat ID="25" Author="" Copyright="COPYRIGHT 2001, Carl Cramér" Reference="Net Book of Feats">
  <Name>Called Shot</Name>
  <Types Types="">
  </Types>
  <Prerequisites>Dexterity 13+.</Prerequisites>
  <Benefit>On your action, before making attack rolls for the round, you may choose to subtract a number from all attack rolls for the round and add the same number to all weapon damage rolls for dexterity-based attacks. This number may not exceed your base attack bonus. The penalty on attacks and bonus on damage apply until your next action.</Benefit>
  <Special>Creatures lacking an anatomy and thus immune to critical hits, are immune to this extra damage. Called shot can be used with ranged weapons at ranges up to 30 feet.</Special>
  <Notes>Dexterity-based attacks are attacks that use the dexterity modifier rather than the strength modifier for attack rolls; missile weapons, thrown weapons and weapons used with the Weapon Finesse feat. Called shot cannot be used with ranged touch attacks.</Notes>
  <Source ID="0"/>
</Feat>
<Feat ID="26" Author="" Copyright="COPYRIGHT 2001, Carl Cramér" Reference="Net Book of Feats">
  <Name>Camouflage</Name>
  <Types Types="">
  </Types>
  <Prerequisites>Hide skill</Prerequisites>
  <Benefit>You can apply your Hide skill to objects or even other creatures as a standard action.  Often this requires arranging scenery to provide superior concealment.  All normal Hide modifiers, including size, apply.  A creature hidden in this manner cannot move about without breaking concealment.
You can hide objects and weapons on a creature: use the size of the weapon to determine the hide modifiers.  A pat-down search allows the use of the Search skill with a +10 circumstance bonus.</Benefit>
  <Notes>Your DM may allow anyone to use the Hide skill for this, without requiring a feat.</Notes>
  <Source ID="0"/>
</Feat>
<Feat ID="27" Author="" Copyright="COPYRIGHT 2001, Sigfried Trent" Reference="Net Book of Feats">
  <Name>Campaigner</Name>
  <Types Types="">
  </Types>
  <Benefit>You can sleep in any kind of armor for any amount of time without suffering fatigue penalties or discomfort.  Other conditions such as sleeping on a hard surface, or with bed bugs, which are uncomfortable but not dangerous will likewise not prevent you from a good nights sleep.</Benefit>
  <Notes>Players seem to like doing this so why not have a feat for it.  It could work for the rugged soldier or a ranger sleeping in the rain.</Notes>
  <Source ID="0"/>
</Feat>
<Feat ID="28" Author="" Copyright="COPYRIGHT 2001, Bradley H. Bemis Jr." Reference="Net Book of Feats">
  <Name>Cannibalistic Casting</Name>
  <Types Types="">
  </Types>
  <Benefit>You can cast a spell by using a number of constitution points equal to the level of the spell rather than using a spell slot (this feat assumes you have run out of slots).  These lost points of constitution are considered ability score damage against your constitution score and are treated as such for all purposes.  0-level spells count as one spell level for the purpose of this feat.</Benefit>
  <Special>Spellcasters that must prepare spells are limited to selecting spells previously prepared and cast that day.</Special>
  <Source ID="0"/>
</Feat>
<Feat ID="29" Author="" Copyright="COPYRIGHT 2000, Bradley H. Bemis Jr." Reference="Net Book of Feats">
  <Name>Cantrip</Name>
  <Types Types="">
  </Types>
  <Prerequisites>Intel 13+, Knowledge (Arcana)</Prerequisites>
  <Benefit>Grants any individual the ability to know/understand up to their intelligence modifier's worth of cantrips (which they must locate/be trained in).  The character can use his selection of cantrips by preparing (as a wizard) and using one per day.  Anyone trying to cast a spell (even though it's just 0-level) must meet all of the requirements and suffer all of the penalties associated with the use of arcane magics.</Benefit>
  <Special>This feat may be taken multiple times; however, no additional cantrips can ever be learned (past the individuals intelligence modifier).  Each additional time this feat is taken, the caster may prepare one additional cantrip per day.  The total maximum number of cantrips that can be cast in a single day (regardless of the number of times this feat is taken), is also limited to the casters intelligence modifier.</Special>
  <Source ID="0"/>
</Feat>
<Feat ID="30" Author="" Copyright="COPYRIGHT 2001, Bradley H. Bemis Jr." Reference="Net Book of Feats">
  <Name>Cantriptification</Name>
  <Types Types="">
  </Types>
  <Prerequisites>Caster level of 3 or greater, 5 or more ranks of Knowledge (arcana)</Prerequisites>
  <Benefit>Instead of picking and choosing cantrips (o-level spells) for the day, you can freely use any cantrip available to you (known or in your spellbooks) up to the total number of cantrips you can cast per day.</Benefit>
  <Source ID="0"/>
</Feat>
<Feat ID="31" Author="" Copyright="COPYRIGHT 2001, Carl Cramér" Reference="Net Book of Feats">
  <Name>Channel Against Outsiders</Name>
  <Types Types="">
  </Types>
  <Prerequisites>Ability to turn or rebuke undead, Extra Turning.</Prerequisites>
  <Benefit>Select one group of outsiders (such as fire elementals, slaadi or devils) that are either hostile to your faith/alignment (for turning) or associated with your faith/alignment (for rebuking).  You can channel divine energy against this type of outsider to turn or rebuke them as if they were undead of twice their HD.  A cleric that turns undead also turns outsiders, and a cleric that rebukes undead also rebukes outsiders.  When turning outsiders, those whose modified hit dice are half your turning level or less are dismissed to their home plane rather than destroyed.</Benefit>
  <Special>On their home plane, you turn or rebuke these outsiders as undead of four times their HD, but there, they really can be destroyed instead of merely dismissed.  This feat can be taken several times.  It does not stack.  Each time, you may choose a new type of outsiders to turn or rebuke.</Special>
  <Source ID="0"/>
</Feat>
<Feat ID="32" Author="" Copyright="COPYRIGHT 2001, Eric D. Harry" Reference="Net Book of Feats">
  <Name>Channel Psionic Touch</Name>
  <Types Types="">
  </Types>
  <Prerequisites>Str 13+, Power Attack, and Psionic Weapon.</Prerequisites>
  <Benefit>You are able to manifest psionic touch powers through a held melee weapon, allowing you to make a standard armed attack and inflict normal weapon damage plus the effect of your psionic power on a successful strike.  Manifesting the power is still a standard action (unless you have the Quicken Power feat) and you must wait until your next attack action in order to make your armed attack.  When resolving your attack, compare your attack roll against your target's normal AC and AC against touch attacks.  If your attack roll fails to beat the target's normal AC but beats his or her AC against touch attacks, the power is discharged normally but the weapon inflicts no additional damage. Once the power is manifest your melee weapon holds the charge of the power exactly as if the power had been manifest in the normal manner.  You cannot pass a charged weapon to another character as doing so discharges your power.  Likewise, the power dissipates (without discharging) if the weapon is ever thrown or leaves your hand.</Benefit>
  <Normal>You can manifest a psionic touch power as either a touch attack (no armor, shield or natural armor bonus to AC) or a normal unarmed strike.</Normal>
  <Special>You cannot manifest personal psionic powers (like Claws of the Bear, Claws of the Vampire, etc.) with this feat.  For purposes of this feat, the weapon used to manifest your psionic touch power is immune to the effects of your power while it holds the charge of the power.</Special>
  <Source ID="0"/>
</Feat>
<Feat ID="33" Author="" Copyright="COPYRIGHT 2001, Eric D. Harry" Reference="Net Book of Feats">
  <Name>Channel Touch Spell</Name>
  <Types Types="">
  </Types>
  <Benefit>You can cast any of your touch spells through a held melee weapon, allowing you to make a standard armed attack and inflict normal weapon damage plus the effect of your spell on a successful strike.  Casting the spell is still a standard action (unless you have the Quicken Spell feat) and you must wait until your next attack action in order to make your armed attack.  When resolving your attack, compare your attack roll against your target's normal AC and AC against touch attacks.  If your attack roll fails to beat the target's normal AC but beats his or her AC against touch attacks, the spell is discharged normally but the weapon inflicts no additional damage.  Casting a touch spell in this manner uses up a spell slot one level higher than level of the spell cast.
Once the spell is cast your melee weapon holds the charge of the spell exactly as if the spell had been cast in the normal manner.  You cannot pass a charged weapon to another character as doing so discharges your spell.  Likewise, the spell dissipates (without discharging) if the weapon is ever thrown or leaves your hand.</Benefit>
  <Normal>You can discharge a touch spell as either a touch attack (no armor, shield or natural armor bonus to AC) or a normal unarmed strike.</Normal>
  <Source ID="0"/>
</Feat>
<Feat ID="56" Author="" Copyright="COPYRIGHT 2000, Bradley H. Bemis Jr." Reference="Net Book of Feats">
  <Name>Class Learning</Name>
  <Types Types="">
  </Types>
  <Benefit>You may choose a cross-class skill in which you have a certain knack.  You may treat this skill as if it were a class skill.</Benefit>
  <Special>This feat may be taken multiple times, choosing a new skill each time. You are still limited by level + 3 for the maximum number of skill points you may spend on this skill.</Special>
  <Source ID="0"/>
</Feat>
<Feat ID="57" Author="" Copyright="COPYRIGHT 2001, Carl Cramér" Reference="Net Book of Feats">
  <Name>Class Secrets</Name>
  <Types Types="">
  </Types>
  <Benefit>Pick one exclusive skill that is normally prohibited to your class.  You can now learn this skill as a cross-class skill.</Benefit>
  <Special>This feat can be picked several times.  It does not stack.  Each time, it applies to a new skill.</Special>
  <Notes>If you wish to learn the formerly prohibited skill as a class skill, you can pick this feat, and the Cross-Class Learning feat (from the netbook of feats) applicable to the same skill.</Notes>
  <Source ID="0"/>
</Feat>
<Feat ID="34" Author="" Copyright="COPYRIGHT 2000, System Reference Document" Reference="System Reference Document">
  <Name>Cleave</Name>
  <Types Types="">
  </Types>
  <Prerequisites>Str 13+, Power Attack.</Prerequisites>
  <Benefit>If the character deals a creature enough damage to make it drop (typically by dropping it to below 0 hit points, killing it, etc.), the character gets an immediate, extra melee attack against another creature in the immediate vicinity. The character cannot take a 5-foot step before making this extra attack. The extra attack is with the same weapon and at the same bonus as the attack that dropped the previous creature. The character can use this ability once per round.</Benefit>
  <Source ID="0"/>
</Feat>
<Feat ID="35" Author="" Copyright="COPYRIGHT 2000, Michael J. Kletch" Reference="Net Book of Feats">
  <Name>Cleave Asunder</Name>
  <Types Types="">
  </Types>
  <Prerequisites>Fracture, Cleave</Prerequisites>
  <Benefit>When attacking an opponent's weapon, shield or other held object, if the object is broken, you can immediately make another attack against the same opponent or another object he or she holds.  You can use this ability only once per round.</Benefit>
  <Source ID="0"/>
</Feat>
<Feat ID="36" Author="" Copyright="COPYRIGHT 2000, Carl Cramér" Reference="Net Book of Feats">
  <Name>Clinch</Name>
  <Types Types="">
  </Types>
  <Prerequisites>Base Attack +3, Dodge.</Prerequisites>
  <Benefit>Move in under the guard of an opponent standing within five feet, as a move-equivalent action. He gets an attack of opportunity against you while you do this. You don't actually move anywhere, just step slightly closer to your opponent, but you do get the benefit of the Mobility feat (if you have it). After you have moved in close, you get a +4 cover bonus to AC, and a +4 circumstance bonus to attack rolls against the opponent you closed in on. If you and your opponent is ever more than 5 feet away from each other, you lose this bonus. You also lose the bonus if you move in on or attack someone else.</Benefit>
  <Special>To use this feat your weapon must be of a size class two categories smaller than your opponent's. So a tiny dagger works against a medium-sized longsword, but not against a small shortsword. A natural weapon or unarmed attack has a size code two sizes smaller than the creature using it .</Special>
  <Notes>Roman shortswordsmen used this against longspears under king Pyrrhus. It was just successful enough to coin the term 'pyrrhic victory'.</Notes>
  <Source ID="0"/>
</Feat>
<Feat ID="38" Author="" Copyright="COPYRIGHT 2000, System Reference Document" Reference="System Reference Document">
  <Name>Combat Casting</Name>
  <Types Types="">
  </Types>
  <Benefit>The character gets a +4 bonus to Concentration checks made to cast a spell while on the defensive.</Benefit>
  <Source ID="0"/>
</Feat>
<Feat ID="39" Author="" Copyright="COPYRIGHT 2000, Michael J. Kletch" Reference="Net Book of Feats">
  <Name>Combat Focus</Name>
  <Types Types="">
  </Types>
  <Prerequisites>Dodge, Improved Initiative, base attack bonus of +5 or higher.</Prerequisites>
  <Benefit>On your action, before making attack rolls for a round, you may choose to focus your efforts against one opponent.  Against this opponent, you get a +2 bonus to attack and a +1 dodge bonus to Armor Class.  The +1 Armor Class bonus from Dodge must be applied to the same opponent for a total bonus of +2.  You have a -2 penalty to Armor Class against all other opponents.</Benefit>
  <Source ID="0"/>
</Feat>
<Feat ID="40" Author="" Copyright="COPYRIGHT 2000, Michael J. Kletch" Reference="Net Book of Feats">
  <Name>Combat Opportunist</Name>
  <Types Types="">
  </Types>
  <Prerequisites>Combat Reflexes, Weapon Focus with the particular weapon</Prerequisites>
  <Benefit>When you make an attack of opportunity, you may add sneak attack damage.  This ability can only be used once per round, and following this attack, you may not make any further Attacks of Opportunity until after your next action.  This may negate the benefits of Combat Reflexes for the current round.</Benefit>
  <Normal>Only the loss of Dex bonus to Armor Class or flanked status allow a character to add sneak attack damage.</Normal>
  <Special>You can take this feat multiple times.  Its effects do not stack.  Each time you take the feat, it applies to a new weapon.</Special>
  <Source ID="0"/>
</Feat>
<Feat ID="41" Author="" Copyright="COPYRIGHT 2000, System Reference Document" Reference="System Reference Document">
  <Name>Combat Reflexes</Name>
  <Types Types="">
  </Types>
  <Benefit>When foes leave themselves open, the character may make a number of additional attacks of opportunity equal to the character's Dexterity modifier. The character still may only make one attack of opportunity per enemy.
The character may also make attacks of opportunity while flat-footed.</Benefit>
  <Special>A rogue with the Combat Reflexes feat still can only make one attack of opportunity in a round if he uses his opportunist ability to make that attack.</Special>
  <Source ID="0"/>
</Feat>
<Feat ID="42" Author="" Copyright="COPYRIGHT 2000, Michael J. Kletch" Reference="Net Book of Feats">
  <Name>Combat Surge</Name>
  <Types Types="">
  </Types>
  <Prerequisites>Improved Initiative, base attack bonus of +2 or higher</Prerequisites>
  <Benefit>On your action, before making attack rolls for a round, you may choose to take a -4 penalty to your armor class until your next action.  If you do so, you will gain +2 to your initiative for the remainder of this combat.  The bonus begins on the next round. If the character takes the Refocus action, all bonuses gained from prior uses of this feat are lost.</Benefit>
  <Normal>A character without this feat can only modify his or her initiative situation with the Refocus full round action.</Normal>
  <Source ID="0"/>
</Feat>
<Feat ID="43" Author="" Copyright="COPYRIGHT 2000, Michael J. Kletch" Reference="Net Book of Feats">
  <Name>Combat Tactics</Name>
  <Types Types="">
  </Types>
  <Prerequisites>Int 13+, base attack bonus of +6 or higher.</Prerequisites>
  <Benefit>When using the full attack action in melee, you may give up one attack from your attack sequence.  You cannot sacrifice your last attack for the round in this way.  You add the base attack bonus from the sacrificed attack to the attack roll for your next attack in the round.  Other attack bonuses from the sacrificed attack, such as bonuses from magic, feats or Strength, are not carried over.  Combat Tactics can only be employed once per round.
If using two weapons or a double weapon, you may give up any one attack from any source.  You may not combine Combat Tactics with Flurry of Blows or another feat or ability with a similar mechanic.
Example: A 13th level fighter has three attacks in a round with base attack bonuses of +13/+8/+3.  Against a particular opponent, the +13 bonus may be give a good chance to hit, but the +8 bonus for the second attack is just not enough and the attack at +3 is almost useless.  Combat Tactics is used, and the second attack is sacrificed.  The third attack now has a +11 bonus to hit; the +8 is carried from the second attack and added to the +3 that the third attack would normally have.</Benefit>
  <Source ID="0"/>
</Feat>
<Feat ID="44" Author="" Copyright="COPYRIGHT 2001, Carl Cramér" Reference="Net Book of Feats">
  <Name>Concentration Spell</Name>
  <Types Types="">
  </Types>
  <Benefit>You can maintain a spell with a duration longer than one round through concentration.  You must start concentrating right after casting the spell, and, for as long as you keep it up, need not count time off the spell's duration.  After you stop maintaining the spell, it's normal duration resumes and then terminates as usual.  You cannot use this feat to maintain a spell past ten times normal duration nor can you resume concentration.  A Concentration Spell uses up a spell slot one level higher than the spell's normal level.</Benefit>
  <Source ID="0"/>
</Feat>
<Feat ID="45" Author="" Copyright="COPYRIGHT 2000, Bradley H. Bemis Jr." Reference="Net Book of Feats">
  <Name>Concerted Attack</Name>
  <Types Types="">
  </Types>
  <Prerequisites>Base attack +3 or better, Knowledge (Combat)</Prerequisites>
  <Benefit>You can direct the efforts of your allies to gain an additional bonus to flanking efforts.  When you are leading a flanking effort against a single opponent, your allies involved in the melee gain a +4 flanking bonus on the attack roll.</Benefit>
  <Normal>Gain a +2 on your attack roll when flanking</Normal>
  <Special>You must be able to effectively communicate with the other flanking members.</Special>
  <Source ID="0"/>
</Feat>
<Feat ID="46" Author="" Copyright="COPYRIGHT 2001, Bradley H. Bemis Jr." Reference="Net Book of Feats">
  <Name>Controlled Burst</Name>
  <Types Types="">
  </Types>
  <Benefit>When casting burst-based area of effect spells, you can reduce the affected area in increments of 5 ft.  You have total control over the radius, but not the direction.  A controlled burst spell takes up a spell slot one level higher.
Example: Using this feat, you can cast a small fireball into a square next to you without having it impact you or your comrades.</Benefit>
  <Source ID="0"/>
</Feat>
<Feat ID="47" Author="" Copyright="COPYRIGHT 2001, Tyson Neumann, Agustín Martín" Reference="Net Book of Feats">
  <Name>Counter Strike</Name>
  <Types Types="">
  </Types>
  <Prerequisites>Base Attack Bonus +5, Dex 15+, Dodge, Expertise, Combat Reflexes, Skilled Parry</Prerequisites>
  <Benefit>Whenever you have successfully avoided an attack through use of the Skilled Parry feat, you may make an attack of opportunity against the attacker provided you are not unarmed.</Benefit>
  <Special>You may make a Counter Strike provided you are not denied your Dexterity bonus to Armor Class and you still have an attack of opportunity available to use.  Counter Strike counts as an attack of opportunity and as such, the number of attacks of opportunity you have each round limits its usage.</Special>
  <Source ID="0"/>
</Feat>
<Feat ID="48" Author="" Copyright="COPYRIGHT 2000, System Reference Document" Reference="System Reference Document">
  <Name>Craft Magic Arms And Armor</Name>
  <Types Types="">
  </Types>
  <Prerequisites>Spellcaster level 5th+.</Prerequisites>
  <Benefit>The character can create any magic weapon, armor, or shield whose prerequisites the character meets. Enhancing a weapon, suit of armor, or shield takes 1 day for each 1,000 gp in the price of its magical features. To enhance a weapon, suit of armor, or shield, the character must spend 1/25 of its features' total price in XP and use up raw materials costing half of this total price.
The character can also mend a broken magic weapon, suit of armor, or shield if it is one that the character could make. Doing so costs half the XP, half the raw materials, and half the time it would take to enchant that item in the first place.
The weapon, armor, or shield to be enhanced must be a masterwork item that the character must provide. (Its cost is not included in the above cost.)</Benefit>
  <Source ID="0"/>
</Feat>
<Feat ID="49" Author="" Copyright="COPYRIGHT 2000, Bradley H. Bemis Jr." Reference="Net Book of Feats">
  <Name>Craft Magic Tattoo</Name>
  <Types Types="">
  </Types>
  <Prerequisites>Spellcaster level 9+, 5 or more ranks in Craft (Artist)</Prerequisites>
  <Benefit>You can apply your magic and artistry together to create a magic tattoo.  The tattoo is created to emulate the effects of a single spell as if it were a spell like ability.  The base price for a tattoo of this nature is spell level x caster level x 400gp.  Crafting a magic tattoo takes one day for each 1,000gp of its base price. To craft a magic tattoo, you and the recipient must each spend 1/25th of its base price in XP.  The creator must also use up raw materials costing half of the base price.</Benefit>
  <Special>The power of the tattoo can only be used once each day.  The caster level is based on the lowest caster level needed to cast the spell. If two or more magic tattoos are attempted on the same body (regardless of size), the magics will disrupt each other (i.e. you may never have more than one magic tattoo).  A magic tattoo can be removed using a remove curse cast at one level higher than the spell level of the spell effect granted by the tattoo (using heighten spell or a similar method).  The act of casting remove curse only takes away the magic.  The tattoo itself remains until removed through mundane methods.  The tattoo is treated as a Miscellaneous Magic Item for all other intents and purposes.</Special>
  <Source ID="0"/>
</Feat>
<Feat ID="50" Author="" Copyright="COPYRIGHT 2000, System Reference Document" Reference="System Reference Document">
  <Name>Craft Rod</Name>
  <Types Types="">
  </Types>
  <Prerequisites>Spellcaster level 9th+.</Prerequisites>
  <Benefit>The character can create any rod whose prerequisites the character meets. Crafting a rod takes 1 day for each 1,000 gp in its base price. To craft a rod, the character must spend 1/25 of its base price in XP and use up raw materials costing half of its base price.
Some rods incur extra costs in material components or XP as noted in their descriptions. These costs are in addition to those derived from the rod's base price.</Benefit>
  <Source ID="0"/>
</Feat>
<Feat ID="51" Author="" Copyright="COPYRIGHT 2000, System Reference Document" Reference="System Reference Document">
  <Name>Craft Staff</Name>
  <Types Types="">
  </Types>
  <Prerequisites>Spellcaster level 12th+.</Prerequisites>
  <Benefit>The character can create any staff whose prerequisites the character meets. Crafting a staff takes 1 day for each 1,000 gp in its base price. To craft a staff, the character must spend 1/25 of its base price in XP and use up raw materials costing half of its base price.
A newly created staff has 50 charges.
Some staffs incur extra costs in material components or XP as noted in their descriptions. These costs are in addition to those derived from the staff's base price.</Benefit>
  <Source ID="0"/>
</Feat>
<Feat ID="52" Author="" Copyright="COPYRIGHT 2000, System Reference Document" Reference="System Reference Document">
  <Name>Craft Wand</Name>
  <Types Types="">
  </Types>
  <Prerequisites>Spellcaster level 5th+.</Prerequisites>
  <Benefit>The character can create a wand of any spell of 4th level or lower that the character knows. Crafting a wand takes 1 day for each 1,000 gp in its base price. The base price of a wand is its caster level multiplied by the spell level multiplied by 750 gp. To craft a wand, the character must spend 1/25 of this base price in XP and use up raw materials costing half of this base price.
A newly created wand has 50 charges.
Any wand that stores a spell with a costly material component or an XP cost also carries a commensurate cost. In addition to the cost derived from the base cost, the character must expend fifty copies of the material component or pay fifty times the XP cost.</Benefit>
  <Source ID="0"/>
</Feat>
<Feat ID="53" Author="" Copyright="COPYRIGHT 2000, System Reference Document" Reference="System Reference Document">
  <Name>Craft Wondrous Item</Name>
  <Types Types="">
  </Types>
  <Prerequisites>Spellcaster level 3rd+.</Prerequisites>
  <Benefit>The character can create any miscellaneous magic item whose prerequisites the character meet. Enchanting a miscellaneous magic item takes 1 day for each 1,000 gp in its price. To enchant a miscellaneous magic item, the spellcaster must spend 1/25 of the item's price in XP and use up raw materials costing half of this price.
The character can also mend a broken miscellaneous magic item if it is one that the character could make. Doing so costs half the XP, half the raw materials, and half the time it would take to enchant that item in the first place.
Some wondrous items incur extra costs in material components or XP as noted in their descriptions. These costs are in addition to those derived from the item's base price. The character must pay such a cost to create an item or to mend a broken one.</Benefit>
  <Source ID="0"/>
</Feat>
<Feat ID="54" Author="" Copyright="COPYRIGHT 2000, Bradley H. Bemis Jr." Reference="Net Book of Feats">
  <Name>Create Camouflage</Name>
  <Types Types="">
  </Types>
  <Prerequisites>5 or more ranks in Hide, Knowledge of the terrain used</Prerequisites>
  <Benefit>You are so good at camouflaging yourself, that you can increase your level of concealment after 5 rounds of preparation.  When there is no concealment around you, you gain the effects of one-quarter concealment (10% miss chance).  When in a concealed position, you are concealed as if the level of concealment was one place better. When using this feat, you must make a successful hide check against a DC of 15 at the beginning of the encounter (before the enemy sees you).  The DC is adjusted by the DM for factors involved in your effort to camouflage yourself, such as your starting appearance/dress and the terrain involved.  Your Hide check can also be adjusted by taking more time to prepare.  Additional preparation time gains you a +1 modifier to your hide check for every additional 5 rounds of preparation past the required 5 rounds (to a maximum of +5). Each round that you attempt to take an action while camouflaged, your opponents can attempt a spot check.  This spot check is an opposed check against the score of your hide result.  Once spotted, you lose the benefit of this feat against your opponent for the remainder of the encounter.</Benefit>
  <Source ID="0"/>
</Feat>
<Feat ID="55" Author="" Copyright="COPYRIGHT 2001, Brian A. Smith" Reference="Net Book of Feats">
  <Name>Create Opportunity</Name>
  <Types Types="">
  </Types>
  <Prerequisites>Dex 15+, Combat Reflexes, BAB +3</Prerequisites>
  <Benefit>In lieu of ALL your attacks of opportunity for one round, you may make a single attack of opportunity against a target who moves more than 5' and moves through your threatened area in a manner that does not normally provoke an attack of opportunity.</Benefit>
  <Normal>Tumbling successfully does not provoke an attack of opportunity.  Spring attack does not provoke an attack of opportunity from the attacker's target.  You get no attacks of opportunity against a target with at least 50% cover.</Normal>
  <Notes>If you have made even a single attack of opportunity since your last action, you may not use this feat, since you can no longer give up ALL attacks of opportunity.  If the target has the feat Mobility, the mobility bonus to AC still applies.</Notes>
  <Source ID="0"/>
</Feat>
<Feat ID="58" Author="" Copyright="COPYRIGHT 2001, Eric D. Harry" Reference="Net Book of Feats">
  <Name>Crystal Psiweapon</Name>
  <Types Types="">
  </Types>
  <Prerequisites>Masterwork weapon imbedded with a crystal or any weapon imbued with permanent psionic power.</Prerequisites>
  <Benefit>You can seed a personality fragment in a weapon, granting the weapon limited sentience and linking it to your life-force.  The crystal psiweapon provides you with a skill bonus based upon the type of personality fragment that you place in the weapon (as with a standard psicrystal), and it gains in intelligence as you gain in level.  A crystal psiweapon is not a true psicrystal, however, and it does not have the other special abilities of a psicrystal unless you also have the psicrystal class ability.  Because the weapon is linked to your life-force, you can telekinetically summon it to your hand at a range of 10 feet as a free action with the cost of 1 power point.  Should the crystal psiweapon ever be destroyed, whether by accident or on purpose, you suffer the same XP penalty that a psion does after destruction of his or her psicrystal.</Benefit>
  <Special>You can apply other feats that enhance psicrystals, such as the Improved Psicrystal and Power Psicrystal feats, to your crystal psiweapon. If you have the psicrystal class ability your psicrystal becomes a part of your crystal psiweapon and continues to gain additional psicrystal abilities as you rise in level. You can only have one psicrystal or crystal psiweapon at any one time. Creation of a crystal psiweapon requires one day of meditation and a masterwork weapon imbedded with a crystal worth at least 50 gp. The personality fragment of a crystal psiweapon can also be created in or transferred to a psionic weapon, again after one day of meditation and a cost of 50 gp. In this way, your personality fragment can move from weapon to weapon repeatedly over your career.</Special>
  <Source ID="0"/>
</Feat>
<Feat ID="59" Author="" Copyright="COPYRIGHT 2000, Bradley H. Bemis Jr." Reference="Net Book of Feats">
  <Name>Defensive Casting</Name>
  <Types Types="">
  </Types>
  <Prerequisites>Dodge</Prerequisites>
  <Benefit>This feat allows you to take 10 on your concentration check for casting defensively.</Benefit>
  <Normal>You can avoid drawing an attack of opportunity when casting a spell while involved in combat.  When casting defensively, you must make a concentration check with a DC of 15 + the spells level or the spell fails.  Casting a spell in this fashion is a full round action.</Normal>
  <Special>This feat can only be used when facing a single opponent in melee.</Special>
  <Source ID="0"/>
</Feat>
<Feat ID="60" Author="" Copyright="COPYRIGHT 2000, Bradley H. Bemis Jr." Reference="Net Book of Feats">
  <Name>Defensive Position</Name>
  <Types Types="">
  </Types>
  <Benefit>You are an alert combatant with a sixth sense about opponents.  As long as you are mobile, you may decrease your face by one category.  This will help limit the number of opponents that can attack you at one time.
Example: A large (long) creature has a face of 5ft x 10ft.  This feat would allow that creature to decrease it face to large (tall) instead, for 5ft x 5ft face.  With a 5ft by 10ft face, this creature could have been attacked by up to 10 attackers.  Now, without any cover or other restrictions that could limit the number of attackers, the creature can still decrease its face enough to reduce the number of attackers to a maximum of 8.</Benefit>
  <Source ID="0"/>
</Feat>
<Feat ID="61" Author="" Copyright="COPYRIGHT 2000, Bradley H. Bemis Jr." Reference="Net Book of Feats">
  <Name>Defensive Study</Name>
  <Types Types="">
  </Types>
  <Prerequisites>2 or more ranks of Sense Motive, Alertness</Prerequisites>
  <Benefit>Grants you the ability to substitute your intelligence modifier for your dexterity modifier when calculating armor class against a single opponent.  To gain this benefit, you must be able to assess your opponent completely for at least three rounds of combat.  During this period of study you are only able to take a partial action each round.  Through the study of attack patterns you understand the best ways to avoid the attack methods used by your opponent.</Benefit>
  <Source ID="0"/>
</Feat>
<Feat ID="62" Author="" Copyright="COPYRIGHT 2000, System Reference Document" Reference="System Reference Document">
  <Name>Deflect Arrows</Name>
  <Types Types="">
  </Types>
  <Prerequisites>Dex 13+, Improved Unarmed Strike.</Prerequisites>
  <Benefit>The character must have at least one hand free (holding nothing) to use this feat. Once per round when the character would normally be hit with a ranged weapon, the character may make a Reflex saving throw against a DC of 20 (if the ranged weapon has a magical bonus to attack, the DC increases by that amount). If the character succeeds, the character deflects the weapon. The character must be aware of the attack and not flat-footed. Attempting to deflect a ranged weapon doesn't count as an action. Exceptional ranged weapons can't be deflected.</Benefit>
  <Source ID="0"/>
</Feat>
<Feat ID="63" Author="" Copyright="COPYRIGHT 2001, Michael J. Kletch" Reference="Net Book of Feats">
  <Name>Deflect Attack</Name>
  <Types Types="">
  </Types>
  <Prerequisites>Str 13+, Int 13+, Power Attack, Sunder, Expertise</Prerequisites>
  <Benefit>When you are Fighting Defensively, your opponent provokes an Attack of Opportunity just before attacking you.  Since you are Fighting Defensively, your Attack of Opportunity has a -4 penalty to attack.
If the opponent attacks you with a weapon, your Attack of Opportunity can only be used as a Sunder attack against the weapon that is used to attack you.  If the opponent attacks you with an unarmed attack or a natural weapon, you attack the unarmed strike or natural weapon, effectively making an Attack of Opportunity against your opponent.
If your attack actually damages the opponent's weapon (or the opponent, in the case of an unarmed strike or natural weapon), subtract the damage dealt to the weapon or opponent from the damage you would sustain from their attack.  In this way, it is possible to negate the damage from an opponent's attack.</Benefit>
  <Special>If you are attacking unarmed and you wish to use Deflect Attack, the prerequisites increase to "Str 13+, Dex 15+, Int 13+, Power Attack, Sunder, Expertise, Improved Unarmed Strike, Eagle Claw Attack, base attack bonus +2".  This simply adds Eagle Claw Attack, necessary for unarmed Sunder attacks, and its prerequisites to this feat.</Special>
  <Source ID="0"/>
</Feat>
<Feat ID="64" Author="" Copyright="COPYRIGHT 2000, Michael J. Kletch" Reference="Net Book of Feats">
  <Name>Deft Lunge</Name>
  <Types Types="">
  </Types>
  <Prerequisites>Expertise, Dex 13+</Prerequisites>
  <Benefit>When you use the attack action or full attack action in non-mounted melee combat, you may take as much as a -5 penalty to Armor Class to add the same number (up to +5) to a single attack roll in the same round.  This number may not exceed your base attack bonus.  Unless you also have the Mobility feat, this attack draws an Attack of Opportunity from the defender.  The changes to Armor Class last until your next action.  The bonus to your attack roll will stack with any other bonus.</Benefit>
  <Source ID="0"/>
</Feat>
<Feat ID="65" Author="" Copyright="COPYRIGHT 2001, Carl Cramér" Reference="Net Book of Feats">
  <Name>Demolition</Name>
  <Types Types="">
  </Types>
  <Prerequisites>Profession (siege engineer), Power Attack, Str 13+.</Prerequisites>
  <Benefit>If you take a full-round action that provokes an attack of opportunity to strike an immobile, inanimate object, the strike is a critical hit and has it's damage multiplied by your weapon's critical hit multiple. You can only do this against an immobile object, thus it is not possible to score a critical hit against an object held or worn by another character this way. With this feat, it is also possible to score critical hits or do a coup-de-grace against constructs. These attacks are resolved in normal fashion except that constructs automatically pass their Fortitude saves against death when they suffer a coup-de grace.</Benefit>
  <Normal>Objects and constructs are not subject to critical hits or coup-de-grace.</Normal>
  <Notes>This could be a house rule, and usable by all, rather than a feat. But in that case, all objects and constructs should add five points to their hardness ratings. It is introduced to make tools like picks and axes better than swords at chopping down doors and sundering statues.</Notes>
  <Source ID="0"/>
</Feat>
<Feat ID="66" Author="" Copyright="COPYRIGHT 2001, Bradley H. Bemis Jr." Reference="Net Book of Feats">
  <Name>Destructive Force</Name>
  <Types Types="">
  </Types>
  <Benefit>You can raise the damage cap of capped spells by two die (assuming you are of sufficient level to do so).  A Destructive Force spell takes up a spell slot of one level higher.
Example: A fireball spell is capped at 10D6 (at 10th level).  Using this feat, a 15th level caster could instead do up to 12d6 points of damage.</Benefit>
  <Notes>This feat can be used with any spell having a damage cap expressed in the spells description.  A damage cap can be identified by a statement similar to 'deals xdx points of x damage per caster level (maximum xdx)'.</Notes>
  <Source ID="0"/>
</Feat>
<Feat ID="67" Author="" Copyright="COPYRIGHT 2001, Eric D. Harry" Reference="Net Book of Feats">
  <Name>Detect Poison</Name>
  <Types Types="">
  </Types>
  <Benefit>You can use your Search skill to detect poison without casting the detect poison spell.  This is an extraordinary ability that requires a full round action with a DC equal to the save DC of the poison and can only be done at a range of 5 feet.</Benefit>
  <Source ID="0"/>
</Feat>
<Feat ID="68" Author="" Copyright="COPYRIGHT 2000, Bradley H. Bemis Jr." Reference="Net Book of Feats">
  <Name>Determined Soul</Name>
  <Types Types="">
  </Types>
  <Prerequisites>Iron Will</Prerequisites>
  <Benefit>Add your wisdom bonus to the number of points of damage you can sustain before entering each category of the death and dying system.
Example: You have an 18 Wis (+4 bonus).  You become disabled at -4, unconscious (and dying) from -5 to -13, and are dead at -14.</Benefit>
  <Source ID="0"/>
</Feat>
<Feat ID="69" Author="" Copyright="COPYRIGHT 2001, Eric D. Harry" Reference="Net Book of Feats">
  <Name>Discover Psionic Combat Mode</Name>
  <Types Types="">
  </Types>
  <Benefit>You immediately discover one psionic attack or defense mode of your choice and can use this attack or defense mode normally.</Benefit>
  <Special>If you have learned all the combat modes by use of this feat you gain no benefit when learning one by level advancement later.</Special>
  <Source ID="0"/>
</Feat>
<Feat ID="70" Author="" Copyright="COPYRIGHT 2001, Eric D. Harry" Reference="Net Book of Feats">
  <Name>Discover Psionic Power</Name>
  <Types Types="">
  </Types>
  <Benefit>You discover one additional psionic power of any level that you can manifest.</Benefit>
  <Special>You can choose this feat multiple times but may only learn one additional psionic power per power level.</Special>
  <Source ID="0"/>
</Feat>
<Feat ID="71" Author="" Copyright="COPYRIGHT 2001, Eric D. Harry" Reference="Net Book of Feats">
  <Name>Disease Resistance</Name>
  <Types Types="">
  </Types>
  <Benefit>You gain a +4 bonus on all Fortitude saves against disease.</Benefit>
  <Source ID="0"/>
</Feat>
<Feat ID="309" Author="" Copyright="COPYRIGHT 2001, Eric D. Harry" Reference="Net Book of Feats">
  <Name>Divination</Name>
  <Types Types="">
  </Types>
  <Benefit>All spells and spell-like abilities from the divination school of magic must beat the creature's SR in order to discover anything about it.</Benefit>
  <Normal>SR does not normally apply to spells and spell-like abilities from the divination school.</Normal>
  <Special>Characters that gain SR by race (like drow) can choose this feat as a Special feat.  If using the default Psionics-Magic Transparency option, this feat also extends your SR to resist all psionic powers from the telepathy and clairsentience disciplines.</Special>
  <Source ID="0"/>
</Feat>
<Feat ID="72" Author="" Copyright="COPYRIGHT 2001, Eric D. Harry" Reference="Net Book of Feats">
  <Name>Divine Armor</Name>
  <Types Types="">
  </Types>
  <Prerequisites>Ability to turn or rebuke undead, Cha 13+, Divine Vigor, Extra Turning.</Prerequisites>
  <Benefit>By spending one of your turn or rebuke undead attempts, your armor or body gains a sacred (if you channel positive energy) or profane (if you channel negative energy) bonus to Armor Class equal to your charisma bonus for a number of rounds equal to your charisma bonus.  When active, your armor or body glows with divine light (or a  profane aura) in a radius of 5 feet.  The bonus provided by Divine Armor is fully effective against incorporeal creatures.</Benefit>
  <Source ID="0"/>
</Feat>
<Feat ID="73" Author="" Copyright="COPYRIGHT 2001, Eric D. Harry" Reference="Net Book of Feats">
  <Name>Divine Armor Of The Soul</Name>
  <Types Types="">
  </Types>
  <Prerequisites>Ability to turn or rebuke undead, Cha 13+, Divine Ghost Armor, Extra Turning.</Prerequisites>
  <Benefit>By spending one of your turn or rebuke undead attempts, you become immune to the ability draining and level draining attacks of the undead for a number of rounds equal to your charisma bonus.</Benefit>
  <Source ID="0"/>
</Feat>
<Feat ID="74" Author="" Copyright="COPYRIGHT 2001, Carl Cramér" Reference="Net Book of Feats">
  <Name>Divine Dispel</Name>
  <Types Types="">
  </Types>
  <Prerequisites>Extra Turning, ability to turn or rebuke undead.</Prerequisites>
  <Benefit>You can dispel or counter a magic spell by making a turning check as if turning an undead creature of the opposing spellcaster's level. You can only dispel spells with the 'evil' descriptor (if you turn undead) or the 'good' descriptor (if you rebuke undead). A spell that is dispelled as it is being cast has no effect whatsoever; otherwise, it ends as if it's duration had run out. This power cannot affect spells immune to dispel magic.</Benefit>
  <Special>Each attempt to use Divine Dispel uses up one of your turn or rebuke attempts for the day.</Special>
  <Notes>If your religion is strongly opposed to law or chaos, your DM may allow you to channel energy against spells with the lawful or chaotic descriptor instead, and other types of Divine Dispel are certainly possible as well for certain religions.</Notes>
  <Source ID="0"/>
</Feat>
<Feat ID="75" Author="" Copyright="COPYRIGHT 2001, Bradley H. Bemis Jr." Reference="Net Book of Feats">
  <Name>Divine Dominion</Name>
  <Types Types="">
  </Types>
  <Prerequisites>6 or more ranks in Knowledge (religion)</Prerequisites>
  <Benefit>Select a third domain from your deities domain list.  All spells within the new domain list are considered domain spells for you.</Benefit>
  <Special>You do not gain the domain powers granted, you only gain the ability to use the domain spells listed as domain spells for your character.  This feat is only usable by clerics and can only be taken once.</Special>
  <Source ID="0"/>
</Feat>
<Feat ID="76" Author="" Copyright="COPYRIGHT 2001, Eric D. Harry" Reference="Net Book of Feats">
  <Name>Divine Fist</Name>
  <Types Types="">
  </Types>
  <Prerequisites>Ability to turn or rebuke undead, Cha 13+, Improved Unarmed Strike.</Prerequisites>
  <Benefit>By spending one of your turn or rebuke attempts per day, you can add your Charisma bonus to your damage rolls on successful unarmed attacks for a number of rounds equal to your Charisma bonus.</Benefit>
  <Special>Divine Fist is equivalent to Divine Might, allowing you to later learn feats that included Divine Might as a prerequisite, though you are then restricted to using these feats with unarmed strikes only.</Special>
  <Notes>Depending on your interpretation of 3rd edition rules, this feat is either unneeded as it is weaker than Divine Might (if you believe Divine Might can be used with unarmed strikes) or a separate feat on its own (if you believe that Divine Might can only be used with a weapon).</Notes>
  <Source ID="0"/>
</Feat>
<Feat ID="77" Author="" Copyright="COPYRIGHT 2001, Eric D. Harry" Reference="Net Book of Feats">
  <Name>Divine Flame</Name>
  <Types Types="">
  </Types>
  <Prerequisites>Ability to turn or rebuke undead, Cha 13+.</Prerequisites>
  <Benefit>By spending one of your turn or rebuke undead attempts, you can sheath your weapon with sacred or profane flame.  If you channel positive energy, your weapon is sheathed in white flames that inflict +1d6 points of sacred damage against evil opponents for a number of rounds equal to your charisma bonus.  If you channel negative energy, you weapon is sheathed in black flames that inflict +1d6 points of profane damage against good opponents instead.  These flames do not give off heat or ignite flammable objects, though sacred flames give off light equal to a torch.  The sacred or profane damage inflicted by Divine Flame is unaffected by protection from elements and similar spells.</Benefit>
  <Source ID="0"/>
</Feat>
<Feat ID="78" Author="" Copyright="COPYRIGHT 2001, Eric D. Harry" Reference="Net Book of Feats">
  <Name>Divine Fury</Name>
  <Types Types="">
  </Types>
  <Prerequisites>Ability to turn undead, Cha 13+, Extra Turning, Divine Vengeance.</Prerequisites>
  <Benefit>By spending one of your turn undead attempts, you can ignore the damage reduction of all undead opponents for a number of rounds equal to your charisma modifier.</Benefit>
  <Source ID="0"/>
</Feat>
<Feat ID="79" Author="" Copyright="COPYRIGHT 2001, Eric D. Harry" Reference="Net Book of Feats">
  <Name>Divine Ghost Armor</Name>
  <Types Types="">
  </Types>
  <Prerequisites>Ability to turn or rebuke undead, Cha 13+, Extra Turning.</Prerequisites>
  <Benefit>This feat can only be used when wearing armor.  By spending one turn or rebuke undead attempt, your armor gains the ghost touch special ability.  This allows you to apply your armor bonus against incorporeal attacks.  The duration of the ghost touch protection is limited to a number of rounds equal to your charisma bonus.</Benefit>
  <Source ID="0"/>
</Feat>
<Feat ID="80" Author="" Copyright="COPYRIGHT 2001, Eric D. Harry" Reference="Net Book of Feats">
  <Name>Divine Ghost Weapon</Name>
  <Types Types="">
  </Types>
  <Prerequisites>Ability to turn or rebuke undead, Cha 13+, Divine Might.</Prerequisites>
  <Benefit>By spending one of your turn or rebuke undead attempts, your weapon can be used to attack incorporeal opponents as if it had the ghost touch power, negating an incorporeal creatures ability to ignore 50% of successful attacks from a corporeal source.  Though you do not gain a bonus on attack or damage rolls with this feat, you can also negate the damage reduction of incorporeal or undead opponents as if wielding a +1 magic weapon.  The bonuses provided by this feat last for a number of rounds equal to your Charisma bonus.</Benefit>
  <Source ID="0"/>
</Feat>
<Feat ID="81" Author="" Copyright="COPYRIGHT 2000, Bradley H. Bemis Jr." Reference="Net Book of Feats">
  <Name>Divine Gift</Name>
  <Types Types="">
  </Types>
  <Prerequisites>Wisdom 13+, Knowledge (Religion)</Prerequisites>
  <Benefit>Grants any individual the ability to know/understand up to their wisdom modifier's worth of orisons (0-level divine spells chosen from the character's deity).  The character can use his selection of orisons by preparing and using one per day.  Anyone trying to cast a spell (even though its just 0-level) must meet all of the requirements and suffer all of the penalties associated with the use of divine magics.</Benefit>
  <Special>This feat may be taken multiple times; however, no additional orisons can ever be learned (past the individuals wisdom modifier).  Each additional time this feat is taken, the caster may prepare one additional orison per day.  The total maximum number of orisons that can be cast in a single day (regardless of the number of times this feat is taken), is also limited to the caster's wisdom modifier.</Special>
  <Source ID="0"/>
</Feat>
<Feat ID="82" Author="" Copyright="COPYRIGHT 2001, Eric D. Harry" Reference="Net Book of Feats">
  <Name>Divine Impact</Name>
  <Types Types="">
  </Types>
  <Prerequisites>Ability to turn or rebuke undead, Charisma 13+, Strength 13+, Divine Might, Power Attack, base attack bonus +3 or higher.</Prerequisites>
  <Benefit>By spending one of your turn or rebuke attempts per day, you can resolve your next melee attack as a touch attack, ignoring any benefit to your opponent's Armor Class provided by armor, shield or natural armor.  Once you have channeled energy for this feat, you must make this attack within a number of rounds equal to your Charisma bonus.  Like all divine feats, activating Divine Impact requires a standard action.</Benefit>
  <Special>This is a modification of the Deep Impact psionic feat found in the Psionic Book for use as a divine feat.</Special>
  <Source ID="0"/>
</Feat>
<Feat ID="83" Author="" Copyright="COPYRIGHT 2001, Eric D. Harry" Reference="Net Book of Feats">
  <Name>Divine Sight</Name>
  <Types Types="">
  </Types>
  <Prerequisites>Ability to turn or rebuke undead, Cha 13+.</Prerequisites>
  <Benefit>By spending one of your turn or rebuke undead attempts, you gain a +2 enhancement bonus on Spot and Search checks and a +2 sacred bonus on Will disbelief saves against illusion effects for a number of minutes equal to your charisma modifier.</Benefit>
  <Source ID="0"/>
</Feat>
<Feat ID="84" Author="" Copyright="COPYRIGHT 2001, Eric D. Harry" Reference="Net Book of Feats">
  <Name>Divine Weapon</Name>
  <Types Types="">
  </Types>
  <Prerequisites>Ability to turn or rebuke undead, Cha 13+, Str 13+, Power Attack, Divine Might, base attack bonus +3 or higher.</Prerequisites>
  <Benefit>Spend two of your turn/rebuke undead attempts to channel energy into your weapon, granting it a bonus on attack and damage rolls equal to your charisma bonus for a number of rounds equal to your charisma bonus.</Benefit>
  <Source ID="0"/>
</Feat>
<Feat ID="85" Author="" Copyright="COPYRIGHT 2001, Eric D. Harry" Reference="Net Book of Feats">
  <Name>Divine Wrath</Name>
  <Types Types="">
  </Types>
  <Prerequisites>Ability to turn/rebuke outsider.</Prerequisites>
  <Benefit>If you channel positive energy, you can spend one of your turn outsider attempts to add 2d6 points of divine damage against evil outsiders on every successful melee attack until the end of your next action.  If you channel negative energy, you inflict 2d6 points of profane damage against good outsiders instead.</Benefit>
  <Source ID="0"/>
</Feat>
<Feat ID="86" Author="" Copyright="COPYRIGHT 2000, System Reference Document" Reference="System Reference Document">
  <Name>Dodge</Name>
  <Types Types="">
  </Types>
  <Prerequisites>Dex 13+.</Prerequisites>
  <Benefit>During the character's action, the character designates an opponent and receive a +1 dodge bonus to Armor Class against attacks from that opponent. The character can select a new opponent on any action. Note: A condition that makes the character lose his or her Dexterity bonus to Armor Class (if any) also makes the character lose dodge bonuses. Also, dodge bonuses stack with each other, unlike most other types of bonuses.</Benefit>
  <Source ID="0"/>
</Feat>
<Feat ID="87" Author="" Copyright="COPYRIGHT 2001, Eric D. Harry, Brian A. Smith" Reference="Net Book of Feats">
  <Name>Double Weapon Fighting</Name>
  <Types Types="">
  </Types>
  <Prerequisites>Proficient with weapon, BAB +1 or better</Prerequisites>
  <Benefit>You fight with your chosen double weapon as though you had Two Weapon Fighting, Ambidexterity, and as though you were using two weapons with a light weapon in your off hand.</Benefit>
  <Normal>Use a double weapon as though you were using two weapons with a light weapon in your off hand.</Normal>
  <Special>You may take this feat multiple times.  Each time, it applies to a different double weapon.</Special>
  <Notes>You can learn later feats for which Ambidexterity or Two-Weapon fighting are prerequisites based on the 'virtual' feats learned with Double Weapon Fighting, but you can then only use those feats with the specific weapon you have chosen.</Notes>
  <Source ID="0"/>
</Feat>
<Feat ID="88" Author="" Copyright="COPYRIGHT 2001, Eric D. Harry" Reference="Net Book of Feats">
  <Name>Draconic Bloodline</Name>
  <Types Types="">
  </Types>
  <Benefit>You have a remarkable affinity for Arcane spell magic: add +1 to the Difficulty Class for all saving throws against your Arcane spells.  You may also treat the Sorcerer class as a favored class in addition to any other favored class that you gain by race.</Benefit>
  <Special>You can only take this feat at 1st level and this feat stacks with the Spell Focus and Greater Spell Focus feats.  Though you have Draconic ancestry you still gain the regular bonuses and penalties of a typical member of your race.  You are also vulnerable to attacks that target your unique Draconic heritage (like dragonbane weapons) even though you are only distantly related to Dragonkind.</Special>
  <Source ID="0"/>
</Feat>
<Feat ID="89" Author="" Copyright="COPYRIGHT 2001, Albert Nakano (Bertman4)" Reference="Net Book of Feats">
  <Name>Ducking Shot</Name>
  <Types Types="">
  </Types>
  <Prerequisites>Point Blank Shot, Dodge, Dex 13+</Prerequisites>
  <Benefit>You get a +4 dodge bonus to Armor Class against attacks of opportunities caused while making a ranged attack in an area threatened by your enemies.</Benefit>
  <Notes>A condition that makes you lose your Dexterity bonus to Armor Class (if any) also makes you lose dodge bonuses.</Notes>
  <Source ID="0"/>
</Feat>
<Feat ID="90" Author="" Copyright="COPYRIGHT 2001, Eric D. Harry" Reference="Net Book of Feats">
  <Name>Elven Swordmastery</Name>
  <Types Types="">
  </Types>
  <Prerequisites>Elf or half-elf, base attack bonus +1 or higher.</Prerequisites>
  <Benefit>Similar to the Weapon Finesse feat, you may use your Dexterity modifier instead of your Strength modifier on attack rolls when wielding a longsword.  As elven swordplay is a fluid art based on Dexterity and movement, if a shield is used you must apply the shield's armor check penalty to your attack rolls.</Benefit>
  <Normal>This is a modification of the Weapon Finesse feat.  The Weapon Finesse feat cannot normally be applied to the longsword.</Normal>
  <Special>Elven Swordmastery can be used in place of Weapon Finesse as a prerequisite for other feats.</Special>
  <Source ID="0"/>
</Feat>
<Feat ID="91" Author="" Copyright="COPYRIGHT 2000, System Reference Document" Reference="System Reference Document">
  <Name>Empower Spell</Name>
  <Types Types="">
  </Types>
  <Benefit>All variable, numeric effects of an empowered spell are increased by one-half. An empowered spell deals half again as much damage as normal, cures half again as many hit points, affects half again as many targets, etc., as appropriate. Saving throws and opposed rolls (such as the one the character makes when the character casts dispel magic) are not affected. Spells without random variables are not affected. An empowered spell uses up a spell slot two levels higher than the spell's actual level.</Benefit>
  <Source ID="0"/>
</Feat>
<Feat ID="92" Author="" Copyright="COPYRIGHT 2000, System Reference Document" Reference="System Reference Document">
  <Name>Endurance</Name>
  <Types Types="">
  </Types>
  <Benefit>Whenever the character makes a check for performing a physical action that extends over a period of time (running, swimming, holding the character's breath, and so on), the character gets a +4 bonus to the check.</Benefit>
  <Source ID="0"/>
</Feat>
<Feat ID="93" Author="" Copyright="COPYRIGHT 2001, Eric D. Harry" Reference="Net Book of Feats">
  <Name>Enhanced Draconic Bloodline</Name>
  <Types Types="">
  </Types>
  <Prerequisites>Draconic Bloodline, ability to cast Arcane spells without preparation (like a Bard or Sorcerer).</Prerequisites>
  <Benefit>If a Bard or Sorcerer, you gain bonus spells based on your Charisma attribute (per Table 1-1, page 8 of the 3rd Edition Player's Handbook).  These spells are added to your number of spells known; this feat does not increase the number of spells that you can cast per day.</Benefit>
  <Normal>Bards and Sorcerers are normally fixed in their number of spells known per level.</Normal>
  <Special>The bonus spells provided by this feat cannot be combined with the bonus spells provided by any other feat (based on ability score) other than Cantrip.</Special>
  <Source ID="0"/>
</Feat>
<Feat ID="94" Author="" Copyright="COPYRIGHT 2001, Eric D. Harry" Reference="Net Book of Feats">
  <Name>Enlarge Breath Weapon</Name>
  <Types Types="">
  </Types>
  <Benefit>Double the range of the creature's breath weapon, unless it is cone-shaped.  If the creature has a cone-shaped breath weapon, increase the range of its breath weapon (and its width and height as well) by 50% instead.</Benefit>
  <Source ID="0"/>
</Feat>
<Feat ID="95" Author="" Copyright="COPYRIGHT 2000, System Reference Document" Reference="System Reference Document">
  <Name>Enlarge Spell</Name>
  <Types Types="">
  </Types>
  <Benefit>An enlarged spell has its range doubled. Spells whose ranges are not defined by distance do not have their ranges increased. A spell whose area or effect is determined by its range has the dimensions of its area or effect increased proportionally. An enlarged spell uses up a spell slot one level higher than the spell's actual level.</Benefit>
  <Source ID="0"/>
</Feat>
<Feat ID="97" Author="" Copyright="COPYRIGHT 2000, System Reference Document" Reference="System Reference Document">
  <Name>Exotic Weapon Proficiency</Name>
  <Types Types="">
  </Types>
  <Prerequisites>Base attack bonus +1 or higher.</Prerequisites>
  <Benefit>The character makes attack rolls with the weapon normally.</Benefit>
  <Normal>A character who uses a weapon without being proficient with it suffers a -4 penalty on attack rolls.</Normal>
  <Special>The character can gain this feat multiple times. Each time The character takes the feat, it applies to a new weapon. Proficiency with the bastard sword or the dwarven waraxe has a prerequisite of Str 13+.</Special>
  <Source ID="0"/>
</Feat>
<Feat ID="98" Author="" Copyright="COPYRIGHT 2001, Rebecca Glenn (Becky)" Reference="Net Book of Feats">
  <Name>Expand Spell</Name>
  <Types Types="">
  </Types>
  <Benefit>An Expanded spell has its area of effect increased by + 5 ft to all dimensions. This feat does not affect spells without an area of effect stated in spatial terms. Areas of effect of "personal" or "touch" or no AREA listed are not affected. If the spell specifies numbers of targets, that number is not affected (see Empower Spell in Core Rulebook I). An Expanded spell takes up a spell slot two levels higher than the spell's actual level.
Example: Burning Hands (1st level) affects anyone in a semicircle burst of flames 10-ft-long, starting at the caster. Expanded Burning Hands (3rd level) affects anyone in a semicircle burst of flames 15-feet-long, starting at the caster.</Benefit>
  <Source ID="0"/>
</Feat>
<Feat ID="99" Author="" Copyright="COPYRIGHT 2001, Carl Cramér, Curtis Bennett" Reference="Net Book of Feats">
  <Name>Expanded Domains</Name>
  <Types Types="">
  </Types>
  <Prerequisites>Ability to cast clerical spells and domain spells.</Prerequisites>
  <Benefit>You can prepare domain spells from all of your chosen domains in your clerical spell slots. You may still only prepare domain spells in your domain spell slots.</Benefit>
  <Notes>If you wish, you can still substitute domain spells memorized in regular spell slots for cure wounds spells.</Notes>
  <Source ID="0"/>
</Feat>
<Feat ID="100" Author="" Copyright="COPYRIGHT 2000, Michael J. Kletch" Reference="Net Book of Feats">
  <Name>Expert Aim</Name>
  <Types Types="">
  </Types>
  <Prerequisites>Precise Shot, base attack bonus +6 or higher</Prerequisites>
  <Benefit>If you take the Full Attack action when using a device missile weapon (e.g. bow, crossbow), you may choose to make a single attack with a range of 30 ft. or less using your Expert Aim.  While you normally apply your Dexterity bonus only to attack, in this case you also apply your Dexterity bonus to damage.
This feat is ineffective against creatures that are not subject to critical hits (e.g. constructs, elementals, oozes, plants and undead).</Benefit>
  <Normal>Your dexterity bonus applies only to your attack roll.</Normal>
  <Source ID="0"/>
</Feat>
<Feat ID="101" Author="" Copyright="COPYRIGHT 2000, Bradley H. Bemis Jr." Reference="Net Book of Feats">
  <Name>Expert Cower</Name>
  <Types Types="">
  </Types>
  <Benefit>You are so good at cowering that you can make yourself a smaller target.  When there is no cover around you, you gain the effects of one-quarter cover (+2 AC bonus, +1 save bonus).  When in a covered area, you are covered as if the level of cover was one place better.  While cowering, you are considered immobile and flat-footed.  You can only take a partial action each round and this action cannot be a movement action (i.e. you could cower behind a rock and still fire a bow once per round, but you could not cower as you run from rock to rock).  The act of finding a good spot and cowering (i.e. scrunching yourself up to gain the benefits of this feat) I, in itself, a full round action.</Benefit>
  <Source ID="0"/>
</Feat>
<Feat ID="102" Author="" Copyright="COPYRIGHT 2001, Bradley H. Bemis Jr." Reference="Net Book of Feats">
  <Name>Expert Healing</Name>
  <Types Types="">
  </Types>
  <Prerequisites>5 or more ranks of Heal</Prerequisites>
  <Benefit>When attempting to heal a comrade after battle, you can attempt a heal check against a DC equal to the number of points of damage sustained during the encounter.  A successful check allows you to heal 1d4 hit points of damage.</Benefit>
  <Special>This feat can only be used once after each encounter where damage was suffered.  The maximum amount of healing is always limited to damage sustained from fresh wounds only (not wounds from a previous encounter).</Special>
  <Source ID="0"/>
</Feat>
<Feat ID="103" Author="" Copyright="COPYRIGHT 2000, System Reference Document" Reference="System Reference Document">
  <Name>Expertise</Name>
  <Types Types="">
  </Types>
  <Prerequisites>Int 13+.</Prerequisites>
  <Benefit>When the character uses the attack action or full attack action in melee, the character can take a penalty of as much as -5 on the character's attack and add the same number (up to +5) to the character's Armor Class. This number may not exceed the character's base attack bonus. The changes to attack rolls and Armor Class last until the character's next action. The bonus to the character's Armor Class is a dodge bonus.</Benefit>
  <Normal>A character not capable of the Expertise feat can fight defensively while using the attack or full attack action to take a -4 penalty on attacks and gain a +2 dodge bonus to Armor Class.</Normal>
  <Source ID="0"/>
</Feat>
<Feat ID="104" Author="" Copyright="COPYRIGHT 2000, System Reference Document" Reference="System Reference Document">
  <Name>Extend Spell</Name>
  <Types Types="">
  </Types>
  <Benefit>An extended spell lasts twice as long as normal. Spells with a concentration, instantaneous, or permanent duration are not affected by this feat. An extended spell uses up a spell slot one level higher than the spell's actual level.</Benefit>
  <Source ID="0"/>
</Feat>
<Feat ID="105" Author="" Copyright="COPYRIGHT 2001, Carl Cramér" Reference="Net Book of Feats">
  <Name>Extend Spell List</Name>
  <Types Types="">
  </Types>
  <Benefit>With this feat, you get to add the spells of one clerical domain to your spell list, regardless of your class.  You cast these spells as if they were normal spells of your spellcaster class.  The new spells become arcane spells if you have an arcane spellcaster class but in this case you must still learn the spells in the normal manner; this feat only adds them to your spell list.  If the domain power of the domain you picked is a spell-like ability, you get this spell added to your spell lists, as well.  Examples include animal friendship of the animal domain and freedom of movement of the travel domain.</Benefit>
  <Special>A wizard must always research these spells from scratch, using the standard game rules.  As a divine spellcaster, you cannot learn domains inappropriate for the powers you serve.</Special>
  <Notes>These spells have nothing to do with gods or domains, really; the domains are merely used as reasonable groups of spells that a themed spellcaster might learn.  Use this feat with caution: it fits in open-ended campaigns, where characters are allowed to step outside the usual class limitations.  It lets sorcerers and wizards learn healing spells and divine spellcasters to learn offensive spells like burning hands.</Notes>
  <Source ID="0"/>
</Feat>
<Feat ID="106" Author="" Copyright="COPYRIGHT 2001, William Setzer" Reference="Net Book of Feats">
  <Name>Extra Bardic Music</Name>
  <Types Types="">
  </Types>
  <Prerequisites>Bardic Music Ability</Prerequisites>
  <Benefit>This feat allows you to use your Bardic Music ability four more times per day.</Benefit>
  <Special>You can take this feat multiple times, gaining four extra uses each time.</Special>
  <Source ID="0"/>
</Feat>
<Feat ID="107" Author="" Copyright="COPYRIGHT 2001" Reference="Net Book of Feats">
  <Name>Extra Primeval Ability</Name>
  <Types Types="">
  </Types>
  <Prerequisites>Innate supernatural or spell-like ability.</Prerequisites>
  <Benefit>Choose one innate supernatural or spell-like ability that the creature can use one or more times per day.  The creature can now use this ability one more time per day.</Benefit>
  <Special>This feat can be taken multiple times and will stack with itself.  Each additional time that this feat is taken you can apply it to the same innate supernatural or spell-like ability or to one of your other innate supernatural or spell-like abilities.  This feat cannot be used with class based spell-like abilities, like the druid's wild shape or paladin's ability to cure disease.</Special>
  <Source ID="0"/>
</Feat>
<Feat ID="108" Author="" Copyright="COPYRIGHT 2001, Eric D. Harry" Reference="Net Book of Feats">
  <Name>Extra Rage</Name>
  <Types Types="">
  </Types>
  <Prerequisites>Rage class ability, base attack bonus +2 or higher.</Prerequisites>
  <Benefit>You can rage one more time per day.</Benefit>
  <Special>This feat can be taken more than once, each time allowing you to enter a fit of rage one more time per day.</Special>
  <Source ID="0"/>
</Feat>
<Feat ID="109" Author="" Copyright="COPYRIGHT 2000, System Reference Document" Reference="System Reference Document">
  <Name>Extra Turning</Name>
  <Types Types="">
  </Types>
  <Prerequisites>Ability to Turn Undead</Prerequisites>
  <Benefit>Allows a character to turn undead four more times per day than normal.</Benefit>
  <Special>A character can take this feat multiple times, gaining four extra daily turning attempts each time.</Special>
  <Source ID="0"/>
</Feat>
<Feat ID="110" Author="" Copyright="COPYRIGHT 2001, Eric D. Harry" Reference="Net Book of Feats">
  <Name>Extra Wild Shape</Name>
  <Types Types="">
  </Types>
  <Prerequisites>Cha 13+, wild shape class ability,</Prerequisites>
  <Benefit>You can use your wild shape class ability one more time per day.</Benefit>
  <Normal>Wild shape is a class ability of the Druid gained at 5th level.</Normal>
  <Special>You may take this feat multiple times.</Special>
  <Source ID="0"/>
</Feat>
<Feat ID="111" Author="" Copyright="COPYRIGHT 2001, Carl Cramér" Reference="Net Book of Feats">
  <Name>Fake Spell</Name>
  <Types Types="">
  </Types>
  <Prerequisites>Spellcraft</Prerequisites>
  <Benefit>You say the words and make the gestures, but you just don't have the power needed to make the spell actually happen?  it just looks like you do. You must have seen the spell you want to fake being cast several times in order to fake it. Anyone can see through your trickery with an opposed Spellcraft check.</Benefit>
  <Special>Somebody who has readied an action to counterspell and who fails to see through your trickery will think you are about to cast the spell being faked.</Special>
  <Notes>If the spell effect would have been unnoticeable (such as most divination spells) or you can fake the effects of the spell (perhaps through illusion, alchemical pyrotechnics or a willing accomplice), people watching you will believe the spell was real. Bluff, Perform, Alchemy and several other skills may be helpful in achieving this, but faking the spell effects themselves is outside the scope of this feat.</Notes>
  <Source ID="0"/>
</Feat>
<Feat ID="112" Author="" Copyright="COPYRIGHT 2000, System Reference Document" Reference="System Reference Document">
  <Name>Far Shot</Name>
  <Types Types="">
  </Types>
  <Prerequisites>Point Blank Shot.</Prerequisites>
  <Benefit>When the character uses a projectile weapon, such as a bow, its range increment increases by one-half (multiply by 1.5). When the character uses a thrown weapon, its range increment is doubled.</Benefit>
  <Source ID="0"/>
</Feat>
<Feat ID="113" Author="" Copyright="COPYRIGHT 2001, Carl Cramér" Reference="Net Book of Feats">
  <Name>Fast Item Creation</Name>
  <Types Types="">
  </Types>
  <Prerequisites>Ability to cast fourth level spells</Prerequisites>
  <Benefit>You increase the daily rate at which you create magical items by 1000 gp.</Benefit>
  <Normal>All spellcasters normally create items at the rate of 1000 gp per day.</Normal>
  <Special>This feat can be taken several times, and stacks with itself. Each time it is chosen, add 1000 gp to the value of magical items the character can create in a day. Thus, items take half the usual time with one feat's worth of Fast Item Creation, one-third the usual time with two, and so on.</Special>
  <Source ID="0"/>
</Feat>
<Feat ID="114" Author="" Copyright="COPYRIGHT 2001, Bradley H. Bemis Jr." Reference="Net Book of Feats">
  <Name>Fast Mover</Name>
  <Types Types="">
  </Types>
  <Prerequisites>Dex 15+, Run</Prerequisites>
  <Benefit>Add +5 to your base movement rate when wearing light armor or less.</Benefit>
  <Special>This feat can stack with other movement bonuses (such as the barbarian and monks abilities).  This feat can be taken multiple times.</Special>
  <Source ID="0"/>
</Feat>
<Feat ID="115" Author="" Copyright="COPYRIGHT 2001, Carl Cramér" Reference="Net Book of Feats">
  <Name>Fast Spell</Name>
  <Types Types="">
  </Types>
  <Benefit>A Fast Spell has it's casting time halved, to a minimum of one action.  This is only a benefit for spells that normally have a long casting time.  A spell with a casting time of 'one full round' now takes a standard action to cast.  A spell with a casting time longer than one round has it's casting time halved. A Fast Spell uses up a spell slot one level higher than the spell's actual level.</Benefit>
  <Notes>For a spontaneous spellcaster such as a sorcerer or bard, the metamagic rule still cuts in and changes the standard action into a full-round action, which is still not the same as a 1 full-round casting time.</Notes>
  <Source ID="0"/>
</Feat>
<Feat ID="116" Author="" Copyright="COPYRIGHT 2001, Bradley H. Bemis Jr." Reference="Net Book of Feats">
  <Name>Favored Class</Name>
  <Types Types="">
  </Types>
  <Prerequisites>Multiclass character</Prerequisites>
  <Benefit>When becoming a multi-class character you can select a class that is not normally favored by your race without suffering an experience reward penalty.</Benefit>
  <Normal>You suffer an experience reward penalty for multi-classing outside of your favored class list.</Normal>
  <Special>This feat can only be taken one time.  The choice of the non-racially favored class must be explained in the characters history or role-played within the group so that this feat makes sense for the character.</Special>
  <Source ID="0"/>
</Feat>
<Feat ID="117" Author="" Copyright="COPYRIGHT 2000, Brendan Quinn" Reference="Net Book of Feats">
  <Name>Fearsome Display</Name>
  <Types Types="">
  </Types>
  <Prerequisites>Base attack bonus +6, Accurate Attack or Weapon Finesse with the weapon used, 5 or more ranks of Intimidate</Prerequisites>
  <Benefit>As a full round action, you can add 1/2 of your base attack bonus to your intimidation check.</Benefit>
  <Special>This ability is ineffective against those who can't comprehend your skill.</Special>
  <Source ID="0"/>
</Feat>
<Feat ID="118" Author="" Copyright="COPYRIGHT 2001, Eric D. Harry" Reference="Net Book of Feats">
  <Name>Fiery Rage</Name>
  <Types Types="">
  </Types>
  <Prerequisites>Rage character class ability</Prerequisites>
  <Benefit>You can rage for a number of rounds equal to 6 plus your rage-enhanced modified Constitution modifier.</Benefit>
  <Normal>A fit of rage normally lasts a number of rounds equal to 3 plus the raging character's newly modified Constitution modifier.</Normal>
  <Source ID="0"/>
</Feat>
<Feat ID="119" Author="" Copyright="COPYRIGHT 2000, Bradley H. Bemis Jr." Reference="Net Book of Feats">
  <Name>Find Flaw</Name>
  <Types Types="">
  </Types>
  <Prerequisites>5 or more ranks in Craft (within the items broad category type), Knowledge (Engineering)</Prerequisites>
  <Benefit>There is a chance you can find a flaw in the design of an object and exploit that flaw to your benefit.  You must study the item for at least three rounds before attempting to use this feat.  During the period of study, you are only capable of taking a partial action each round.  At the end of the study period you must make an intelligence check against the break DC of the item in question.  You can add a +1 modifier to your check roll for each additional 3 rounds of study past the first 3 required rounds (to a maximum bonus of +5).  If you succeed on the intelligence check, you have found a flaw in the object and can use this feat to exploit that flaw when trying to damage or destroy the object.  When attempting to destroy an item that you have found a flaw in, the hardness of the object is effectively reduced by your Intelligence modifier.</Benefit>
  <Source ID="0"/>
</Feat>
<Feat ID="120" Author="" Copyright="COPYRIGHT 2001, Eric D. Harry" Reference="Net Book of Feats">
  <Name>Fire To Ice</Name>
  <Types Types="">
  </Types>
  <Prerequisites>Ability to cast Arcane or Divine spells with a fire based component</Prerequisites>
  <Benefit>You may prepare and/or cast any fire-based spell as a cold spell with similar range, area of effect and damage.  Casting a spell in this manner uses up a spell slot one level higher than the normal spell</Benefit>
  <Special>It is blasphemous for a Divine spellcaster that follows a deity with access to the Fire domain to select this feat.</Special>
  <Source ID="0"/>
</Feat>
<Feat ID="121" Author="" Copyright="COPYRIGHT 2000, Brendan Quinn" Reference="Net Book of Feats">
  <Name>Flashy Attack</Name>
  <Types Types="">
  </Types>
  <Prerequisites>Base attack bonus +6, Accurate Attack or Weapon Finesse with the weapon used</Prerequisites>
  <Benefit>As a full round action, you can add your charisma modifier (in addition to all other modifiers) to your attack roll.</Benefit>
  <Special>This feat can be taken multiple times, each time it applies to a new weapon.  Fighters may take this as a bonus feat.</Special>
  <Source ID="0"/>
</Feat>
<Feat ID="122" Author="" Copyright="COPYRIGHT 2001, Carl Cramér" Reference="Net Book of Feats">
  <Name>Flurry Of Blades</Name>
  <Types Types="">
  </Types>
  <Prerequisites>Weapon Finesse, Weapon Focus with weapon, base attack bonus +3 or better, dexterity 13+</Prerequisites>
  <Benefit>Choose one weapon that you have Weapon Focus and Weapon Finesse for. When unencumbered, in light armor or less, and wielding this type of weapon, you may make one extra attack per round.  The attack is at your highest base attack bonus, but each attack (the extra one and all the normal ones) suffer a -2 penalty.  You must use the full attack action.  This feat does not stack with other feats/abilities that grant extra attacks, such as Flurry of Blows, two weapon use, double weapons, or creatures that make multiple attacks. It does stack with the iterative attacks of a character with high base attack bonus.</Benefit>
  <Notes>This is a fencing technique, and fits well in a renaissance-style game.</Notes>
  <Source ID="0"/>
</Feat>
<Feat ID="123" Author="" Copyright="COPYRIGHT 2000, Bradley H. Bemis Jr." Reference="Net Book of Feats">
  <Name>Flurry Of Blows</Name>
  <Types Types="">
  </Types>
  <Prerequisites>Improved Unarmed Strike</Prerequisites>
  <Benefit>Make one extra unarmed strike per round at your highest base attack.  All attacks made this round suffer a -2 penalty.</Benefit>
  <Special>This feat cannot be used in conjunction with any other feat that allows multiple attacks or with the virtual feat of the same name gained by a monk.</Special>
  <Source ID="0"/>
</Feat>
<Feat ID="124" Author="" Copyright="COPYRIGHT 2000, System Reference Document" Reference="System Reference Document">
  <Name>Flyby Attack</Name>
  <Types Types="">
  </Types>
  <Prerequisites>Fly speed.</Prerequisites>
  <Benefit>When flying, the creature can take a move action (including a dive) and another partial action at any point during the move. The creature cannot take a second move action during a round when it makes a flyby attack.</Benefit>
  <Normal>Without this feat, the creature takes a partial action either before or after its move.</Normal>
  <Source ID="0"/>
</Feat>
<Feat ID="125" Author="" Copyright="COPYRIGHT 2001, Eric D. Harry" Reference="Net Book of Feats">
  <Name>Focused Primeval Ability</Name>
  <Types Types="">
  </Types>
  <Prerequisites>Innate supernatural or spell-like ability.</Prerequisites>
  <Benefit>Choose one of your innate supernatural or spell-like abilities.  Add +2 to the Difficulty Class for all saving throws made to resist this ability.</Benefit>
  <Special>This feat can be taken multiple times but its benefits do not stack.  Each time that it is taken the creature must apply it to another of its innate supernatural or spell-like abilities. This feat cannot be used with class based spell-like abilities, like the druid's wild shape or paladin's ability to cure disease.</Special>
  <Source ID="0"/>
</Feat>
<Feat ID="126" Author="" Copyright="COPYRIGHT 2001, Eric D. Harry" Reference="Net Book of Feats">
  <Name>Focused Psionic Power</Name>
  <Types Types="">
  </Types>
  <Benefit>Add +1 to the difficulty class for all saving throws and +1 to your manifester level checks to overcome power resistance for all powers manifested from your chosen discipline.</Benefit>
  <Special>This feat can be chosen multiple times and will stack with itself, though each time it is taken you have the option of applying its effects to a different psionic discipline.</Special>
  <Source ID="0"/>
</Feat>
<Feat ID="127" Author="" Copyright="COPYRIGHT 2000, System Reference Document" Reference="System Reference Document">
  <Name>Forge Ring</Name>
  <Types Types="">
  </Types>
  <Prerequisites>Spellcaster level 12th+.</Prerequisites>
  <Benefit>The character can create any ring whose prerequisites the character meets. Crafting a ring takes 1 day for each 1,000 gp in its base price. To craft a ring, the character must spend 1/25 of its base price in XP and use up raw materials costing half of its base price.
The character can also mend a broken ring if it is a ring that the character could make. Doing so costs half the XP, half the raw materials, and half the time it would take to craft that ring in the first place.
Some magic rings incur extra costs in material components or XP as noted in their descriptions.</Benefit>
  <Source ID="0"/>
</Feat>
<Feat ID="128" Author="" Copyright="COPYRIGHT 2001, Carl Cramér" Reference="Net Book of Feats">
  <Name>Fortune</Name>
  <Types Types="">
  </Types>
  <Benefit>You gain the power of good fortune, which is usable once per day.  This extraordinary ability allows you to reroll one roll that you have just made.  You must take the result of the reroll, even if it's worse than the original roll.</Benefit>
  <Source ID="0"/>
</Feat>
<Feat ID="129" Author="" Copyright="COPYRIGHT 2000, Michael J. Kletch" Reference="Net Book of Feats">
  <Name>Fracture</Name>
  <Types Types="">
  </Types>
  <Prerequisites>Sunder, Power Attack, base attack bonus +2 or higher.</Prerequisites>
  <Benefit>When attacking an object with hardness greater than or equal to that of your weapon, you gain +2 circumstance bonus to damage.  When you are attacking an object with hardness less than that of your weapon, you gain a +5 circumstance bonus to damage.</Benefit>
  <Source ID="0"/>
</Feat>
<Feat ID="130" Author="" Copyright="COPYRIGHT 2001, Eric D. Harry" Reference="Net Book of Feats">
  <Name>Ghost Touch</Name>
  <Types Types="">
  </Types>
  <Prerequisites>Wis 13+, Ki Strike class ability.</Prerequisites>
  <Benefit>You can make unarmed attacks against incorporeal opponents as if you had the ghost touch power, negating an incorporeal creatures ability to ignore 50% of successful attacks from a corporeal source.  Like Ki Strike, Ghost Touch is a supernatural ability.</Benefit>
  <Source ID="0"/>
</Feat>
<Feat ID="131" Author="" Copyright="COPYRIGHT 2000, Bradley H. Bemis Jr." Reference="Net Book of Feats">
  <Name>Gifted Learner</Name>
  <Types Types="">
  </Types>
  <Benefit>From this point on, you can add one additional skill point for each level you gain.</Benefit>
  <Special>This feat can only be taken once.  Humans cannot take this feat.</Special>
  <Source ID="0"/>
</Feat>
<Feat ID="132" Author="" Copyright="COPYRIGHT 2001, Eric D. Harry" Reference="Net Book of Feats">
  <Name>Gigantic Weapon</Name>
  <Types Types="">
  </Types>
  <Prerequisites>Str 15+, base attack bonus +3 or higher.</Prerequisites>
  <Benefit>You can wield a weapon two sizes larger than you with two hands, suffering a -2 penalty on all attack rolls when doing so.</Benefit>
  <Normal>You normally can only wield a weapon one size large than you with two hands.</Normal>
  <Source ID="0"/>
</Feat>
<Feat ID="133" Author="" Copyright="COPYRIGHT 2001, Carl Cramér" Reference="Net Book of Feats">
  <Name>Giveaway Spell</Name>
  <Types Types="">
  </Types>
  <Benefit>You transfer the control over a spell to another willing creature that you touch at the time of casting.  This changes the beneficiary of spells like charm person or transfers the control of a spell like levitate or flaming sphere.  Read you in the spell description as the beneficiary of the giveaway spell.  This does not work on spells with a Personal range. You may still select yourself as the beneficiary, in which case this feat has no effect beyond increasing the level of spell slot.</Benefit>
  <Special>In all other ways, the spell functions as normal; save DC and level-dependent functions are based on your abilities.  You still make all the decisions inherent in casting the spell, such as what the (initial) target is, but if the effect can be moved (for example flaming sphere), the creature in control decides how.  You must still be the once concentrating to maintain a concentration spell, but the beneficiary can opt to end a dismissable {duration notation "(D)"} or concentration spell at his whim. A Giveaway Spell uses up a spell slot one level higher than the spell's actual level.</Special>
  <Source ID="0"/>
</Feat>
<Feat ID="134" Author="" Copyright="COPYRIGHT 2000, System Reference Document" Reference="System Reference Document">
  <Name>Great Cleave</Name>
  <Types Types="">
  </Types>
  <Prerequisites>Str 13+, Power Attack, Cleave, base attack bonus +4 or higher.</Prerequisites>
  <Benefit>As Cleave, except that the character has no limit to the number of times the character can use it per round.</Benefit>
  <Source ID="0"/>
</Feat>
<Feat ID="135" Author="" Copyright="COPYRIGHT 2000, System Reference Document" Reference="System Reference Document">
  <Name>Great Fortitude</Name>
  <Types Types="">
  </Types>
  <Benefit>The character gets a +2 bonus to all Fortitude saving throws.</Benefit>
  <Source ID="0"/>
</Feat>
<Feat ID="136" Author="" Copyright="COPYRIGHT 2001, Bradley H. Bemis Jr." Reference="Net Book of Feats">
  <Name>Greater Divine Dominion</Name>
  <Types Types="">
  </Types>
  <Prerequisites>Divine Dominion</Prerequisites>
  <Benefit>You gain the domain powers from the domain selected using the Divine Domain feat.</Benefit>
  <Special>This feat is only usable by clerics and can only be taken once.</Special>
  <Source ID="0"/>
</Feat>
<Feat ID="137" Author="" Copyright="COPYRIGHT 2001, Eric D. Harry" Reference="Net Book of Feats">
  <Name>Greater Focused Primeval Ability</Name>
  <Types Types="">
  </Types>
  <Prerequisites>Innate supernatural or spell-like ability, Focused Primeval Ability.</Prerequisites>
  <Benefit>Choose one innate supernatural or spell-like ability that you have augmented with the Focused Primeval Ability feat.  Add +4 to the Difficulty Class for all saving throws made to resist this ability. This bonus supercedes (i.e., does not stack with) the bonus provided by the Focused Spell-Like Ability feat.</Benefit>
  <Special>The creature can take this feat multiple times but its benefits do not stack.  Each time that it is taken the creature must apply it to another of its innate supernatural or spell-like abilities that has been augmented with the Focused Primeval Ability feat. This feat cannot be used with class based spell-like abilities, like the druid's wild shape or paladin's ability to cure disease.</Special>
  <Source ID="0"/>
</Feat>
<Feat ID="138" Author="" Copyright="COPYRIGHT 2000, Bradley H. Bemis Jr." Reference="Net Book of Feats">
  <Name>Greater Held Charge</Name>
  <Types Types="">
  </Types>
  <Benefit>You can hold a charged touch spell and still cast a spell.  The charge may not be released in the same round as the new spell has been cast, but you do maintain the charge.  The number of times this feat can be used while a specific spell is charged is equal to the caster's constitution modifier.  Once you have cast that many additional spells, if you cast another, the charged spell dissipates as normal.  Spells cast using this feat take up a spell slot one level higher.</Benefit>
  <Normal>If you are holding a spell charge for a touch attack and cast another spell, the spell charge for the touch spell dissipates.</Normal>
  <Notes>Casting another touch spell will override this feat.  You are only considered 'armed' when you attempt to use the touch attack itself, otherwise, you will draw an attack of opportunity as normal.  If you fail a concentration check while maintaining this charge, the charge will fail normally.</Notes>
  <Source ID="0"/>
</Feat>
<Feat ID="140" Author="" Copyright="COPYRIGHT 2001, Eric D. Harry" Reference="Net Book of Feats">
  <Name>Greater Psionic Attack Focus</Name>
  <Types Types="">
  </Types>
  <Prerequisites>Cha 13+, Mental Adversary, Psionic Attack Focus (chosen psionic attack mode).</Prerequisites>
  <Benefit>This feat mimics the Greater Psionic Focus feat, except that it applies to one known psionic attack mode of your choice.  Add +4 to the DC for all Will saves in psionic combat from the psionic attack mode chosen as your Psionic Attack Focus.  This bonus supercedes (does not stack with) the bonus provided by the Psionic Attack Focus feat.</Benefit>
  <Special>You can choose this feat up to five times, each time applying the bonus to a different psionic attack mode.  This feat does not allow you to discover additional psionic attack modes and can only be applied to a psionic attack mode previously discovered and already mastered with the Psionic Attack Focus feat.  A Mind Flayer can choose Psionic Attack Focus and Greater Psionic Attack Focus with its mind blast ability, becoming a fearsome opponent for even the most capable party of adventurers.</Special>
  <Source ID="0"/>
</Feat>
<Feat ID="141" Author="" Copyright="COPYRIGHT 2000, Michael J. Kletch" Reference="Net Book of Feats">
  <Name>Hardened Spell</Name>
  <Types Types="">
  </Types>
  <Prerequisites>Spell Focus in the appropriate school</Prerequisites>
  <Benefit>If the same spell or a reverse effect spell is used as a counterspell to your Hardened Spell, the counterspell is ineffective.  If Dispel Magic or a similar spell or effect is used as a counterspell, the DC for the dispel check is increased by +4.  If you are forced to make any Concentration checks while casting the Hardened Spell, your rolls for those checks gain a +2 bonus.</Benefit>
  <Special>You may take this feat multiple times.  Each time that you take his feat, you get an additional +2 bonus to the DC of the dispel check and an additional +2 bonus to your Concentration checks when and as appropriate.</Special>
  <Source ID="0"/>
</Feat>
<Feat ID="142" Author="" Copyright="COPYRIGHT 2001, Bradley H. Bemis Jr." Reference="Net Book of Feats">
  <Name>Hardy Brawler</Name>
  <Types Types="">
  </Types>
  <Prerequisites>Toughness</Prerequisites>
  <Benefit>You gain a subdual-based damage reduction equal to your constitution modifier.  This only applies to subdual damage.</Benefit>
  <Special>This feat cannot be used against magical weapons or attacks.
Example: If you have a constitution modifier of +3, you can subtract the first three points of subdual damage from each subdual attack.  If a punch only did 2 points of subdual damage, you would take no damage from the strike.  If a punch did 5 points of subdual damage, you would only suffer 2 of those 5 points.</Special>
  <Source ID="0"/>
</Feat>
<Feat ID="143" Author="" Copyright="COPYRIGHT 2001, Eric D. Harry" Reference="Net Book of Feats">
  <Name>Heighten Primeval Ability</Name>
  <Types Types="">
  </Types>
  <Prerequisites>Innate supernatural or spell-like ability.</Prerequisites>
  <Benefit>Choose one of your supernatural abilities or all of your spell-like abilities.  You can use this chosen ability or abilities at +1 level of experience.</Benefit>
  <Special>This feat cannot be used with class based spell-like abilities, like the druid's wild shape or paladin's ability to cure disease.  This feat can be chosen more than once and will stack with itself.</Special>
  <Source ID="0"/>
</Feat>
<Feat ID="144" Author="" Copyright="COPYRIGHT 2000, System Reference Document" Reference="System Reference Document">
  <Name>Heighten Spell</Name>
  <Types Types="">
  </Types>
  <Benefit>A heightened spell has a higher spell level than normal (up to 9th level). Unlike other metamagic feats, Heighten Spell actually increases the effective level of the spell that it modifies. All effects dependent on spell level (such as saving throw DCs and ability to penetrate a minor globe of invulnerability) are calculated according to the heightened level. The heightened spell is as difficult to prepare and cast as a spell of its effective level.</Benefit>
  <Source ID="0"/>
</Feat>
<Feat ID="145" Author="" Copyright="COPYRIGHT 2001, Eric D. Harry" Reference="Net Book of Feats">
  <Name>Herculean Effort</Name>
  <Types Types="">
  </Types>
  <Benefit>You can add +4 to your Strength attribute for purposes of lifting and carrying weight and for figuring your Strength bonus on ability checks for a number of rounds equal to 3 plus your Constitution modifier.  After this time you are fatigued (-2 to Strength,  -2 to Dexterity, can't run or charge) for the rest of the encounter.  Your increased strength does not affect attack or damage rolls, combat maneuvers like Grapple, Bull Rush and Trip, and does not increase your strength bonus on skill checks.</Benefit>
  <Source ID="0"/>
</Feat>
<Feat ID="146" Author="" Copyright="COPYRIGHT 2001, B. Marcus Lindberg" Reference="Net Book of Feats">
  <Name>Heroic Evasion</Name>
  <Types Types="">
  </Types>
  <Prerequisites>Great Fortitude, Iron Will, Lightning Reflexes</Prerequisites>
  <Benefit>You may reroll a check or save you just made and apply a insight bonus equal to your charisma modifier. You may do this once per day. You must take the result of the reroll, even if it's worse than the original roll.</Benefit>
  <Source ID="0"/>
</Feat>
<Feat ID="147" Author="" Copyright="COPYRIGHT 2000, Sigfried Trent" Reference="Net Book of Feats">
  <Name>Heroic Recovery</Name>
  <Types Types="">
  </Types>
  <Prerequisites>Con 13+</Prerequisites>
  <Benefit>When you fall below 0 hit points you do not continue to bleed (i.e. take 1 point of damage each round).  This feat does not prevent you from dying when you have -10 hit points or less.</Benefit>
  <Notes>I wanted to simulate the "We left him for dead, but he came back and kicked our butts." shtick.</Notes>
  <Source ID="0"/>
</Feat>
<Feat ID="148" Author="" Copyright="COPYRIGHT 2001, Carl Cramér" Reference="Net Book of Feats">
  <Name>Hide Tracks</Name>
  <Types Types="">
  </Types>
  <Prerequisites>Track.</Prerequisites>
  <Benefit>You can conceal the tracks you and your companions make while moving. Add your skill bonus in wilderness lore to the difficulty of following your tracks. You can move at full speed while hiding tracks; if you move at half speed, you impose the additional +5 DC modifier on tracking rolls noted in the Track description, PHB.</Benefit>
  <Normal>Anyone can use the wilderness lore skill to remove the traces at a campsite or the search skill to hide clues at a location.</Normal>
  <Source ID="0"/>
</Feat>
<Feat ID="149" Author="" Copyright="COPYRIGHT 2001, Carl Cramér" Reference="Net Book of Feats">
  <Name>Hole In The Middle</Name>
  <Types Types="">
  </Types>
  <Benefit>When you cast an area spell in such a way that you are in the area affected, you can create a hole in the area around yourself to avoid being affected by your own spell. Anyone who occupies your square (for example grappling you or being small enough to fit between your feet or on your shoulder) is also unaffected. A Hole in the Middle spell uses up a spell slot one level higher than the spell's actual level.</Benefit>
  <Source ID="0"/>
</Feat>
<Feat ID="150" Author="" Copyright="COPYRIGHT 2000, Michael J. Kletch" Reference="Net Book of Feats">
  <Name>Impact Spell</Name>
  <Types Types="">
  </Types>
  <Prerequisites>Arcane spellcaster, Heighten Spell</Prerequisites>
  <Benefit>If you prepare a damage causing spell with a higher than normal level using the Heighten Spell metamagic feat, the maximum number of damage dice may be increased.  If the spell causes damage to one creature, or must be split among multiple creatures (e.g. Magic Missile), the revised maximum dice allowed is given in the second column (Single).  If the spell causes damage to any creatures that fall within its area of effect (e.g. Fireball), refer to the third column (Multiple) for the revised maximum dice allowed.
&lt;pre&gt;
New      Creatures         Affected
Level    Single            Multiple
2nd      10                5
3rd      10                10
4th      15                10
5th      15                15
6th      20                15
7th      20                20
8th      25                20
9th      25                25
&lt;/pre&gt;
This table is duplicated in part from the DMG.  It ignores the entry for 1st level.</Benefit>
  <Source ID="0"/>
</Feat>
<Feat ID="151" Author="" Copyright="COPYRIGHT 2000, System Reference Document" Reference="System Reference Document">
  <Name>Improved Bull Rush</Name>
  <Types Types="">
  </Types>
  <Prerequisites>Str 13+, Power Attack.</Prerequisites>
  <Benefit>When the character performs a bull rush, the character does not draw an attack of opportunity from the defender.</Benefit>
  <Source ID="0"/>
</Feat>
<Feat ID="152" Author="" Copyright="COPYRIGHT 2001, Carl Cramér" Reference="Net Book of Feats">
  <Name>Improved Caster Level</Name>
  <Types Types="">
  </Types>
  <Prerequisites>Multiclass spellcaster</Prerequisites>
  <Benefit>Your caster level in one spellcasting class is increased by one, but no higher than your character level.</Benefit>
  <Special>This feat can be learned several times and stacks with itself.
Example: Yushu is a fifth level sorcerer. She advances in character level to six, and decides to advance as a rogue. She also acquires a new feat, and picks this one. Her caster level as a sorcerer is now sixth, so her fireball has range of 640' and does six dice of damage, but the number of spells she can cast and learn are still those of a fifth level sorcerer.</Special>
  <Notes>This means that a multiclass spellcaster can increase the power of his spells up to his character level. It does not allow you to learn, prepare, or cast more spells. Your caster level as a Paladin or Ranger (or any other class whose caster level is half the class level) cannot be improved past half your character level.</Notes>
  <Source ID="0"/>
</Feat>
<Feat ID="153" Author="" Copyright="COPYRIGHT 2000, Michael J. Kletch" Reference="Net Book of Feats">
  <Name>Improved Combat Focus</Name>
  <Types Types="">
  </Types>
  <Prerequisites>Combat Focus</Prerequisites>
  <Benefit>When using the Combat Focus feat, you may specify two opponents to focus against.  Against the second, you have neither bonuses nor penalties.</Benefit>
  <Source ID="0"/>
</Feat>
<Feat ID="154" Author="" Copyright="COPYRIGHT 2000, System Reference Document" Reference="System Reference Document">
  <Name>Improved Critical</Name>
  <Types Types="">
  </Types>
  <Prerequisites>Proficient with weapon, base attack bonus +8 or higher.</Prerequisites>
  <Benefit>When using the weapon the character selected, the character's threat range is doubled.</Benefit>
  <Special>The character can gain this feat multiple times. The effects do not stack. Each time the character takes the feat, it applies to a new weapon.</Special>
  <Notes>"Keen" magic weapons also double their normal, nonmagical threat range. As with all doubled doublings, the result is triple.</Notes>
  <Source ID="0"/>
</Feat>
<Feat ID="155" Author="" Copyright="COPYRIGHT 2001, Eric D. Harry" Reference="Net Book of Feats">
  <Name>Improved Crystal Psiweapon</Name>
  <Types Types="">
  </Types>
  <Prerequisites>Crystal Psiweapon</Prerequisites>
  <Benefit>Your crystal psiweapon gains one additional power chosen from the Psicrystal Special Abilities table on page 11 of the Psionics Handbook.  Your choose of powers is limited by your manifester level per the table.</Benefit>
  <Normal>A crystal psiweapon does not normally gain additional powers unless you have the psicrystal class ability.</Normal>
  <Special>You can choose this feat multiple times, each time incorporating a new psicrystal ability into your crystal psiweapon.</Special>
  <Source ID="0"/>
</Feat>
<Feat ID="156" Author="" Copyright="COPYRIGHT 2001, Carl Cramér" Reference="Net Book of Feats">
  <Name>Improved Deflect Arrows</Name>
  <Types Types="">
  </Types>
  <Prerequisites>Deflect Arrows, dexterity 13+.</Prerequisites>
  <Benefit>You may Deflect Arrows more than once each round.  Each attempt at deflection beyond the first counts as one of your attacks of opportunity for the round.</Benefit>
  <Source ID="0"/>
</Feat>
<Feat ID="157" Author="" Copyright="COPYRIGHT 2001, Michael J. Kletch" Reference="Net Book of Feats">
  <Name>Improved Deflect Attack</Name>
  <Types Types="">
  </Types>
  <Prerequisites>Str 13+, Int 13+, Power Attack, Sunder, Expertise, Combat Reflexes, Deflect Attack</Prerequisites>
  <Benefit>When using Deflect Attack, you ignore the -4 penalty to attack normally associated with Fighting Defensively.  This does not affect any other attacks you make while Fighting Defensively.</Benefit>
  <Source ID="0"/>
</Feat>
<Feat ID="158" Author="" Copyright="COPYRIGHT 2000, System Reference Document" Reference="System Reference Document">
  <Name>Improved Disarm</Name>
  <Types Types="">
  </Types>
  <Prerequisites>Int 13+, Expertise.</Prerequisites>
  <Benefit>The character does not suffer an attack of opportunity when the character attempts to disarm an opponent, nor does the opponent have a chance to disarm.</Benefit>
  <Source ID="0"/>
</Feat>
<Feat ID="159" Author="" Copyright="COPYRIGHT 2001, Carl Cramér" Reference="Net Book of Feats">
  <Name>Improved Dodge</Name>
  <Types Types="">
  </Types>
  <Prerequisites>Dexterity 13+, Dodge.</Prerequisites>
  <Benefit>The dodge bonus to Armor Class that you receive from the Dodge feat now applies against all attacks, not only those of one specific opponent.</Benefit>
  <Source ID="0"/>
</Feat>
<Feat ID="160" Author="" Copyright="COPYRIGHT 2001, Albert Nakano (Bertman4)" Reference="Net Book of Feats">
  <Name>Improved Far Shot</Name>
  <Types Types="">
  </Types>
  <Prerequisites>Point Blank Shot, Far Shot, base attack bonus +2</Prerequisites>
  <Benefit>You gain a +2 bonus that only works to negate range-based penalties.</Benefit>
  <Notes>This feat is not very useful for player characters but would be very useful for NPCs in mass combat situations.</Notes>
  <Source ID="0"/>
</Feat>
<Feat ID="161" Author="" Copyright="COPYRIGHT 2001, Carl Cramér" Reference="Net Book of Feats">
  <Name>Improved Feint</Name>
  <Types Types="">
  </Types>
  <Prerequisites>Bluff skill.</Prerequisites>
  <Benefit>You can now feint in combat as a movement-equivalent action rather than a standard action. You still use the bluff skill to feint and the target must be in your threatened zone. If you use this option, you must expose yourself in order to make such a quick feint, trigger attacks of opportunity if your bluff roll fails.</Benefit>
  <Notes>This is mainly a benefit to rogues, who can sneak attack a target that has been feinted. The risk of an opportunity attack makes this about as dangerous as tumbling.</Notes>
  <Source ID="0"/>
</Feat>
<Feat ID="162" Author="" Copyright="COPYRIGHT 2001, Eric D. Harry" Reference="Net Book of Feats">
  <Name>Improved Inertial Armor</Name>
  <Types Types="">
  </Types>
  <Prerequisites>Inertial Armor, reserve power points 4+.</Prerequisites>
  <Benefit>Increase the armor bonus of your Inertial Armor by +2.</Benefit>
  <Special>This feat can be taken multiple times.  Each time increases your armor bonus by 2 and increases your prerequisite reserve power points by 6.  For instance, if you take Improved Inertial Armor three times, your armor bonus is +10 when your power points are 18 or more, +8 when your power points are 11 or more, +6 when your power points are 4 or more and +4 when your power points are 1 or more.</Special>
  <Source ID="0"/>
</Feat>
<Feat ID="163" Author="" Copyright="COPYRIGHT 2000, System Reference Document" Reference="System Reference Document">
  <Name>Improved Initiative</Name>
  <Types Types="">
  </Types>
  <Benefit>The character gets a +4 bonus on initiative checks.</Benefit>
  <Source ID="0"/>
</Feat>
<Feat ID="164" Author="" Copyright="COPYRIGHT 2001, Eric D. Harry" Reference="Net Book of Feats">
  <Name>Improved Power Double Weapon</Name>
  <Types Types="">
  </Types>
  <Prerequisites>Double Weapon Fighting, Power Attack, Power Double Weapon, base attack bonus +6 or higher.</Prerequisites>
  <Benefit>When wielding a double weapon, you add one and one-half your Strength bonus to damage rolls with both your primary attack(s) and secondary attack(s).</Benefit>
  <Normal>Without this feat you add your full Strength bonus to damage rolls with your primary attacks and half your Strength bonus to damage rolls with your secondary attack.</Normal>
  <Source ID="0"/>
</Feat>
<Feat ID="165" Author="" Copyright="COPYRIGHT 2001, Eric D. Harry" Reference="Net Book of Feats">
  <Name>Improved Psionic Fist</Name>
  <Types Types="">
  </Types>
  <Prerequisites>Str 13+, Psionic Fist, base attack bonus 3+</Prerequisites>
  <Benefit>At the cost of 2 power points, your next unarmed strike deals +1d6 points of bludgeoning damage.  You must decide whether or not to spend these power points prior to your attack, and the points are wasted if the attack misses.  Your hands and feet remain charged with psychic power for a number of rounds equal to your Strength modifier + 1 or until your next unarmed attack, whichever occurs first.  You can charge your unarmed strikes with psionic power as a free action.</Benefit>
  <Special>This feat does not stack with Psionic Fist or Psionic Multifist; only one of the feats can be used at any one time.</Special>
  <Source ID="0"/>
</Feat>
<Feat ID="166" Author="" Copyright="COPYRIGHT 2001, Eric D. Harry" Reference="Net Book of Feats">
  <Name>Improved Psionic Shot</Name>
  <Types Types="">
  </Types>
  <Prerequisites>Str 13+, Point Blank Shot, Psionic Shot, base attack bonus 3+</Prerequisites>
  <Benefit>At the cost of 2 power points, your next ranged shot deals +1d6 points of piercing damage.  You must decide whether or not to spend these power points prior to your attack, and the points are wasted if the attack misses.  Your ammunition remains charged with psychic power for a number of rounds equal to your Strength modifier + 1 or until your next attack with the charged weapon, whichever occurs first.</Benefit>
  <Special>This feat does not stack with Psionic Shot or Psionic Multishot; only one of the feats can be used at any one time.</Special>
  <Source ID="0"/>
</Feat>
<Feat ID="167" Author="" Copyright="COPYRIGHT 2001, Eric D. Harry" Reference="Net Book of Feats">
  <Name>Improved Psionic Weapon</Name>
  <Types Types="">
  </Types>
  <Prerequisites>Str 13+, Power Attack, Psionic Weapon, base attack bonus 3+</Prerequisites>
  <Benefit>At the cost of 2 power points, your melee weapon deals +1d6 points of damage (slashing, piercing or bludgeoning as appropriate).  You must decide whether or not to spend these power points prior to your attack, and the points are wasted if the attack misses.  Your weapon remains charged with psychic power for a number of rounds equal to your Strength modifier + 1 or until your next attack with the charged weapon, whichever occurs first.</Benefit>
  <Special>This feat does not stack with Psionic Weapon Psionic Multiweapon; only one of the feats can be used at any one time.</Special>
  <Source ID="0"/>
</Feat>
<Feat ID="168" Author="" Copyright="COPYRIGHT 2001, Eric D. Harry" Reference="Net Book of Feats">
  <Name>Improved Rapid Metabolism</Name>
  <Types Types="">
  </Types>
  <Prerequisites>Con 13+, Rapid Metabolism.</Prerequisites>
  <Benefit>You can heal a number of hit points equal to your Con bonus even when active and involved in combat or spellcasting.</Benefit>
  <Normal>Hit points can only be regained per day of rest (light nonstrenuous activity, no combat or spellcasting) or complete bed rest.</Normal>
  <Special>Depending on your campaign, your D.M. may want to add this ability to the Rapid Metabolism feat without making it a feat in its own right.</Special>
  <Source ID="0"/>
</Feat>
<Feat ID="169" Author="" Copyright="COPYRIGHT 2000, Michael J. Kletch" Reference="Net Book of Feats">
  <Name>Improved Sneak Attack</Name>
  <Types Types="">
  </Types>
  <Prerequisites>Weapon Focus with the particular weapon</Prerequisites>
  <Benefit>If you roll a critical hit when making a sneak attack, the weapon damage is multiplied as normal for that weapon, but the sneak attack damage is also increased by +1d6.  For ranged weapons, this feat only applies to attacks with ranges up to 30 feet.</Benefit>
  <Normal>Sneak attack damage is not modified by critical hits.</Normal>
  <Special>You can take this feat multiple times.  Its effects do not stack.  Each time you take the feat, it applies to a new weapon.</Special>
  <Source ID="0"/>
</Feat>
<Feat ID="170" Author="" Copyright="COPYRIGHT 2001, Eric D. Harry" Reference="Net Book of Feats">
  <Name>Improved Spells Per Day</Name>
  <Types Types="">
  </Types>
  <Benefit>You can prepare or cast one additional spell per day of one chosen spell level that you can already cast.  Once chosen, the level of the additional spell is set and cannot be changed.</Benefit>
  <Special>You can choose this feat multiple times but may only prepare or cast one additional spell per day of each spell level that you can cast.</Special>
  <Source ID="0"/>
</Feat>
<Feat ID="171" Author="" Copyright="COPYRIGHT 2001, Scott Metzger" Reference="Net Book of Feats">
  <Name>Improved Subdual</Name>
  <Types Types="">
  </Types>
  <Prerequisites>Proficient in a bludgeoning weapon.</Prerequisites>
  <Benefit>When attacking with a bludgeoning weapon and attempting to do subdual damage you do not incur the usual penalties for attempting to do subdual damage.  Also, the weapons threat range is doubled when dealing subdual damage.</Benefit>
  <Source ID="0"/>
</Feat>
<Feat ID="172" Author="" Copyright="COPYRIGHT 2001, Rebecca Glenn (Becky)" Reference="Net Book of Feats">
  <Name>Improved Subdue</Name>
  <Types Types="">
  </Types>
  <Benefit>When using a weapon that does normal damage for a subdual attack, you are not subject to the normal -4 penalty to hit.</Benefit>
  <Normal>Characters striking to subdue with normal weapons do so at -4 to hit.</Normal>
  <Source ID="0"/>
</Feat>
<Feat ID="173" Author="" Copyright="COPYRIGHT 2001, Carl Cramér" Reference="Net Book of Feats">
  <Name>Improved Toughness</Name>
  <Types Types="">
  </Types>
  <Prerequisites>Toughness, base attack bonus +3 or higher.</Prerequisites>
  <Benefit>You gain +4 hit points, for a total feat bonus of +7 hit points.</Benefit>
  <Special>This feat allows you to gain a greater benefit compared to Toughness, but with a base attack bonus requirement.  It can be taken any number of times and stacks with itself and the hit point bonus provided by the Toughness feat.  Each time that it is taken after the first, increase the prerequisite base attack bonus for selecting the feat by +3 and increase the hit points provided by the feat by +1.</Special>
  <Notes>The following table sums up the requirements and bonuses of various levels of Toughness and Improved Toughness you can take up to level 20.
&lt;pre&gt;	
Feat   			       BAB   Bonus Total
Toughness    		     	 -     +3    +3
Improved Toughness 	       +3    +4    +7
Improved Toughness x2   	 +6    +5    +12
Improved Toughness x3   	 +9    +6    +18
Improved Toughness x4    	 +12   +7    +25
Improved Toughness x5	       +15   +8    +33
Improved Toughness x6	       +18   +9    +42&lt;/pre&gt;
</Notes>
  <Source ID="0"/>
</Feat>
<Feat ID="174" Author="" Copyright="COPYRIGHT 2000, System Reference Document" Reference="System Reference Document">
  <Name>Improved Trip</Name>
  <Types Types="">
  </Types>
  <Prerequisites>Int 13+, Expertise.</Prerequisites>
  <Benefit>If the character trips an opponent in melee combat, the character immediately gets a melee attack against that opponent as if the character hadn't used the character's attack for the trip attempt.</Benefit>
  <Source ID="0"/>
</Feat>
<Feat ID="176" Author="" Copyright="COPYRIGHT 2000, System Reference Document" Reference="System Reference Document">
  <Name>Improved Unarmed Strike</Name>
  <Types Types="">
  </Types>
  <Benefit>The character is considered to be armed even when unarmed-that is, armed opponents do not get attacks of opportunity when the character attacks them while unarmed. However, the character still gets an opportunity attack against any opponent who makes an unarmed attack on the character.</Benefit>
  <Special>A monk fighting unarmed automatically gains the benefit of this feat.</Special>
  <Source ID="0"/>
</Feat>
<Feat ID="177" Author="" Copyright="COPYRIGHT 2001, Carl Cramér" Reference="Net Book of Feats">
  <Name>Improvised Weapons</Name>
  <Types Types="">
  </Types>
  <Prerequisites>Base attack bonus +2</Prerequisites>
  <Benefit>When you use a weapon that you are not proficient with, or an improvised weapon for which no proficiency is possible, you suffer only a -2 penalty to hit.</Benefit>
  <Normal>The normal penalty in this situation is -4.</Normal>
  <Source ID="0"/>
</Feat>
<Feat ID="178" Author="" Copyright="COPYRIGHT 2001, Eric D. Harry" Reference="Net Book of Feats">
  <Name>Innate Metamagic</Name>
  <Types Types="">
  </Types>
  <Prerequisites>Int 11+, innate spell-like ability, ability to cast spells, one or more metamagic feats.</Prerequisites>
  <Benefit>The creature can modify any of its innate spell-like abilities with any spell altering metamagic feat that it knows.  In order to alter a spell-like ability in this manner, the creature must prepare (Wizards or Divine spellcasters) or spend (Sorcerer or Bard) a spell slot equal in level to the bonus level required for the metamagic feat in question (see examples below).  Casting a metamagically enhanced spell-like ability also counts as one or its uses of that spell-like ability per day.  Spontaneously casting a metamagically enhanced spell-like ability, like a Sorcerer or Bard, requires a full-round action (rather than 1-action).</Benefit>
  <Normal>Creatures cannot normally modify spell-like abilities with spell altering metamagic feats.</Normal>
  <Special>This feat does not provide knowledge of any other metamagic feat and it cannot be used with class based spell-like abilities, like the druid's wild shape or paladin's ability to cure disease.  Spell altering metamagic feats from Core Rulebook I include: Empower Spell, Enlarge Spell, Extend Spell, Heighten Spell, Maximize Spell, Quicken Spell, Silent Spell and Still Spell.  Because spell-like abilities are cast without need of verbal, somatic or material components, modifying a spell-like ability with Silent Spell or Still Spell provides no additional game related benefit.
Example: Spell slots for modifying a spell-like ability with a spell altering metamagic feat from Core Rulebook I are: Empower Spell (2nd level spell slot), Enlarge Spell (1st level spell slot), Extend Spell (1st level spell slot), Heighten Spell (+1 level spell slot per enhanced level), Maximize Spell (3rd level spell slot) and Quicken Spell (4th level spell slot).</Special>
  <Source ID="0"/>
</Feat>
<Feat ID="180" Author="" Copyright="COPYRIGHT 2001, Michael J. Kletch" Reference="Net Book of Feats">
  <Name>Inner Depths Of The Soul</Name>
  <Types Types="">
  </Types>
  <Prerequisites>Int 13+ Wis 13+, Cha 13+</Prerequisites>
  <Benefit>Any time you cast a spell with an XP cost, manifest a power with an XP cost or create a magic item, the XP cost is reduced by 10%.  Fractional XP costs are rounded up.</Benefit>
  <Special>A character may gain this feat multiple times.  Each time you take this feat beyond the first, the ability score requirements each increase by 2 and the XP cost discount is increased by 5%.
Example: At 6th level Garmand took Inner Depths of the Soul as his feat.  He met the prerequisites of 13 or higher in Intelligence, Wisdom and Charisma.  The XP cost discount is 10%.  At 9th level, he wishes to take the feat again.  He must meet the increased prerequisites of 15 or higher in Intelligence, Wisdom and Charisma.  If he does, then the feat will grant a total discount of 15% to XP costs.</Special>
  <Source ID="0"/>
</Feat>
<Feat ID="181" Author="" Copyright="COPYRIGHT 2000, Michael J. Kletch" Reference="Net Book of Feats">
  <Name>Inspiring Leader</Name>
  <Types Types="">
  </Types>
  <Prerequisites>Cha 13+, Leadership</Prerequisites>
  <Benefit>Your cohorts gain a +1 morale bonus to attack and damage and a +2 morale bonus to saving throws versus all fear effects and mind-affecting spells and abilities while you are personally directing their efforts.  This bonus will last for up to one minute without additional orders being given. All cohorts and followers within thirty feet gain a +1 morale bonus to attack and on saving throws versus all fear effects.  These bonuses remain in effect for up to one minute if you are dropped in combat.</Benefit>
  <Source ID="0"/>
</Feat>
<Feat ID="182" Author="" Copyright="COPYRIGHT 2001, Eric D. Harry" Reference="Net Book of Feats">
  <Name>Instant Awakening</Name>
  <Types Types="">
  </Types>
  <Benefit>When subject to surprise or a coup de grace attack while asleep, you may make an immediate Reflex save (DC 15) to awaken and defend yourself normally.  On a successful save you are not considered helpless or surprised; roll for initiative and resolve the attack in normal fashion.</Benefit>
  <Normal>A sleeping opponent is helpless (+4 circumstance bonus to strike, treat Dexterity as 0 and apply 5 modifier to Armor Class) and subject to a coup de grace attack.</Normal>
  <Source ID="0"/>
</Feat>
<Feat ID="183" Author="" Copyright="COPYRIGHT 2001, Eric D. Harry" Reference="Net Book of Feats">
  <Name>Intuitive Spell Knowledge</Name>
  <Types Types="">
  </Types>
  <Prerequisites>Ability to cast 1st level Arcane spells without preparation (like a Bard or Sorcerer).</Prerequisites>
  <Benefit>You can learn one additional spell of any level that you can cast.</Benefit>
  <Special>You can choose this feat multiple times but may only learn one additional spell per spell level.</Special>
  <Source ID="0"/>
</Feat>
<Feat ID="184" Author="" Copyright="COPYRIGHT 2000, System Reference Document" Reference="System Reference Document">
  <Name>Iron Will</Name>
  <Types Types="">
  </Types>
  <Benefit>The character gets a +2 bonus to all Will saving throws.</Benefit>
  <Source ID="0"/>
</Feat>
<Feat ID="185" Author="" Copyright="COPYRIGHT 2001, Eric D. Harry" Reference="Net Book of Feats">
  <Name>Ki Of The Masters</Name>
  <Types Types="">
  </Types>
  <Prerequisites>Wis 13+, Str 11+, Improved Unarmed Strike, Stunning Fists, base attack +3 or higher.</Prerequisites>
  <Benefit>On a successful unarmed strike you can add your Wisdom modifier instead of your Strength modifier to the damage roll.  This feat is an extraordinary ability.</Benefit>
  <Source ID="0"/>
</Feat>
<Feat ID="186" Author="" Copyright="COPYRIGHT 2000, System Reference Document" Reference="System Reference Document">
  <Name>Leadership</Name>
  <Types Types="">
  </Types>
  <Prerequisites>The character must be at least 6th level.</Prerequisites>
  <Benefit>Having this feat enables the character to attract loyal companions and devoted followers, subordinates who assist her. See Table: Leadership for what sort of cohort and how many followers the character can recruit.
&lt;pre&gt;Table: Leadership
Leadership	Cohort	-- Number of Followers by Level --
Score		Level	1st	2nd	3rd	4th	5th	6th
----------	------	---	---	---	---	---	---
1 or less	-	-	-	-	-	-	-
2		1st	-	-	-	-	-	-
3		2nd	-	-	-	-	-	-
4		3rd	-	-	-	-	-	-
5		3rd	-	-	-	-	-	-
6		4th	-	-	-	-	-	-
7		5th	-	-	-	-	-	-
8		5th	-	-	-	-	-	-
9		6th	-	-	-	-	-	-
10		7th	5	-	-	-	-	-
11		7th	6	-	-	-	-	-
12		8th	8	-	-	-	-	-
13		9th	10	1	-	-	-	-
14		10th	15	1	-	-	-	-
15		10th	20	2	1	-	-	-
16		11th	25	2	1	-	-	-
17		12th	30	3	1	1	-	-
18		12th	35	3	1	1	-	-
19		13th	40	4	2	1	1	-
20		14th	50	5	3	2	1	-
21		15th	60	6	3	2	1	1
22		15th	75	7	4	2	2	1
23		16th	90	9	5	3	2	1
24		17th	110	11	6	3	2	1
25+		17th	135	13	7	4	2	2
&lt;/pre&gt;
Leadership Score: A character's Leadership score equals his level plus any Charisma modifier. In order to take into account negative Charisma modifiers, Table: Leadership allows for very low Leadership scores, but the character must still be 6th level or higher in order to gain the Leadership feat and thus attract a cohort. Outside factors can affect a character's Leadership score, as detailed in Table: Leadership Modifiers.
Cohort Level: The character can attract a cohort of up to this level. Regardless of the character's Leadership score, he can't recruit a cohort of his level or higher.
Number of Followers by Level: The character can lead up to the indicated number of characters of each level. 
&lt;pre&gt;Table: Leadership Modifiers
General Leadership Modifiers
The Leader Has a Reputation of             Leadership Modifier
------------------------------             -------------------
Great prestige                                  +2
Fairness and generosity                         +1
Special power                                   +1
Failure                                         -1
Aloofness                                       -1
Cruelty                                         -2&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;Cohort-Only Leadership Modifiers
The Leader                                  Leadership Modifier
----------                                  -------------------
Has a familiar/paladin's warhorse/             -2 animal companion
Recruits a cohort of a different alignment     -1
Caused the death of a cohort                   -2*
*Cumulative per cohort killed.&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;Follower-Only Leadership Modifiers
The Leader                                  Leadership Modifier
----------                                  -------------------
Has a stronghold, base of operations,          +2 guildhouse, and so on
Moves around a lot                             -1
Caused the death of other followers            -1&lt;/pre&gt;
	</Benefit>
  <Special>With the DM's permission, a leader may seek out a special cohort who is not a member of the standard PC races (the common races).&lt;br&gt;&lt;/br&gt;
Replacing Cohorts and Followers: If a leader loses a cohort or followers, he can generally replace them, according to his current Leadership score. It takes time (1d4 months) to recruit replacements. If the leader is to blame for the deaths of the cohort or followers, it takes extra time to replace them, up to a full year. Note that the leader also picks up a reputation of failure, which decreases his Leadership score.</Special>
  <Source ID="0"/>
</Feat>
<Feat ID="187" Author="" Copyright="COPYRIGHT 2001, Eric D. Harry" Reference="Net Book of Feats">
  <Name>Learned Metamagic</Name>
  <Types Types="">
  </Types>
  <Prerequisites>Ability to cast Arcane spells without preparation (like a Bard or Sorcerer), Int 13+, Spellcraft 8+, Knowledge (arcana) 8+, metamagic feat.</Prerequisites>
  <Benefit>You can prepare metamagically-enhanced versions of spells that you know exactly like a Wizard.  Prepared metamagic spells take up a spellcasting slot of the appropriate level (against a Bard or Sorcerer's spells per day) until cast, per the base spell and metamagic feat used to augment it.  This spell slot cannot be used to cast another spell without wasting the prepared metamagic spell.   Only spells known by the Bard or Sorcerer can be prepared in this fashion, and preparing a metamagic spell takes a minimum amount of time equal to 15 minutes plus the enhanced levels of the spells prepared.  A prepared metamagic spell is cast exactly as if the spell were cast by a Wizard, per the normal casting time of the base spell, and once cast the metamagic spell cannot be recast without being prepared again.</Benefit>
  <Normal>Bards and Sorcerers do not normally prepare spells</Normal>
  <Special>This feat does not provide knowledge of any other metamagic feat.</Special>
  <Source ID="0"/>
</Feat>
<Feat ID="188" Author="" Copyright="COPYRIGHT 2000, Bradley H. Bemis Jr." Reference="Net Book of Feats">
  <Name>Learning Mastery</Name>
  <Types Types="">
  </Types>
  <Benefit>You can raise your skill point limit by one point (i.e. class level +4).</Benefit>
  <Normal>You are limited to your level +3 for the number of ranks you may have in a skill.</Normal>
  <Special>You do not gain any skill points from this feat, you only get to increase you maximum limit.  This affects both class and cross-class skills (cross-class skills are still based on ½ your max class skill ranks.  This feat can only be taken once.</Special>
  <Source ID="0"/>
</Feat>
<Feat ID="189" Author="" Copyright="COPYRIGHT 2000, Bradley H. Bemis Jr." Reference="Net Book of Feats">
  <Name>Learning Sacrifice</Name>
  <Types Types="">
  </Types>
  <Benefit>Rather than learning a feat, you may add an additional number of skill points to you character's skill point pool.  The number of skill points gained is equal to your intelligence modifier.</Benefit>
  <Special>You are still restricted in the number of skill points you can have in any one skill (based on level).  This feat may be taken multiple times.  The number of points gained is based on intelligence at the time the Skill Learning feat is taken.  Changes to intelligence after the fact do not impact the number of skill points gained.</Special>
  <Source ID="0"/>
</Feat>
<Feat ID="190" Author="" Copyright="COPYRIGHT 2001, Eric D. Harry" Reference="Net Book of Feats">
  <Name>Legendary Toughness</Name>
  <Types Types="">
  </Types>
  <Prerequisites>Con 13+, Great Fortitude, Toughness, base attack bonus +12 or higher</Prerequisites>
  <Benefit>You gain damage reduction 1/-, allowing you to negate the first point of damage that you suffer every time that you take hit point damage.  This can reduce the amount of damage that you suffer to 0 but never below 0.</Benefit>
  <Special>This feat can only be taken once and stacks with all other feats and abilities that provide damage reduction.</Special>
  <Source ID="0"/>
</Feat>
<Feat ID="191" Author="" Copyright="COPYRIGHT 2001, Carl Cramér" Reference="Net Book of Feats">
  <Name>Lethal Fist</Name>
  <Types Types="">
  </Types>
  <Prerequisites>Improved Unarmed Strike (feat or monk class ability).</Prerequisites>
  <Benefit>You can opt to do normal or subdual damage with unarmed and grappling attacks.</Benefit>
  <Special>Monks already have this as a class ability.</Special>
  <Source ID="0"/>
</Feat>
<Feat ID="192" Author="" Copyright="COPYRIGHT 2000, Bradley H. Bemis Jr." Reference="Net Book of Feats">
  <Name>Life Line</Name>
  <Types Types="">
  </Types>
  <Benefit>When dying, your chance to stabilize is 10% for each point of your constitution modifier. Likewise, all recovery efforts, whether aided or unaided are also 10% for each point of your constitution modifier.</Benefit>
  <Normal>The chance to stabilize is 10%</Normal>
  <Source ID="0"/>
</Feat>
<Feat ID="193" Author="" Copyright="COPYRIGHT 2001, Carl Cramér" Reference="Net Book of Feats">
  <Name>Light Sleeper</Name>
  <Types Types="">
  </Types>
  <Benefit>You can make listen rolls even while asleep. On a successful roll, you wake up. You also fall asleep easily, so you still get your rest even if you wake up several times per night.</Benefit>
  <Source ID="0"/>
</Feat>
<Feat ID="194" Author="" Copyright="COPYRIGHT 2000, System Reference Document" Reference="System Reference Document">
  <Name>Lightning Reflexes</Name>
  <Types Types="">
  </Types>
  <Benefit>The character gets a +2 bonus to all Reflex saving throws.</Benefit>
  <Source ID="0"/>
</Feat>
<Feat ID="243" Author="" Copyright="COPYRIGHT 2001, Eric D. Harry" Reference="Net Book of Feats">
  <Name>Like Abilities</Name>
  <Types Types="">
  </Types>
  <Prerequisites>Innate spell-like ability.</Prerequisites>
  <Benefit>When using any of its innate spell-like abilities, add +1 to the Difficulty Class for all saving throws made to resist the ability and add +1 to any caster level check made to overcome another creature's spell resistance.</Benefit>
  <Special>This feat cannot be used with class based spell-like abilities, like the druid's wild shape or paladin's ability to cure disease.</Special>
  <Source ID="0"/>
</Feat>
<Feat ID="315" Author="" Copyright="COPYRIGHT 2001, Eric D. Harry" Reference="Net Book of Feats">
  <Name>Like Casting</Name>
  <Types Types="">
  </Types>
  <Prerequisites>Innate spell like ability, ability to cast spells.</Prerequisites>
  <Benefit>The creature can use its class derived spell slots or prepared spells to spontaneously cast any of its spell-like abilities in a manner similar to the way a cleric can spontaneously cast cure or inflict spells.  This allows the creature to convert one of its spell slots or prepared spells of the same level or higher to power the casting of the spell-like ability without using up one of the spell-like ability's uses per day.  The spell-like ability must appear on the same spell list as the spell slot or prepared spell used to power the casting.  A spontaneously cast spell-like ability requires a full-round action but does not require any material, somatic or verbal components.</Benefit>
  <Special>This feat cannot be used to spontaneously cast spell-like abilities that do not have a spell level.</Special>
  <Source ID="0"/>
</Feat>
<Feat ID="139" Author="" Copyright="COPYRIGHT 2001, Eric D. Harry" Reference="Net Book of Feats">
  <Name>Like Penetration</Name>
  <Types Types="">
  </Types>
  <Prerequisites>Innate spell-like ability, Innate Spell Penetration.</Prerequisites>
  <Benefit>The creature gains a +4 bonus to caster level checks (1d20+caster level) to overcome a creature's spell resistance. This bonus supercedes (i.e., does not stack with) the bonus provided by the Innate Spell-Like Penetration feat.</Benefit>
  <Special>This feat cannot be used with class based spell-like abilities, like the druid's wild shape or paladin's ability to cure disease.</Special>
  <Source ID="0"/>
</Feat>
<Feat ID="179" Author="" Copyright="COPYRIGHT 2001, Eric D. Harry" Reference="Net Book of Feats">
  <Name>Like Penetration</Name>
  <Types Types="">
  </Types>
  <Prerequisites>Innate spell-like ability.</Prerequisites>
  <Benefit>Similar in effect to the Spell Penetration feat, the creature gains a +2 bonus to caster level checks (1d20+caster level) to overcome a creature's spell resistance with its spell-like abilities.</Benefit>
  <Special>This feat cannot be used with class based spell-like abilities, like the druid's wild shape or paladin's ability to cure disease.</Special>
  <Source ID="0"/>
</Feat>
<Feat ID="195" Author="" Copyright="COPYRIGHT 2000, Bradley H. Bemis Jr." Reference="Net Book of Feats">
  <Name>Linked Learning</Name>
  <Types Types="">
  </Types>
  <Prerequisites>5 or more ranks in both skills to be linked</Prerequisites>
  <Benefit>Choose any two skills, regardless of relationship and gain a +2 synergy bonus to one of them.  This relationship should be established through the character's history, or a role-playing development.  All links are based on the discretion of the DM and should make sense based on the story created.</Benefit>
  <Special>This feat does not stack with skills that already have synergy bonuses.</Special>
  <Source ID="0"/>
</Feat>
<Feat ID="196" Author="" Copyright="COPYRIGHT 2001, Carl Cramér" Reference="Net Book of Feats">
  <Name>Magic Secret</Name>
  <Types Types="">
  </Types>
  <Benefit>Because all your magic is tied to a secret, those not knowing this secret find it harder to unravel your spells. The difficulty of any dispel check against your spells is 15 + your caster level instead of the normal 10 + caster level. But the drawback is that anyone who knows your magical secret will automatically succeed in any dispel check against your magic.</Benefit>
  <Special>The effects of the spells are not changed in any way. The feat affects all your spells from the moment you learn it; you cannot avoid using it</Special>
  <Notes>A magical secret can be most anything, but it must be something that is possible to figure out. A secret name, your birthday, the name of your mentor or patron, the fact that you are of a strange race or parentage, your sex (or lack thereof), the true color of your hair; all are possible spell secrets. Anyone researching your background or making their knowledge skill roll about you will learn you have this feat, but not what your exact secret is.</Notes>
  <Source ID="0"/>
</Feat>
<Feat ID="197" Author="" Copyright="COPYRIGHT 2001, Carl Cramér" Reference="Net Book of Feats">
  <Name>Main Gauche</Name>
  <Types Types="">
  </Types>
  <Prerequisites>Two-Weapon Fighting</Prerequisites>
  <Benefit>If you are using a light off-hand weapon, or even holding a buckler, hat or rolled up cloak in your off hand, you can use your off-hand weapon to defend. It also works with a double weapon. You must make a full-round attack, and you are giving up all off-hand attacks for the round. This gives you a +4 bonus to Armor Class and a -2 penalty to attack.</Benefit>
  <Special>If you use a buckler this way, you do not get its normal armor bonus.</Special>
  <Notes>Main Gauche means simply 'left hand', but it is often applied to a left-hand parrying dagger and the fighting style that goes with it. The forerunner of modern fencing, it uses an off hand weapon to deflect attacks, but not to attack with. This feat represent the very earliest fencing styles, and is appropriate for an early renaissance campaign.</Notes>
  <Source ID="0"/>
</Feat>
<Feat ID="198" Author="" Copyright="COPYRIGHT 2001, Sigfried Trent" Reference="Net Book of Feats">
  <Name>Manic Depressive</Name>
  <Types Types="">
  </Types>
  <Benefit>Each morning you must make a percentage roll to determine whether you are manic or depressed.  If you roll above 50% you are manic and gain a +2 morale bonus to all saves and charisma for the rest of the day.  If you roll below 50% you suffer a -2 penalty to all saves and charisma for the rest of the day.</Benefit>
  <Notes>I know this simple mechanic doesn't handle the complexity of the condition and to properly play it the player should role-play the personality change the character undergoes.  I don't think it's a great feat, and it is outside the scope of a typical feat, but it could be interesting to play.  This feat should either be taken at character creation or in response to some traumatic life event.</Notes>
  <Source ID="0"/>
</Feat>
<Feat ID="199" Author="" Copyright="COPYRIGHT 2000, System Reference Document" Reference="System Reference Document">
  <Name>Martial Weapon Proficiency</Name>
  <Types Types="">
  </Types>
  <Benefit>The character makes attack rolls with the weapon normally.</Benefit>
  <Normal>A character who uses a weapon without being proficient with it suffers a -4 penalty on attack rolls.</Normal>
  <Notes>The character can gain this feat multiple times. Each time the character takes the feat, it applies to a new weapon.
A cleric whose deity's favored weapon is a martial weapon and who chooses War as one of his domains receives the Martial Weapon Proficiency feat related to that weapon for free, as well as the Weapon Focus feat related to that weapon.</Notes>
  <Source ID="0"/>
</Feat>
<Feat ID="200" Author="" Copyright="COPYRIGHT 2001, Eric D. Harry" Reference="Net Book of Feats">
  <Name>Maximize Psionic Attack</Name>
  <Types Types="">
  </Types>
  <Prerequisites>Cha 13+, Mental Adversary</Prerequisites>
  <Benefit>You inflict maximum ability point damage on a successful psionic attack with any of your psionic attack modes.  Maximized psionic attacks cost a number of power points equal to the cost of the psionic attack mode +8.  Unlike the Mental Adversary feat, these power points must be spent on initiating the maximized psionic attack mode, prior to determining the success or failure of the attack.  On a failed attack these points are lost.</Benefit>
  <Source ID="0"/>
</Feat>
<Feat ID="201" Author="" Copyright="COPYRIGHT 2000, System Reference Document" Reference="System Reference Document">
  <Name>Maximize Spell</Name>
  <Types Types="">
  </Types>
  <Benefit>All variable, numeric effects of a maximized spell are maximized. A maximized spell deals maximum damage, cures the maximum number of hit points, affects the maximum number of targets, etc., as appropriate. Spells without random variables are not affected. A maximized spell uses up a spell slot three levels higher than the spell's actual level.
An empowered, maximized spell gains the separate benefits of each feat: the maximum result plus one-half the normally rolled result.</Benefit>
  <Source ID="0"/>
</Feat>
<Feat ID="202" Author="" Copyright="COPYRIGHT 2001, Eric D. Harry" Reference="Net Book of Feats">
  <Name>Metaffinity</Name>
  <Types Types="">
  </Types>
  <Prerequisites>Ability to cast Arcane spells without preparation (like a Bard or Sorcerer), at least one other metamagic feat.</Prerequisites>
  <Benefit>Despite the fact that you do not prepare spells, you are able to cast any spell augmented by any other metamagic feat that you know without increasing the spell's casting time. Spells quickly cast through use of this feat use up a spell slot one level higher than the spell's metamagically enhanced level.</Benefit>
  <Normal>Sorcerers, Bards and other Arcane spellcasters that do not prepare spells normally take more time to cast a metamagic spell than a normal one.  If a spell's normal casting time is 1-action, a Sorcerer or Bard can cast a metamagically-enhanced version of the spell as a full-round action.  With the Metaffinity feat, you are able to cast the same metamagically-enhanced spell in 1-action.</Normal>
  <Special>This feat can be combined with the Quicken Spell feat, a feat not normally useful to Sorcerers and Bards.
Example: Aerryk, a 17th level Sorcerer, has the Metaffinity, Quicken Spell and Maximize Spell feats.  He can cast a maximized Lightning Bolt spell as a full- round action by using up a 6th level spell slot or use his Metaffinity feat to cast a maximized Lightning Bolt in 1-action by using up a 7th level spell slot.  He could also use his Metaffinity feat to cast a quickened Lightning Bolt as a free action by using up an 8th level spell slot, but would not be able to maximize the spell.</Special>
  <Source ID="0"/>
</Feat>
<Feat ID="203" Author="" Copyright="COPYRIGHT 2001, Eric D. Harry" Reference="Net Book of Feats">
  <Name>Metaspell</Name>
  <Types Types="">
  </Types>
  <Prerequisites>Ability to cast Arcane spells without preparation (like a Bard or Sorcerer).</Prerequisites>
  <Benefit>When you gain new spells, you have the option of learning a metamagically-enhanced spell in place of another spell of the appropriate level.  This spell takes up a spell-slot appropriate for the normal level of the spell, modified by the metamagic feat used to augment the spell.  You do not need to know the base spell nor the metamagic feat used to modify the spell in order to use this feat.  Once a metamagically-enhanced spell is learned in this manner, you cannot cast the spell without its metamagic enhancement, though you can augment the spell in standard fashion with additional metamagic feats.  A metamagic spell learned in this fashion is cast as if the spellcaster were a Wizard, without increasing the time needed to cast the spell.
Example: A Sorcerer normally gains a 5th level spell on attaining 10th level.  Instead of learning a standard 5th level spell, a Sorcerer with the Metaspell feat could learn an Empowered Fireball spell (3rd level spell +2 spell levels for the Empower feat).</Benefit>
  <Source ID="0"/>
</Feat>
<Feat ID="204" Author="" Copyright="COPYRIGHT 2001, Carl Cramér" Reference="Net Book of Feats">
  <Name>Mimicry</Name>
  <Types Types="">
  </Types>
  <Prerequisites>Perform (with training as a mimic).</Prerequisites>
  <Benefit>As a standard action, you can imitate almost any sound (footsteps, a door opening or closing, or two people fighting). You cannot simulate anything louder than a shout or duplicate the sound of any magical effect like a banshee's wail. Use the perform skill opposed by the audience's listen skill to be convincing.</Benefit>
  <Normal>Any performer capable of mimicking can imitate voices and common animal sounds. Imitating speech patterns and mannerisms is covered under the disguise skill.</Normal>
  <Special>You cannot make the sounds appear to come from somewhere else without additional abilities beside this feat.</Special>
  <Source ID="0"/>
</Feat>
<Feat ID="206" Author="" Copyright="COPYRIGHT 2000, Bradley H. Bemis Jr." Reference="Net Book of Feats">
  <Name>Mindless Effort</Name>
  <Types Types="">
  </Types>
  <Prerequisites>10 or more ranks in Concentration</Prerequisites>
  <Benefit>A concentration based spell cast using this feat can continue to function without concentration for a period of rounds equal to your primary ability modifier.  If there is already a modifier to the duration of the spell once concentration has ceased, you may add your modifier to that duration.  This spell takes up a spell slot one level higher.</Benefit>
  <Source ID="0"/>
</Feat>
<Feat ID="207" Author="" Copyright="COPYRIGHT 2001, Albert Nakano (Bertman4)" Reference="Net Book of Feats">
  <Name>Minor Spell Mastery</Name>
  <Types Types="">
  </Types>
  <Prerequisites>spellcasting level 3+ (divine or arcane)</Prerequisites>
  <Benefit>You must permanently sacrifice one 0-level spell slot. In exchange, you can cast one 0-level spell of your choice as a spell-like ability a number of times per day equal to your governing ability modifier.</Benefit>
  <Special>You may take this feat multiple times, each time with a different 0-level spell.
Example: A 9th level Bard with 19 Charisma decides to take this feat. He picks detect magic spell to master.  Normally, he can cast three 0-level spells per day. Now, he can only prepare and cast two 0-level spells. However, he can cast detect magic 4 times per day as a spell-like ability.</Special>
  <Source ID="0"/>
</Feat>
<Feat ID="208" Author="" Copyright="COPYRIGHT 2000, Michael J. Kletch" Reference="Net Book of Feats">
  <Name>Missile Proof</Name>
  <Types Types="">
  </Types>
  <Prerequisites>Combat Reflexes, Shield Proficiency.</Prerequisites>
  <Benefit>You must be using a Buckler, Small Shield or Large Shield when using this feat.  Once per round when you or someone immediately behind you would normally be hit with a ranged weapon, you may make a Reflex saving throw against a DC of 20 (if the ranged weapon has a magical bonus to attack, the DC increases by that amount).  You add a Small or Large Shield's armor bonus, and enhancement bonus if applicable, to your Reflex roll for purposes of this feat.  If you succeed, you deflect the weapon.  You must be aware of the attack and not flat-footed.  You may block an incoming missile attack with your shield only once per round. This feat also allows the character to block magical projectile attacks (e.g. Melf's acid arrow, fire arrow), but the shield will sustain any damage from the spell that exceeds its hardness. Against special attacks with splash damage (e.g. acid, alchemist's fire, etc.), if the Reflex saving throw is successful, the shield takes the primary damage and you take only the splash damage.</Benefit>
  <Special>You may take this feat multiple times.  Its effects do not stack.  Each time you take this feat, you may block an additional missile attack with your shield.  You may not block more attacks in a round than 1 + your Dexterity bonus.</Special>
  <Source ID="0"/>
</Feat>
<Feat ID="209" Author="" Copyright="COPYRIGHT 2000, System Reference Document" Reference="System Reference Document">
  <Name>Mobility</Name>
  <Types Types="">
  </Types>
  <Prerequisites>Dex 13+, Dodge.</Prerequisites>
  <Benefit>The character gets a +4 dodge bonus to Armor Class against attacks of opportunity caused when the character moves out of or within a threatened area. Note: A condition that makes the character lose the Dexterity bonus to Armor Class (if any) also makes the character lose dodge bonuses. Also, dodge bonuses stack with each other, unlike most types of bonuses.</Benefit>
  <Source ID="0"/>
</Feat>
<Feat ID="210" Author="" Copyright="COPYRIGHT 2001, Eric D. Harry" Reference="Net Book of Feats">
  <Name>Monk Weapon Mastery</Name>
  <Types Types="">
  </Types>
  <Prerequisites>Proficient with chosen weapon, Weapon Focus (chosen weapon), base attack bonus +6 or higher</Prerequisites>
  <Benefit>Choose any single weapon that meets the above requirements.  The monk can now use her more favorable unarmed attack bonus, including the improved number of attacks per round, when wielding that weapon and may incorporate use of that weapon with her flurry of blows ability.</Benefit>
  <Normal>At first level, every monk has this ability with the kama, nunchaku ; siangham.  I also recommend allowing a Monk to wield a quarterstaff is a similar manner.</Normal>
  <Source ID="0"/>
</Feat>
<Feat ID="211" Author="" Copyright="COPYRIGHT 2000, System Reference Document" Reference="System Reference Document">
  <Name>Mounted Archery</Name>
  <Types Types="">
  </Types>
  <Prerequisites>Ride skill, Mounted Combat.</Prerequisites>
  <Benefit>The penalty the character suffers when using a ranged weapon from horseback is halved: -2 instead of -4 if the character's mount is taking a double move, and -4 instead of -8 if the character's mount is running.</Benefit>
  <Source ID="0"/>
</Feat>
<Feat ID="212" Author="" Copyright="COPYRIGHT 2000, System Reference Document" Reference="System Reference Document">
  <Name>Mounted Combat</Name>
  <Types Types="">
  </Types>
  <Prerequisites>Ride skill.</Prerequisites>
  <Benefit>Once per round when the character's mount is hit in combat, the character may make a Ride check to negate the hit. The hit is negated if the character's Ride check is greater than the attack roll (essentially, the Ride check becomes the mount's Armor Class if it's higher than the mount's regular AC).</Benefit>
  <Source ID="0"/>
</Feat>
<Feat ID="213" Author="" Copyright="COPYRIGHT 2000, System Reference Document" Reference="System Reference Document">
  <Name>Multiattack</Name>
  <Types Types="">
  </Types>
  <Prerequisites>Three or more natural weapons.</Prerequisites>
  <Benefit>The creature's secondary attacks with natural weapons suffer only a -2 penalty.</Benefit>
  <Normal>Without this feat, the creature's secondary natural attacks suffer a -5 penalty.</Normal>
  <Source ID="0"/>
</Feat>
<Feat ID="214" Author="" Copyright="COPYRIGHT 2000, System Reference Document" Reference="System Reference Document">
  <Name>Multidexterity</Name>
  <Types Types="">
  </Types>
  <Prerequisites>Dex 15+, three or more arms.</Prerequisites>
  <Benefit>The creature ignores all penalties for using an off hand.</Benefit>
  <Normal>Without this feat, a creature who uses an off hand suffers a -4 penalty to attack rolls, ability checks, and skill checks. A creature has one primary hand, and all the others are off hands; for example, a four-armed creature has one primary hand and three off hands.</Normal>
  <Special>This feat replaces the Ambidexterity feat for creatures with more than two arms.</Special>
  <Source ID="0"/>
</Feat>
<Feat ID="215" Author="" Copyright="COPYRIGHT 2000, System Reference Document" Reference="System Reference Document">
  <Name>Multiweapon Fighting</Name>
  <Types Types="">
  </Types>
  <Prerequisites>Three or more hands.</Prerequisites>
  <Benefit>Penalties for fighting with multiple weapons are reduced by 2.</Benefit>
  <Normal>A creature without this feat suffers a -6 penalty to attacks made with its primary hand and a -10 penalty to attacks made with its off hands. (It has one primary hand, and all the others are off hands.) See Attacking with Two Weapons, page 124 in the Player's Handbook.</Normal>
  <Special>This feat replaces the Two-Weapon Fighting feat for creatures with more than two arms. The Multidexterity feat further reduces penalties for off-hand attacks.</Special>
  <Source ID="0"/>
</Feat>
<Feat ID="216" Author="" Copyright="COPYRIGHT 2000, Bradley H. Bemis Jr." Reference="Net Book of Feats">
  <Name>Natural Leader</Name>
  <Types Types="">
  </Types>
  <Benefit>When organizing a cooperative effort, each helper can add the leader's Charisma bonus to their individual check rolls.
Example: A group of 3 heroes is attempting to move a heavy boulder.  This requires a strength check against DC 10 for the two helpers.  If they make it, the leader gains a +2 circumstance bonus. The leader must then make his strength check.  Using this feat, the leader can generate a morale based check bonus for the helpers and add his charisma modifier to their check rolls.</Benefit>
  <Source ID="0"/>
</Feat>
<Feat ID="217" Author="" Copyright="COPYRIGHT 2001, Eric D. Harry" Reference="Net Book of Feats">
  <Name>Night Owl</Name>
  <Types Types="">
  </Types>
  <Benefit>You only need half the usual amount of sleep or trance (based on your race) to awaken fully refreshed and recovered from fatigue penalties.</Benefit>
  <Normal>Without this feat you require 8 hours of sleep (4 hours of trance if an elf) to awaken refreshed.</Normal>
  <Special>Like elven spellcasters, you still need 8 hours of restful calm in order to prepare spells even if you have a lesser sleep or trance requirement to stay refreshed.</Special>
  <Source ID="0"/>
</Feat>
<Feat ID="218" Author="" Copyright="COPYRIGHT 2001, Carl Cramér" Reference="Net Book of Feats">
  <Name>Opportunity Counterspell</Name>
  <Types Types="">
  </Types>
  <Prerequisites>Quicken Spell, Spellcraft skill</Prerequisites>
  <Benefit>You get one free ready action each round that you can only use for counterspelling. If you use this ready action, you do not get any attacks of opportunity for the round, but your initiative does not change as it does from a normal ready action.</Benefit>
  <Special>You cannot use this feat to cast extra spells for effect; it only allows counterspelling of an opponent's spells.</Special>
  <Notes>Your casting of the counterspell may trigger an opportunity attack in the normal fashion. You cannot use this feat to cast extra spells for effect; it only allows counterspelling of an opponent's spells.</Notes>
  <Source ID="0"/>
</Feat>
<Feat ID="219" Author="" Copyright="COPYRIGHT 2001, Carl Cramér" Reference="Net Book of Feats">
  <Name>Pack Attack</Name>
  <Types Types="">
  </Types>
  <Benefit>If an ally (with or without this feat) is flanking your opponent, you are considered to be flanking that opponent also, and get all the normal benefits of flanking.</Benefit>
  <Normal>You must be one of the attackers that cause the target to become flanked to receive a flanking bonus.</Normal>
  <Source ID="0"/>
</Feat>
<Feat ID="220" Author="" Copyright="COPYRIGHT 2001, Carl Cramér" Reference="Net Book of Feats">
  <Name>Pack Initiative</Name>
  <Types Types="">
  </Types>
  <Prerequisites>Pack Attack</Prerequisites>
  <Benefit>If you and an ally both have this feat, you may change your initiative order to act on the same initiative count as your ally.  This free action must be taken after initiative checks are rolled, but before regular rounds begin. It lasts for the entire combat, or until you ready or delay your action, just as if you had initially rolled this initiative roll.</Benefit>
  <Special>You still cannot act on an initiative count higher than your normal maximum initiative count (20 + initiative bonus).</Special>
  <Source ID="0"/>
</Feat>
<Feat ID="221" Author="" Copyright="COPYRIGHT 2000, Bradley H. Bemis Jr." Reference="Net Book of Feats">
  <Name>Pack Mule</Name>
  <Types Types="">
  </Types>
  <Benefit>You can carry weight (encumbrance) as if your Strength were two points higher.</Benefit>
  <Source ID="0"/>
</Feat>
<Feat ID="222" Author="" Copyright="COPYRIGHT 2001, Bradley H. Bemis Jr." Reference="Net Book of Feats">
  <Name>Pack Rat</Name>
  <Types Types="">
  </Types>
  <Benefit>There is a slim chance that you may have any small (2 lbs or less) non-magical, standard item on your person or in your pack.  The chance to find such an item is an intelligence check against a DC of 15 + the GP cost of the item (all items are considered to cost at least one GP for the purpose of this feat).  This feat can only be attempted once for any item sought until after you have returned to a town area for supplies.
Example: You have just located an ancient carving on a cave wall that yields secrets in a writing you do not understand.  Someone has the great idea to do a rubbing of the wall.  Bonzo the wizard pulls out a piece of parchment, but no one has anything to rub over it with.  You flip through the pockets of your cloak and find an old dried up husk of charcoal.</Benefit>
  <Notes>This feat cannot be used to find extra money, or saleable items.  You can only find one item of any item in this fashion (until you have a chance to restock in town).  It is simply your tendency to absent-mindedly stick small things here and there without paying attention.</Notes>
  <Source ID="0"/>
</Feat>
<Feat ID="223" Author="" Copyright="COPYRIGHT 2001, Sigfried Trent" Reference="Net Book of Feats">
  <Name>Pain Is My Friend</Name>
  <Types Types="">
  </Types>
  <Benefit>As a full round action you deal 4 points of damage to yourself, for a number of rounds equal to 3 plus your constitution modifier you gain a +2 rage bonus to strength and a +2 fear bonus to intimidation checks.</Benefit>
  <Notes>This is kind of barbarian rage, although it could represent an inner focus and determination as apposed to an uncontrolled frenzy, or even a sick dementia.</Notes>
  <Source ID="0"/>
</Feat>
<Feat ID="224" Author="" Copyright="COPYRIGHT 2001, Eric D. Harry" Reference="Net Book of Feats">
  <Name>Penetrating Ki Strike</Name>
  <Types Types="">
  </Types>
  <Prerequisites>Wis 13+, Improved Unarmed Strike, Stunning Attack class ability, Ki Strike class ability, base attack bonus +9 or higher.</Prerequisites>
  <Benefit>You can resolve your next unarmed melee attack as a touch attack, ignoring any benefit to your opponent's Armor Class provided by armor, shield or natural armor.  Each use of Penetrating Ki Strike counts as three of your stunning attacks per day and you must declare use of this feat prior to your attack roll.  A failed attack roll ruins your attempt and wastes three stunning attacks.  Penetrating Ki Strike is a supernatural ability.</Benefit>
  <Source ID="0"/>
</Feat>
<Feat ID="225" Author="" Copyright="COPYRIGHT 2001, Eric D. Harry" Reference="Net Book of Feats">
  <Name>Penetrating Psionic Fist</Name>
  <Types Types="">
  </Types>
  <Prerequisites>Str 13+, Psionic Fist, Unavoidable Strike, base attack bonus +6 or higher.</Prerequisites>
  <Benefit>Although you do not gain a bonus on attack or damage rolls with this feat, by spending 3 power points your unarmed strikes can ignore damage reduction as if your hands and feet had an enhancement bonus of +1.  You can increase the effective enhancement bonus of your unarmed strikes by paying 3 additional power points per +1 enhancement bonus, allowing you to penetrate even stronger damage reduction. You must decide whether or not to pay the cost for this feat prior to making your attack and the power points are lost if your attack misses.  Your hands and feet can remain "charged" for a number of rounds equal to your Strength modifier +1 or until your next unarmed attack, whichever occurs first.</Benefit>
  <Source ID="0"/>
</Feat>
<Feat ID="226" Author="" Copyright="COPYRIGHT 2001, Eric D. Harry" Reference="Net Book of Feats">
  <Name>Penetrating Psionic Shot</Name>
  <Types Types="">
  </Types>
  <Prerequisites>Dex 13+, Point Blank Shot, Psionic Shot, Fell Shot, base attack bonus +6 or higher.</Prerequisites>
  <Benefit>Although you do not gain a bonus on attack or damage rolls with this feat, by spending 3 power points your ranged attacks can ignore damage reduction as if they had an enhancement bonus of +1.  You can increase the effective enhancement bonus of your ranged shots by paying 3 additional power points per +1 enhancement bonus, allowing you to penetrate even stronger damage reduction. You must decide whether or not to pay the cost for this feat prior to making your attack and the power points are lost if your attack misses. Your arrow, bolt or bullet remains "charged" for a number of rounds equal to your Strength modifier +1 or until your next ranged attack, whichever occurs first.</Benefit>
  <Source ID="0"/>
</Feat>
<Feat ID="227" Author="" Copyright="COPYRIGHT 2001, Eric D. Harry" Reference="Net Book of Feats">
  <Name>Penetrating Psionic Weapon</Name>
  <Types Types="">
  </Types>
  <Prerequisites>Str 13+, Power Attack, Psionic Weapon, Deep Impact, base attack bonus +6 or higher.</Prerequisites>
  <Benefit>Although you do not gain a bonus on attack or damage rolls with this feat, by spending 3 power points your melee weapon can ignore damage reduction as if it had an enhancement bonus of +1.  You can increase the effective enhancement bonus of your melee weapon by paying 3 additional power points per +1 enhancement bonus, allowing you to penetrate even stronger damage reduction. You must decide whether or not to pay the cost for this feat prior to making your attack and the power points are lost if your attack misses.  Your melee weapon can remain "charged" for a number of rounds equal to your Strength modifier +1 or until your next melee attack, whichever occurs first.</Benefit>
  <Source ID="0"/>
</Feat>
<Feat ID="228" Author="" Copyright="COPYRIGHT 2000, Michael J. Kletch" Reference="Net Book of Feats">
  <Name>Penetrating Shot</Name>
  <Types Types="">
  </Types>
  <Prerequisites>Weapon Specialization with the weapon, Point Blank Shot, base attack bonus +8 or higher</Prerequisites>
  <Benefit>Any threat roll that also is a successful attack with the weapon always results in a Critical Hit.  This feat only applies to attacks with ranges up to 30 feet.</Benefit>
  <Special>You can take this feat multiple times.  Its effects do not stack.  Each time you take the feat, it applies to a new weapon.</Special>
  <Source ID="0"/>
</Feat>
<Feat ID="229" Author="" Copyright="COPYRIGHT 2001, Carl Cramér" Reference="Net Book of Feats">
  <Name>Pidgin</Name>
  <Types Types="">
  </Types>
  <Benefit>You can make yourself understood by almost anyone.  This lets you communicate basic things, like a need for supplies and to barter, even if you have no language in common with those you are speaking to.  You may use no more than two words in a sentence and two syllables in each word when roleplaying the speaking of pidgin.</Benefit>
  <Notes>You can only communicate with creatures who can speak some language.  A purely telepathic creature, or one communicating through scents but not words, is unintelligible to you.</Notes>
  <Source ID="0"/>
</Feat>
<Feat ID="230" Author="" Copyright="COPYRIGHT 2001, Carl Cramér" Reference="Net Book of Feats">
  <Name>Piercing Shot</Name>
  <Types Types="">
  </Types>
  <Prerequisites>Proficiency with any crossbow.</Prerequisites>
  <Benefit>When you shoot a crossbow or firearm, any threat roll that also is a successful attack with the weapon always results in a Critical Hit.  This feat only applies to attacks at a range of up to 30 feet.</Benefit>
  <Normal>See Critical Hits, page 123 in the 3rd Edition Player's Handbook.</Normal>
  <Notes>This could be a house rule rather than a feat.</Notes>
  <Source ID="0"/>
</Feat>
<Feat ID="231" Author="" Copyright="COPYRIGHT 2001, Carl Cramér" Reference="Net Book of Feats">
  <Name>Pin Weapon</Name>
  <Types Types="">
  </Types>
  <Prerequisites>Base attack bonus +3.</Prerequisites>
  <Benefit>As a full-round action, you can strike an opponent's weapon to pin it. This works like a disarm but does not trigger an attack of opportunity. A successful pin causes both of you to be flat-footed as long as it is maintained.</Benefit>
  <Special>You must remain within 5' of one another to maintain the pin. Either of you can end the pin on your turn by moving away, letting go of his weapon, or as a standard action.
Example: Friar Tuck is rescuing some children from a castle dungeon when a guard blocks the way. Tuck pins his weapon, shouting for the children to run past. The guard cannot make any attacks of opportunity, as he is flat-footed.</Special>
  <Notes>You can only use Pin Weapon unarmed if you have the Improved Unarmed Combat feat.</Notes>
  <Source ID="0"/>
</Feat>
<Feat ID="232" Author="" Copyright="COPYRIGHT 2000, System Reference Document" Reference="System Reference Document">
  <Name>Point Blank Shot</Name>
  <Types Types="">
  </Types>
  <Benefit>The character gets a +1 bonus to attack and damage rolls with ranged weapons at ranges of up to 30 feet.</Benefit>
  <Source ID="0"/>
</Feat>
<Feat ID="233" Author="" Copyright="COPYRIGHT 2001, Carl Cramér" Reference="Net Book of Feats">
  <Name>Poison Resistance</Name>
  <Types Types="">
  </Types>
  <Benefit>You receive a +4 bonus to all Fortitude saves against poison.</Benefit>
  <Source ID="0"/>
</Feat>
<Feat ID="234" Author="" Copyright="COPYRIGHT 2001, Carl Cramér" Reference="Net Book of Feats">
  <Name>Poison Tolerance</Name>
  <Types Types="">
  </Types>
  <Prerequisites>Poison Use, Con 13+</Prerequisites>
  <Benefit>You are able to train your body to ignore the effects of certain (specific) poisons. You must have access to the poison so you can gradually work up an immunity by subjecting yourself to increasingly larger doses. It takes at least a full dose of the poison and one month's time (during which you can still do other things) to work up the immunity.</Benefit>
  <Special>You can only maintain a number of immunities equal to your Constitution bonus at any one time. The immunity will fade in a month if you do not use another dose to keep it up.</Special>
  <Source ID="0"/>
</Feat>
<Feat ID="235" Author="" Copyright="COPYRIGHT 2001, Carl Cramér" Reference="Net Book of Feats">
  <Name>Poison Use</Name>
  <Types Types="">
  </Types>
  <Prerequisites>Alchemy</Prerequisites>
  <Benefit>You can use poisons with no danger to yourself.</Benefit>
  <Source ID="0"/>
</Feat>
<Feat ID="236" Author="" Copyright="COPYRIGHT 2001, Carl Cramér" Reference="Net Book of Feats">
  <Name>Pole Fighting</Name>
  <Types Types="">
  </Types>
  <Prerequisites>Strength 13+, weapon proficiency with a pole arm</Prerequisites>
  <Benefit>When using a pole arm in two hands, you can use the butt end to make an additional attack. The butt end counts as a normal club for most purposes, but it keeps the pole-weapon's original size. For pole-arms without reach, this allows you to use them as double weapons. That is, you can fight as if using two weapons, but if you do, you incur all the normal penalties associated with fighting with two weapons, as if you were using a one-handed weapon and a light weapon.  For pole arms with reach, it means you can use the butt, without reach, and thus strike adjacent opponents. You are effectively using your butt end in two hands and get the improved damage bonus from strength that this allows.</Benefit>
  <Special>Pole arms include the halfspear, shortspear, trident, glaive, guisarme, halberd, longspear, ranseur and quarterstaff. The merits of this feat are intrinsic to the quarterstaff.</Special>
  <Source ID="0"/>
</Feat>
<Feat ID="237" Author="" Copyright="COPYRIGHT 2000, System Reference Document" Reference="System Reference Document">
  <Name>Power Attack</Name>
  <Types Types="">
  </Types>
  <Prerequisites>Str 13+.</Prerequisites>
  <Benefit>On the character's action, before making attack rolls for a round, the character may choose to subtract a number from all melee attack rolls and add the same number to all melee damage rolls. This number may not exceed the character's base attack bonus. The penalty on attacks and bonus on damage applies until the character's next action.</Benefit>
  <Source ID="0"/>
</Feat>
<Feat ID="238" Author="" Copyright="COPYRIGHT 2001, Eric D. Harry" Reference="Net Book of Feats">
  <Name>Power Double Weapon</Name>
  <Types Types="">
  </Types>
  <Prerequisites>Double Weapon Fighting, Power Attack, base attack bonus +3 or higher.</Prerequisites>
  <Benefit>When wielding a double weapon, you add your full Strength bonus to damage rolls with all of your primary and secondary attacks.</Benefit>
  <Normal>Without this feat you add your full Strength bonus to damage rolls with your primary attack(s) and half your Strength bonus to damage rolls with your secondary attack(s).</Normal>
  <Source ID="0"/>
</Feat>
<Feat ID="239" Author="" Copyright="COPYRIGHT 2001, Carl Cramér" Reference="Net Book of Feats">
  <Name>Power Finesse</Name>
  <Types Types="">
  </Types>
  <Prerequisites>Proficient with weapon, base attack bonus +1 or higher.</Prerequisites>
  <Benefit>You can now learn the Weapon Finesse feat applied to any melee weapon, regardless of it's size. Power Finesse has no other effect in and of itself.</Benefit>
  <Notes>Even with this feat, the DM may not allow Weapon Finesse for certain clumsy weapons, such as the great club.</Notes>
  <Source ID="0"/>
</Feat>
<Feat ID="240" Author="" Copyright="COPYRIGHT 2001, Eric D. Harry" Reference="Net Book of Feats">
  <Name>Power Psicrystal</Name>
  <Types Types="">
  </Types>
  <Prerequisites>Psicrystal class ability, ability to manifest 3rd level psionic powers.</Prerequisites>
  <Benefit>You can store extra power points in your psicrystal.  In effect, the psicrystal gains the powers of a crystal capacitor capable of storing 5 power points.  The psicrystal retains all of its other powers and continues to advance in ability as normal.</Benefit>
  <Normal>Psicrystals cannot normally store power points.</Normal>
  <Special>This feat can be combined with Crystal Psiweapon.</Special>
  <Source ID="0"/>
</Feat>
<Feat ID="242" Author="" Copyright="COPYRIGHT 2001, Peter K. Campbell" Reference="Net Book of Feats">
  <Name>Power Resting</Name>
  <Types Types="">
  </Types>
  <Benefit>You require only 4 hours of rest prior to preparing to relearn arcane spells and/or regain power points.</Benefit>
  <Normal>You require 8 hours of rest prior to preparing to relearn arcane spells and/or regain power points.</Normal>
  <Special>This feat does not allow you to gain any more spells or power points per day than normal, nor does it reduce the resting time you require to avoid or recover from fatigue.  It does allow you to relearn arcane spells and/or regain power points even if you are fatigued.</Special>
  <Source ID="0"/>
</Feat>
<Feat ID="244" Author="" Copyright="COPYRIGHT 2001, Carl Cramér" Reference="Net Book of Feats">
  <Name>Powerless Spell</Name>
  <Types Types="">
  </Types>
  <Benefit>You can cast a spell in such a way that it has no effect beyond a simple light show, an obviously powerless version of the real thing with an instantaneous duration and no lasting effect. A Fireball would only be a billowing cloud of hot air, a lightning bolt would become an obviously powerless, but still impressive, display of static. This allows you to show people that you have a powerful spell without expending a high-level spell slot, but the main use is in counterspelling. As it is the spell itself and not the effect that causes counterspelling, such a spell would have very little effect on the real world, but could still be used to counterspell. By giving up the entire spell effect, you make the spell easier to prepare and cast, so that a spell takes up a spell slot two levels lower, but never lower than level zero.</Benefit>
  <Special>Spells whose effects are to negate or counterspell magic still lose their effect. So a powerless dispel magic can only be used to counterspell another dispel magic spell; it cannot be used as an attempt to counterspell any other spell (as that is the effect of a dispel magic spell, lost through the Powerless Spell feat). Nor can a powerless darkness spell be used to counter a light spell, for the same reason.</Special>
  <Source ID="0"/>
</Feat>
<Feat ID="245" Author="" Copyright="COPYRIGHT 2000, System Reference Document" Reference="System Reference Document">
  <Name>Precise Shot</Name>
  <Types Types="">
  </Types>
  <Prerequisites>Point Blank Shot.</Prerequisites>
  <Benefit>The character can shoot or throw ranged weapons at an opponent engaged in melee without suffering the standard -4 penalty.</Benefit>
  <Source ID="0"/>
</Feat>
<Feat ID="246" Author="" Copyright="COPYRIGHT 2001, Eric D. Harry" Reference="Net Book of Feats">
  <Name>Primeval Power</Name>
  <Types Types="">
  </Types>
  <Prerequisites>Innate supernatural or spell-like ability.</Prerequisites>
  <Benefit>Half of the damage inflicted by the creature's chosen supernatural or spell-like ability is derived from arcane, divine or profane power and is resistant to protection from elements and similar magic.  The other half of the damage is inflicted normally.  Celestial creatures infuse their chosen ability with divine power, fiendish creatures with profane power and other creatures with arcane power.</Benefit>
  <Notes>Beware, never underestimate the power of a Dragon!</Notes>
  <Source ID="0"/>
</Feat>
<Feat ID="247" Author="" Copyright="COPYRIGHT 2001, Eric D. Harry" Reference="Net Book of Feats">
  <Name>Profane Death Blow</Name>
  <Types Types="">
  </Types>
  <Prerequisites>Ability to rebuke undead, Sneak Attack.</Prerequisites>
  <Benefit>Spend one of your rebuke undead attempts to add your Charisma modifier as a profane bonus to the attack and damage roll of your next sneak attack.  After channeling the negative energy to power this feat, you must make this attack within a number of rounds equal to your Charisma bonus.</Benefit>
  <Special>If you have the Death Attack assassin class ability, you may similarly spend one of your rebuke undead attempts to add your Charisma modifier as a profane bonus to the DC of the Fortitude save made to resist your next Death Attack.</Special>
  <Source ID="0"/>
</Feat>
<Feat ID="248" Author="" Copyright="COPYRIGHT 2001, Eric D. Harry" Reference="Net Book of Feats">
  <Name>Profane Shadow Strike</Name>
  <Types Types="">
  </Types>
  <Prerequisites>Ability to rebuke undead, ability to cast Divine spells of 3rd level or higher, Extra Turning, Profane Ghoul Strike.</Prerequisites>
  <Benefit>By spending one of your rebuke undead attempts, you drain 1d4 points of temporary strength damage from all living opponents struck by you in melee combat until the end of your next action. Characters reduced to strength 0 by this feat are slain but do not normally rise again as shadows unless you have the Profane Shadowspawn feat.</Benefit>
  <Source ID="0"/>
</Feat>
<Feat ID="249" Author="" Copyright="COPYRIGHT 2001, Eric D. Harry" Reference="Net Book of Feats">
  <Name>Profane Shadowspawn</Name>
  <Types Types="">
  </Types>
  <Prerequisites>Ability to rebuke undead, ability to cast Divine spells of 4th level or higher, Extra Turning, Profane Ghoul Touch, Profane Shadow Strike.</Prerequisites>
  <Benefit>Any humanoid drained to strength 0 by use of your Profane Shadow Strike feat becomes a shadow under your control within 1d4 rounds.  Created shadows are automatically under your control but count against the maximum number of hit dice that you can normally command through use of your rebuke undead power (equal to 1 HD/rebuke level).  Shadows created in excess of this number are not in your control, are immune to further use of your rebuke undead ability and will immediately attack you.</Benefit>
  <Normal>Humanoids slain by Profane Shadow Strike do not rise again as shadows under your control.</Normal>
  <Special>Shadows created through this feat cannot spawn other shadows.</Special>
  <Source ID="0"/>
</Feat>
<Feat ID="250" Author="" Copyright="COPYRIGHT 2001, Eric D. Harry" Reference="Net Book of Feats">
  <Name>Profane Wightspawn</Name>
  <Types Types="">
  </Types>
  <Prerequisites>Ability to rebuke undead, ability to cast Divine spells of 5th level or higher, Extra Turning, Profane Ghoul Touch, Profane Wight Strike</Prerequisites>
  <Benefit>Any humanoid slain by use of your Profane Wight Strike feat becomes a wight under your control within 1d4 rounds.  Created wights are automatically under your control but count against the maximum number of hit dice that you can normally command through use of your rebuke undead power (equal to 1 HD/rebuke level).  Wights created in excess of this number are not in your control, are immune to further use of your rebuke undead ability and will immediately attack you.</Benefit>
  <Normal>Humanoids slain by Profane Wight Strike do not rise again as wights under your control.</Normal>
  <Special>Wights created through use of this feat are incapable of spawning other wights.</Special>
  <Source ID="0"/>
</Feat>
<Feat ID="251" Author="" Copyright="COPYRIGHT 2001, Eric D. Harry" Reference="Net Book of Feats">
  <Name>Profane Wraith Strike</Name>
  <Types Types="">
  </Types>
  <Prerequisites>Ability to rebuke undead, ability to cast Divine spells of 5th level or higher, Extra Turning, Profane Ghoul Touch, Profane Wight Strike.</Prerequisites>
  <Benefit>By spending one of your rebuke undead attempts, all living opponents struck by you in melee combat until the end of your next action suffer 1d4 points of temporary constitution drain. Characters reduced to constitution 0 by this feat are slain but do not normally rise again as wraiths unless you have the Profane Wraithspawn feat.</Benefit>
  <Special>Though a Wraith is normally an incorporeal opponent, your attacks are still bound by the corporeal world.</Special>
  <Source ID="0"/>
</Feat>
<Feat ID="252" Author="" Copyright="COPYRIGHT 2001, Eric D. Harry" Reference="Net Book of Feats">
  <Name>Profane Wraithspawn</Name>
  <Types Types="">
  </Types>
  <Prerequisites>Ability to rebuke undead, ability to cast Divine spells of 6th level or higher, Extra Turning, Profane Ghoul Strike, Profane Wight Strike, Profane Wraith Strike.</Prerequisites>
  <Benefit>Any humanoid slain by use of your Profane Wraith Strike feat becomes a wraith under your control within 1d4 rounds.  Created wraiths are automatically under your control but count against the maximum number of hit dice that you can normally command through use of your rebuke undead power (equal to 1 HD/rebuke level).  Wraiths created in excess of this number are not in your control, are immune to further use of your rebuke undead ability and will immediately attack you.</Benefit>
  <Normal>Humanoids slain by Profane Wraith Strike do not rise again as wights under your control.</Normal>
  <Special>Wraiths created through use of this feat cannot spawn other wraiths.</Special>
  <Source ID="0"/>
</Feat>
<Feat ID="253" Author="" Copyright="COPYRIGHT 2001, Sigfried Trent" Reference="Net Book of Feats">
  <Name>Prophetic Dreamer</Name>
  <Types Types="">
  </Types>
  <Prerequisites>DM's permission</Prerequisites>
  <Benefit>Once per session, your GM should inform you of a dream you have had that portents an event that may be in your future.  Ideally this dream could warn you of a possible danger, or guide you to a good decision.  The dream need not come true, but should be a possible or likely scenario in the characters future.  Sometimes the dreams are literal and sometimes symbolic, (at the DM's discretion).</Benefit>
  <Notes>This feat isn't for everyone.  It should benefit the character but only as much as the DM wants it to.  This could be a trait or the GM could decide some mystical event allows the character to start having these dreams.</Notes>
  <Source ID="0"/>
</Feat>
<Feat ID="254" Author="" Copyright="COPYRIGHT 2001, Eric D. Harry" Reference="Net Book of Feats">
  <Name>Psionic Attack Focus</Name>
  <Types Types="">
  </Types>
  <Prerequisites>Cha 13+, Mental Adversary</Prerequisites>
  <Benefit>This feat mimics the Psionic Focus feat, except that it applies to one known psionic attack mode of your choice.  Add +2 to the DC for all Will saves in psionic combat from this psionic attack mode.</Benefit>
  <Special>You can choose this feat up to five times, each time applying the bonus to a different known psionic attack mode of your choice.  This feat does not allow you to discover additional psionic attack modes and can only be applied to a psionic attack mode previously discovered.  This feat does not stack with the Greater Psionic Attack Focus feat.  A Mind Flayer can choose Psionic Attack Focus with its mind blast special ability.</Special>
  <Source ID="0"/>
</Feat>
<Feat ID="255" Author="" Copyright="COPYRIGHT 2001, Eric D. Harry" Reference="Net Book of Feats">
  <Name>Psionic Ghost Fist</Name>
  <Types Types="">
  </Types>
  <Prerequisites>Str 13+, Psionic Fist.</Prerequisites>
  <Benefit>By spending 1 power point your unarmed strikes can attack incorporeal opponents as if you had the ghost touch power, negating an incorporeal creature's ability to ignore 50% of successful attacks from a corporeal source. Although your unarmed strikes do not gain a bonus on attack or damage rolls with this feat, they do gain the ability to negate the damage reduction of incorporeal creatures as if your hands and feet were +1 magic weapons.  You must decide whether or not to pay the cost for this feat prior to making your attack and the power point is lost if your attack misses.  Your hands and feet can remain "charged" for a number of rounds equal to your Strength modifier +1 or until your next unarmed attack, whichever occurs first.</Benefit>
  <Source ID="0"/>
</Feat>
<Feat ID="256" Author="" Copyright="COPYRIGHT 2001, Eric D. Harry" Reference="Net Book of Feats">
  <Name>Psionic Ghost Shot</Name>
  <Types Types="">
  </Types>
  <Prerequisites>Dex 13+, Point Blank Shot, Psionic Shot.</Prerequisites>
  <Benefit>By spending 1 power point your ranged shots can attack incorporeal opponents as if they had the ghost touch power, negating an incorporeal creature's ability to ignore 50% of successful attacks from a corporeal source. Although your ranged shots do not gain a bonus on attack or damage rolls with this feat, they do gain the ability to negate the damage reduction of incorporeal creatures as if they were +1 magic weapons.  You must decide whether or not to pay the cost for this feat prior to making your attack and the power point is lost if your attack misses.  Your arrow, bolt or bullet remains "charged" for a number of rounds equal to your Strength modifier +1 or until your next ranged attack, whichever occurs first.</Benefit>
  <Source ID="0"/>
</Feat>
<Feat ID="257" Author="" Copyright="COPYRIGHT 2001, Eric D. Harry" Reference="Net Book of Feats">
  <Name>Psionic Ghost Weapon</Name>
  <Types Types="">
  </Types>
  <Prerequisites>Str 13+, Power Attack, and Psionic Weapon.</Prerequisites>
  <Benefit>By spending 1 power point your melee weapon can attack incorporeal opponents as if it had the ghost touch power, negating an incorporeal creature's ability to ignore 50% of successful attacks from a corporeal source. Although your weapon does not gain a bonus on attack or damage rolls with this feat, it does gain the ability to negate the damage reduction of incorporeal creatures as if it were a +1 magic weapon.  You must decide whether or not to pay the cost for this feat prior to making your attack and the power point is lost if your attack misses.  Your weapon can remain "charged" for a number of rounds equal to your Strength modifier +1 or until your next melee attack, whichever occurs first.</Benefit>
  <Source ID="0"/>
</Feat>
<Feat ID="258" Author="" Copyright="COPYRIGHT 2001, Eric D. Harry" Reference="Net Book of Feats">
  <Name>Psionic Initiative</Name>
  <Types Types="">
  </Types>
  <Prerequisites>Improved Initiative, reserve power points 5+.</Prerequisites>
  <Benefit>You gain an additional +2 bonus to initiative checks.</Benefit>
  <Special>This feat stacks with the Improved Initiative feat or any other skill, feat or ability that provides a bonus on Initiative checks unless otherwise specified.</Special>
  <Source ID="0"/>
</Feat>
<Feat ID="259" Author="" Copyright="COPYRIGHT 2001, Eric D. Harry" Reference="Net Book of Feats">
  <Name>Psionic Multifist</Name>
  <Types Types="">
  </Types>
  <Prerequisites>Str 13+, Psionic Fist, base attack bonus 3+</Prerequisites>
  <Benefit>At the cost of 2 power points, your hands and feet can be charged as a free action to inflict +1 point of damage for a number of rounds equal to your Strength modifier +1.  While your unarmed strikes are charged with psionic power you are considered armed and do not provoke attacks of opportunity.</Benefit>
  <Special>This feat does not stack with Psionic Fist or Improved Psionic Fist; only one of the feats can be used at any one time.</Special>
  <Source ID="0"/>
</Feat>
<Feat ID="260" Author="" Copyright="COPYRIGHT 2001, Eric D. Harry" Reference="Net Book of Feats">
  <Name>Psionic Multishot</Name>
  <Types Types="">
  </Types>
  <Prerequisites>Str 13+, Point Blank Shot, Psionic Shot, base attack bonus 3+</Prerequisites>
  <Benefit>At the cost of 2 power points, all of your ranged attacks can be charged as a free action to inflict +1 point of piercing damage for a number of rounds equal to your Str modifier +1.</Benefit>
  <Special>This feat does not stack with Psionic Shot or Improved Psionic Shot; only one of the feats can be used at any one time.</Special>
  <Source ID="0"/>
</Feat>
<Feat ID="261" Author="" Copyright="COPYRIGHT 2001, Eric D. Harry" Reference="Net Book of Feats">
  <Name>Psionic Multiweapon</Name>
  <Types Types="">
  </Types>
  <Prerequisites>Str 13+, Power Attack, Psionic Weapon, base attack bonus 3+</Prerequisites>
  <Benefit>At the cost of 2 power points, your melee weapon can be charged as a free action to inflict +1 point of damage for a number of rounds equal to your Strength modifier +1.</Benefit>
  <Special>This feat does not stack with Psionic Weapon or Improved Psionic Weapon; only one of the feats can be used at any one time.</Special>
  <Source ID="0"/>
</Feat>
<Feat ID="262" Author="" Copyright="COPYRIGHT 2001, Eric D. Harry" Reference="Net Book of Feats">
  <Name>Psionic Strike</Name>
  <Types Types="">
  </Types>
  <Prerequisites>Str 13+, Psionic Fist, reserve power points 1+.</Prerequisites>
  <Benefit>As long as you have 1 or more power points, your unarmed strikes are charged with psionic power.  Your unarmed strikes do not provoke attacks of opportunity from armed opponents and inflict 1d6 points of lethal damage in unarmed combat if Medium-sized and 1d4 points of real damage if Small-sized.</Benefit>
  <Normal>Unarmed attacks normally provoke attacks of opportunity against armed attackers and inflict 1d4 points of subdual damage in Medium-sized and 1d3 points of subdual damage if small sized.</Normal>
  <Special>This feat can be combined with the Psionic Fist feat, allowing you to inflict 1d10 points of damage if Medium-sized at the cost of 1 power point per strike (1d6 points if Small-sized).</Special>
  <Source ID="0"/>
</Feat>
<Feat ID="263" Author="" Copyright="COPYRIGHT 2001, Sigfried Trent" Reference="Net Book of Feats">
  <Name>Pull Blow</Name>
  <Types Types="">
  </Types>
  <Prerequisites>Expertise, Weapon Focus, Int 13+, Attack Bonus 3+, Heal</Prerequisites>
  <Benefit>To use this feat you must be wielding a weapon for which you have weapon focus.  When you damage an opponent and the damage dealt would take them below zero hit points you may pull your blow and deal exactly enough damage to take them to -1, where they will be unconscious but stable (not taking bleeding damage).  You cannot use this feat on a critical strike.</Benefit>
  <Notes>Imagine a master swordsman that cuts with such precision that he wound exactly the amount they wish by cutting "just so".  I'm not sure that this is better than subdual damage except that you make your decision after the fact and creatures immune to subdual damage can effectively be subdued.</Notes>
  <Source ID="0"/>
</Feat>
<Feat ID="264" Author="" Copyright="COPYRIGHT 2000, Bradley H. Bemis Jr." Reference="Net Book of Feats">
  <Name>Quick Defense</Name>
  <Types Types="">
  </Types>
  <Prerequisites>Alertness, Uncanny Dodge</Prerequisites>
  <Benefit>If threatened or surprised, you may take up the total defense position immediately.  This action takes place before any attacks are made.  This feat can only be used at the beginning of an encounter.</Benefit>
  <Special>If you choose to take the Quick Defense action, you may not act again within that round.</Special>
  <Source ID="0"/>
</Feat>
<Feat ID="265" Author="" Copyright="COPYRIGHT 2000, System Reference Document" Reference="System Reference Document">
  <Name>Quick Draw</Name>
  <Types Types="">
  </Types>
  <Prerequisites>Base attack bonus +1 or higher.</Prerequisites>
  <Benefit>The character can draw a weapon as a free action instead of as a move-equivalent action.</Benefit>
  <Source ID="0"/>
</Feat>
<Feat ID="266" Author="" Copyright="COPYRIGHT 2001, Eric D. Harry" Reference="Net Book of Feats">
  <Name>Quicken Divine Channeling</Name>
  <Types Types="">
  </Types>
  <Prerequisites>Ability to turn or rebuke undead, Charisma 13+, Extra Turning, Quicken Turning.</Prerequisites>
  <Benefit>You can channel energy to activate another divine feat as a free action a number of times per day equal to your charisma bonus.  This counts against your ability to use one quickened ability per round.  You can still only channel energy to power one divine feat or turning attempt per round.</Benefit>
  <Normal>Divine feats normal require a standard action to channel the requisite energy to power the feat.</Normal>
  <Special>You can take this feat more than once, each time gaining the ability to use quicken a divine feat one more time per day.</Special>
  <Source ID="0"/>
</Feat>
<Feat ID="267" Author="" Copyright="COPYRIGHT 2000, System Reference Document" Reference="System Reference Document">
  <Name>Quicken Spell</Name>
  <Types Types="">
  </Types>
  <Benefit>Casting a quickened spell is a free action. The character can perform another action, even casting another spell, in the same round as the character casts a quickened spell. The character may only cast one quickened spell per round. A spell whose casting time is more than 1 full round cannot be quickened. A quickened spell uses up a spell slot four levels higher than the spell's actual level.</Benefit>
  <Source ID="0"/>
</Feat>
<Feat ID="268" Author="" Copyright="COPYRIGHT 2001, Eric D. Harry" Reference="Net Book of Feats">
  <Name>Quicksilver</Name>
  <Types Types="">
  </Types>
  <Prerequisites>Dex 13+, Dodge, base attack bonus +3 or higher.</Prerequisites>
  <Benefit>Increase the dodge bonus provided to your Armor Class by your Dodge feat to +2.  This supercedes (does not stack with) the Dodge feat. You can also apply this +2 bonus as a dodge bonus to Reflex saves against your chosen opponent.  Any condition that makes you loose your dexterity bonus to Armor Class also makes you loose any dodge bonuses to your Armor Class or Reflex saves.</Benefit>
  <Special>This feat stacks with the Improved Dodge feat (also in this netbook), allowing you to apply the +2 dodge bonus to AC and Reflex saves granted by the Quicksilver feat against all opponents.</Special>
  <Source ID="0"/>
</Feat>
<Feat ID="269" Author="" Copyright="COPYRIGHT 2001, Carl Cramér" Reference="Net Book of Feats">
  <Name>Rank Fighting</Name>
  <Types Types="">
  </Types>
  <Prerequisites>Weapon proficiency with a reach weapon.</Prerequisites>
  <Benefit>You can ignore the normal 50% cover provided by a friend in between you and your opponent when striking with a reach weapon. You make such attacks with no penalty.</Benefit>
  <Normal>A friend in the way of a reach weapon attack provides 50% cover, and thus gives a +4 bonus to the target's AC. The intervening creature takes no damage if struck instead. See 'Cover and Reach Weapons' in the Player's Handbook, page 132.</Normal>
  <Source ID="0"/>
</Feat>
<Feat ID="270" Author="" Copyright="COPYRIGHT 2000, System Reference Document" Reference="System Reference Document">
  <Name>Rapid Shot</Name>
  <Types Types="">
  </Types>
  <Prerequisites>Point Blank Shot, Dex 13+.</Prerequisites>
  <Benefit>The character can get one extra attack per round with a ranged weapon. The attack is at the character's highest base attack bonus, but each attack (the extra one and the normal ones) suffers a -2 penalty. The character must use the full attack action to use this feat.</Benefit>
  <Source ID="0"/>
</Feat>
<Feat ID="96" Author="" Copyright="COPYRIGHT 2001, Michael J. Kletch" Reference="Net Book of Feats">
  <Name>Ready Shield</Name>
  <Types Types="">
  </Types>
  <Prerequisites>Extend Power, Persistent Power</Prerequisites>
  <Benefit>You may prepare a Psionic Defense Mode that you know, and that defense will remain active until you are attacked by a Psionic Attack Mode or until one day passes.  To manifest a Defense Mode in this fashion costs the normal number of power points for that defense + 3.  If you are caught flat-footed, stunned or otherwise unable to raise a defense (the primary reason for this feat), the defense mode prepared with Ever-Ready Shield will be used against that attack.  If you are able to act, you may raise any defense normally without losing the Ever-Ready Shield.
Like any psionic defense mode, it is applicable only to one attack by one opponent.  If you are assaulted by multiple adversaries before you are able to act, you may maintain this same Defense Mode against each successive attacker by paying the normal power point cost for the Defense Mode + 3.  If you choose not to maintain the defense against a particular attacker, the ability to mount a defense is gone until you lose your flat-footed status or other condition (i.e. you must withstand further attacks bare-brained).</Benefit>
  <Normal>If a psionic attacker catches you flat-footed and uses a Psionic Attack Mode, you are unable to raise a defense and must withstand the attack 'bare-brained' as described on pages 41-42 of the Psionics Handbook.</Normal>
  <Source ID="0"/>
</Feat>
<Feat ID="347" Author="" Copyright="COPYRIGHT 2001, Eric D. Harry" Reference="Net Book of Feats">
  <Name>Rebuke Resistance</Name>
  <Types Types="">
  </Types>
  <Benefit>The creature adds +2 to its Hit Dice total when resisting turn or rebuke attempts.</Benefit>
  <Special>This feat can be taken more than once and its benefits stack with itself.  Each time it is taken, add +2 to the creature's Hit Dice when resisting turn or rebuke attempts.</Special>
  <Source ID="0"/>
</Feat>
<Feat ID="271" Author="" Copyright="COPYRIGHT 2000, Bradley H. Bemis Jr." Reference="Net Book of Feats">
  <Name>Recharge</Name>
  <Types Types="">
  </Types>
  <Prerequisites>Item creation feat for the item in question</Prerequisites>
  <Benefit>You may spend 3/4 of the required time, experience, and money recharging an item.  You may fully recharge the item or you may recharge the item on a charge-by-charge basis.  To recharge a magical device, your recharging cost is 75% of the original item (for each element of creation).  To determine the cost for a specific number of charges (if you don't want to fully recharge a device for whatever reason), take the recharging costs and divide them by the maximum number of charges the device can carry.  This is your recharge cost per charge.</Benefit>
  <Special>This feat can only be used with items that have charges.  They can only be recharged to the maximum number of charges allowed at the time it was originally created.  This uses the optional rule that charged items can be recharged.
Example: Nimrod, the creator, designs a new wand that can make cheese.  This wand uses a number of charges based on the kind of cheese made.  Nimrod is a 9th level wizard with a 17 Intelligence (I use the alternate charges rule presented under Item Creation).  His new wand is created with the ability to hold a maximum of 36 charges (level 9 x Intelligence bonus of +3) for a total of 9 x 4.  Nimrod has been using his wand of cheese quite frequently (he's a were-mouse) and only has 6 charges left.  Since creating his wand, he is now 10th level and also received a boost to his intelligence (now 18).... these have no impact on the wand, because it was created to hold 36 charges... that's all it will ever hold unless Nimrod goes through the initial creation process again (which I might discount slightly).  Lets say this wand cost him 5,000gp and 800xp.  The recharge cost for this wand is 3,750gp and 600xp.  Now lets say that Nimrod doesn't have the XP to spend, but really wants to recharge the wand.  He is willing to settle for a smaller recharge, but can only spare 100xps.  Now we need to determine the cost per charge.  Our recharge cost is 3,750gp and 600xp, so we need to divide those by 36 (the maximum number of charges).  The result is 104gp and 17xp for each charge.  We said Nimrod had 100xp to spare, so he could add 5 charges (now he has 11 available).  The cost of these 5 charges is 520gp and 85xp.  Last I heard, Nimrod was working on a wand of wine to go with his cheese.</Special>
  <Source ID="0"/>
</Feat>
<Feat ID="272" Author="" Copyright="COPYRIGHT 2001, Carl Cramér" Reference="Net Book of Feats">
  <Name>Reflex Set</Name>
  <Types Types="">
  </Types>
  <Prerequisites>Hold the Line, Combat Reflexes</Prerequisites>
  <Benefit>When you are charged while holding a weapon that can be set against a charge, you get to make an attack of opportunity before the charge attack is made, and you get the double damage usually associated with setting such a weapon against a charge on this attack of opportunity. This is not cumulative with the normal ready action used to set a weapon against a charge.</Benefit>
  <Special>Weapons capable of being set against a charge are noted 'a' on the weapons table, SRD. This feat supercedes Hold the Line (meaning you don't get two opportunity attacks).</Special>
  <Source ID="0"/>
</Feat>
<Feat ID="273" Author="" Copyright="COPYRIGHT 2000, Bradley H. Bemis Jr." Reference="Net Book of Feats">
  <Name>Research Genius</Name>
  <Types Types="">
  </Types>
  <Prerequisites>Intel 12+, Spellcaster level 5+</Prerequisites>
  <Benefit>You may reduce the time required for spell research by 25%.</Benefit>
  <Notes>This is based on the variant spell research rules presented in the DMG.</Notes>
  <Source ID="0"/>
</Feat>
<Feat ID="274" Author="" Copyright="COPYRIGHT 2001, Bradley H. Bemis Jr." Reference="Net Book of Feats">
  <Name>Research Trinity</Name>
  <Types Types="">
  </Types>
  <Benefit>When creating a new spell you may greatly reduce one of the requirements (Time, Cost, or Resources), but must double the other two.  Time can be reduced to one day/spell level by doubling the cost of the research (2,000gp/spell level) and the size of the library needed (resources); or, you could reduce the cost to 100gp/level of the spell by doubling the time required (2 weeks/spell level) and the size of the library needed (resources); or, you could decrease the resources required (to just your brains and your spellbooks) by doubling both the time (2 weeks/level of the spell) and the cost (2,000gp/level of the spell). When using this feat for research, the DC for determining success (a Spellcraft check) increases to 15 + the spells level.</Benefit>
  <Normal>There are three primary elements required for the successful creation of a new spell:  Time (one week for each level of the spell), Cost (1,000gp for each level of the spell), and Resources (a well stocked library and a place to test ideas).  At the end of the research period, a Spellcraft check against DC 10 + the new spell's level is required to determine success.</Normal>
  <Source ID="0"/>
</Feat>
<Feat ID="275" Author="" Copyright="COPYRIGHT 2000, Bradley H. Bemis Jr." Reference="Net Book of Feats">
  <Name>Restore Effort</Name>
  <Types Types="">
  </Types>
  <Prerequisites>Mindless Effort</Prerequisites>
  <Benefit>You may resume concentration of a spell that was cast using the Mindless Effort metamagic feat.  You must resume the spell before it expires or the duration ends.</Benefit>
  <Special>Spells cast using this feat are still limited by the normal duration of the spell cast.</Special>
  <Source ID="0"/>
</Feat>
<Feat ID="277" Author="" Copyright="COPYRIGHT 2001, Carl Cramér" Reference="Net Book of Feats">
  <Name>Riposte</Name>
  <Types Types="">
  </Types>
  <Prerequisites>Weapon Finesse, Expertise, base attack bonus +6 or more</Prerequisites>
  <Benefit>When unencumbered, in light armor or less, and wielding a weapon that you have Finesse for, you may make an attack of opportunity against an opponent who tries to attack you in melee and misses.</Benefit>
  <Special>This does not work if you are denied your dexterity bonus to AC. You cannot use other feats that allow extra attacks (such as cleave) with a riposte.</Special>
  <Notes>This is a fencing technique, and fits well in a renaissance-style game.</Notes>
  <Source ID="0"/>
</Feat>
<Feat ID="278" Author="" Copyright="COPYRIGHT 2001, Carl Cramér" Reference="Net Book of Feats">
  <Name>Ritual Spell</Name>
  <Types Types="">
  </Types>
  <Benefit>A spell with a normal casting time of ten minutes or less can be cast as a ritual with a casting time of six hours. The ritual also requires a number of (unskilled) helpers equal to the spell level and must be conducted in a suitable place appropriate to the spell, such as a temple or wizard's sanctum. The benefit is that the spell takes up a spell slot one level lower than normal.</Benefit>
  <Special>If you have an appropriate sacrifice, perform the ritual at the right time in the right place, have an artifact or item of power or the ritual fits in the story, the DM may reduce the required spell slot even further. Recommended for evil NPCs, whose terrible rituals the PCs must stop.</Special>
  <Notes>This is particularly useful to divine spellcasters, who know high-level spells but normally just can't cast them. Many cleric spells do very well as rituals. Wizards can learn spells of a level they cannot normally cast, but must scribe it using the standard rules, not take it for free when they go up in level. Sorcerers and bards can never learn spells that they cannot normally cast, and thus find this feat almost useless.</Notes>
  <Source ID="0"/>
</Feat>
<Feat ID="279" Author="" Copyright="COPYRIGHT 2000, System Reference Document" Reference="System Reference Document">
  <Name>Run</Name>
  <Types Types="G">
    <Type Name="General">G</Type>
  </Types>
  <Benefit>When running, the character moves five times normal speed instead of four times normal speed. If the character makes a running jump, increase the distance or height cleared by one-fourth, but not past the maximum.</Benefit>
  <Normal>You move four times your speed while running (if wearing medium, light, or no armor and carrying no more than a medium load) or three times your speed (if wearing heavy armor or carrying a heavy load), and you lose your Dexterity bonus to AC. </Normal>
  <Source ID="0"/>
</Feat>
<Feat ID="205" Author="" Copyright="COPYRIGHT 2001, Bradley H. Bemis Jr." Reference="Net Book of Feats">
  <Name>S Eye</Name>
  <Types Types="">
  </Types>
  <Prerequisites>Iron Will</Prerequisites>
  <Benefit>Gain an additional  +2 to will saves against the effects of illusions and enchantments.</Benefit>
  <Special>This additional modifier stacks with Iron Will.</Special>
  <Source ID="0"/>
</Feat>
<Feat ID="280" Author="" Copyright="COPYRIGHT 2000, System Reference Document" Reference="System Reference Document">
  <Name>Scribe Scroll</Name>
  <Types Types="">
  </Types>
  <Prerequisites>Spellcaster level 1st+.</Prerequisites>
  <Benefit>The character can create a scroll of any spell that the character knows. Scribing a scroll takes 1 day for each 1,000 gp in its base price. The base price of a scroll is its spell level multiplied by its caster level multiplied by 25 gp. To scribe a scroll, the character must spend 1/25 of this base price in XP and use up raw materials costing half of this base price.
Any scroll that stores a spell with a costly material component or an XP cost also carries a commensurate cost. In addition to the costs derived from the base price, the character must expend the material component or pay the XP when scribing the scroll.</Benefit>
  <Source ID="0"/>
</Feat>
<Feat ID="281" Author="" Copyright="COPYRIGHT 2001, Carl Cramér" Reference="Net Book of Feats">
  <Name>Seduction</Name>
  <Types Types="">
  </Types>
  <Benefit>Sex sells, and friends can be won by seduction.  You get a +4 bonus to Bluff and Diplomacy attempts against people who find your race and gender sexually attractive.  After you use this feat, some people might seek to be intimate with you.  They will resent a blunt rejection, worsening their attitude one step.</Benefit>
  <Notes>Using this feat a lot might give you some notoriety.</Notes>
  <Source ID="0"/>
</Feat>
<Feat ID="282" Author="" Copyright="COPYRIGHT 2000, Michael J. Kletch" Reference="Net Book of Feats">
  <Name>Self Item</Name>
  <Types Types="">
  </Types>
  <Prerequisites>One or more of the following: Craft Magic Arms and Armor, Craft Rod, Craft Wondrous Item, Forge Ring.</Prerequisites>
  <Benefit>A magic item created with one of the prerequisite feats can be made as a Self Item.  In this case, the XP cost for the item is reduced by 25% (round down), but the item will work only for its creator.  If somebody other than the item's creator attempts use it, the item is completely inert.  If the item is ever destroyed, the creator will lose XP equal to full, normal XP cost to make the item; this can cause the creator to lose a level of experience.  Charged items cannot be made using this feat.</Benefit>
  <Source ID="0"/>
</Feat>
<Feat ID="283" Author="" Copyright="COPYRIGHT 2001, Carl Cramér" Reference="Net Book of Feats">
  <Name>Sense Magic</Name>
  <Types Types="">
  </Types>
  <Prerequisites>Spellcraft</Prerequisites>
  <Benefit>You can sense whether an object you are handling or a creature you are touching is magical or under the effects of a spell. the very air might be magical in some places. As a full-round action, you can tell whether if an item is magical with a Spellcraft check (DC 20). A success informs you if there is magic present; a failure indicates that it is not.</Benefit>
  <Special>You cannot retry, take 10, or take 20 when using this feat.</Special>
  <Source ID="0"/>
</Feat>
<Feat ID="284" Author="" Copyright="COPYRIGHT 2001, Eric D. Harry" Reference="Net Book of Feats">
  <Name>Shadowleap</Name>
  <Types Types="">
  </Types>
  <Prerequisites>Shadow jump class ability.</Prerequisites>
  <Benefit>Add an extra 20 feet to the distance that you can shadow jump per day.</Benefit>
  <Normal>Shadow jump is a class ability of the Shadowdancer prestige class, first gained at 4th level.</Normal>
  <Special>This feat may be taken multiple times.  Each additional Shadowleap feat adds an extra 20 feet to the distance that you can shadow jump per day.</Special>
  <Source ID="0"/>
</Feat>
<Feat ID="285" Author="" Copyright="COPYRIGHT 2001, Scott Metzger" Reference="Net Book of Feats">
  <Name>Shield Expertise</Name>
  <Types Types="">
  </Types>
  <Prerequisites>Shield Focus</Prerequisites>
  <Benefit>Your shield's armor bonus is increased by 1 when you wield it.</Benefit>
  <Source ID="0"/>
</Feat>
<Feat ID="286" Author="" Copyright="COPYRIGHT 2001, B. Marcus Lindberg, Scott Metzger" Reference="Net Book of Feats">
  <Name>Shield Focus</Name>
  <Types Types="">
  </Types>
  <Prerequisites>Proficient with shield, base attack bonus +1 or higher</Prerequisites>
  <Benefit>When wielding a specified type of shield it inflicts 1 less skill penalty and 5% less Arcane Spell Failure. This cannot reduce the penalties to sub zero levels.</Benefit>
  <Special>You can gain this feat multiple times. The effect does not stack. Each time you take the feat, it applies to a new type of shield.</Special>
  <Source ID="0"/>
</Feat>
<Feat ID="287" Author="" Copyright="COPYRIGHT 2000, Michael J. Kletch" Reference="Net Book of Feats">
  <Name>Shield Mastery</Name>
  <Types Types="">
  </Types>
  <Prerequisites>Shield Proficiency, base attack bonus of +1 or higher.</Prerequisites>
  <Benefit>When using a buckler, small shield or large shield, you may choose one opponent.  Against this opponent, you gain a +2 dodge bonus to AC.  If you are using a tower shield, your degree of cover is instead increased by one place. You may select a new opponent each round.  You may not use this feat if you are flanked.</Benefit>
  <Source ID="0"/>
</Feat>
<Feat ID="288" Author="" Copyright="COPYRIGHT 2000, System Reference Document" Reference="System Reference Document">
  <Name>Shield Proficiency</Name>
  <Types Types="">
  </Types>
  <Benefit>The character can use a shield and suffer only the standard penalties.</Benefit>
  <Normal>A character who is using a shield with which he or she is not proficient suffers the shield's armor check penalty on attack rolls and on all skill rolls that involve moving, including Ride.</Normal>
  <Source ID="0"/>
</Feat>
<Feat ID="289" Author="" Copyright="COPYRIGHT 2001, B. Marcus Lindberg" Reference="Net Book of Feats">
  <Name>Shield Specialization</Name>
  <Types Types="">
  </Types>
  <Prerequisites>4 fighter levels. Shield Focus in the type of shield.</Prerequisites>
  <Benefit>When you are wearing the specified type of shield you get a +2 dodge bonus to your Armor Class.</Benefit>
  <Special>You can gain this feat multiple times. The effects does not stack. Each time you take the feat, it applies to a new type of shield.</Special>
  <Source ID="0"/>
</Feat>
<Feat ID="290" Author="" Copyright="COPYRIGHT 2000, System Reference Document" Reference="System Reference Document">
  <Name>Shot On The Run</Name>
  <Types Types="">
  </Types>
  <Prerequisites>Point Blank Shot, Dex 13+, Dodge, Mobility.</Prerequisites>
  <Benefit>When using the attack action with a ranged weapon, the character can move both before and after the attack, provided that the character's total distance moved is not greater than the character's speed.</Benefit>
  <Source ID="0"/>
</Feat>
<Feat ID="291" Author="" Copyright="COPYRIGHT 2000, System Reference Document" Reference="System Reference Document">
  <Name>Silent Spell</Name>
  <Types Types="">
  </Types>
  <Benefit>A silent spell can be cast with no verbal components. Spells without verbal components are not affected. A silent spell uses up a spell slot one level higher than the spell's actual level.</Benefit>
  <Special>Bard spells cannot be enhanced by this metamagic feat.</Special>
  <Source ID="0"/>
</Feat>
<Feat ID="292" Author="" Copyright="COPYRIGHT 2001, Sigfried Trent" Reference="Net Book of Feats">
  <Name>Silver Spoon</Name>
  <Types Types="">
  </Types>
  <Benefit>When creating your character you start with double the maximum starting gold for your class.</Benefit>
  <Special>This feat may only be taken at first level.</Special>
  <Notes>This can be a big advantage for a low-level warrior type character, but it quickly evaporates as the game progresses.</Notes>
  <Source ID="0"/>
</Feat>
<Feat ID="293" Author="" Copyright="COPYRIGHT 2000, System Reference Document" Reference="System Reference Document">
  <Name>Simple Weapon Proficiency</Name>
  <Types Types="">
  </Types>
  <Benefit>The character makes attack rolls with simple weapons normally.</Benefit>
  <Normal>A character who uses a weapon without being proficient with it suffers a -4 penalty on attack rolls.</Normal>
  <Source ID="0"/>
</Feat>
<Feat ID="294" Author="" Copyright="COPYRIGHT 2000, System Reference Document" Reference="System Reference Document">
  <Name>Skill Focus</Name>
  <Types Types="">
  </Types>
  <Benefit>The character gets a +2 bonus on all skill checks with that skill.</Benefit>
  <Special>The character can gain this feat multiple times. Its effects do not stack. Each time the character takes the feat, it applies to a new skill.</Special>
  <Source ID="0"/>
</Feat>
<Feat ID="295" Author="" Copyright="COPYRIGHT 2001, Carl Cramér" Reference="Net Book of Feats">
  <Name>Skill Knack</Name>
  <Types Types="">
  </Types>
  <Benefit>Choose a skill, such as ride. You have a special knack with that skill. You must have some special ability, such as long limbs for climbers; long fingers for pick pockets, lightning calculator for profession (bookkeeper) or being double-jointed for escape artist. You get a +3 bonus with the skill in question.</Benefit>
  <Special>You can gain this feat multiple times. Its effects do not stack. Each time you take the feat, it applies to a different skill. The bonus does stack with the bonuses provided by skill learning feats, so you can take several feats to be ultra-specialized in a skill. Anyone can use a sense motive check to get a hunch about you (PHB).  If the result is at least a 10, they are able to tell which skill you have a Skill Knack for from your appearance.</Special>
  <Notes>Because you must be somehow extra qualified for the skill in question, your character description should make allowance for such an aptitude. This means you can only pick Skill Knack when creating your character or be the result of some extraordinary event in the characters career, such as being 'gifted' with donkey ears from a curse for a Skill Knack to the listen skill or getting bowlegged from countless hours in the saddle.</Notes>
  <Source ID="0"/>
</Feat>
<Feat ID="296" Author="" Copyright="COPYRIGHT 2000, Bradley H. Bemis Jr." Reference="Net Book of Feats">
  <Name>Skill Mastery</Name>
  <Types Types="">
  </Types>
  <Prerequisites>Skill Focus in the specified skill</Prerequisites>
  <Benefit>You get a +4 bonus on all skill checks with that skill</Benefit>
  <Special>You can gain this feat multiple times.  Its effects do not stack with Skill Focus or itself.  Each time you take this feat, it applies to a new skill.</Special>
  <Source ID="0"/>
</Feat>
<Feat ID="297" Author="" Copyright="COPYRIGHT 2000, Bradley H. Bemis Jr." Reference="Net Book of Feats">
  <Name>Skill Perfection</Name>
  <Types Types="">
  </Types>
  <Prerequisites>Skill Mastery in the specified skill</Prerequisites>
  <Benefit>You get a +6 bonus on all skill checks with that skill</Benefit>
  <Special>You can gain this feat multiple times.  Its effects do not stack with Skill Focus, Skill Mastery, or itself.  Each time you take this feat, it applies to a new skill.</Special>
  <Source ID="0"/>
</Feat>
<Feat ID="298" Author="" Copyright="COPYRIGHT 2001, Tyson Neumann" Reference="Net Book of Feats">
  <Name>Skilled Parry</Name>
  <Types Types="">
  </Types>
  <Prerequisites>Base Attack Bonus +5, Proficient with Weapon, Int 13+, Dex 13+, Dodge, Expertise</Prerequisites>
  <Benefit>When an opponent attacks you, you are allowed a Reflex Save with DC equal to the opponent's attack roll to avoid all damage from a single attack provided you are not unarmed.</Benefit>
  <Normal>A character not capable of this feat can forgo their attack to defend themselves and move during a round as a standard action and gain a +4 dodge bonus to Armor Class for that round.</Normal>
  <Special>Skilled Parry counts as an attack of opportunity and as such, the number of attacks of opportunity you have each round limits its usage.</Special>
  <Source ID="0"/>
</Feat>
<Feat ID="299" Author="" Copyright="COPYRIGHT 2001, Carl Cramér" Reference="Net Book of Feats">
  <Name>Slow Spell</Name>
  <Types Types="">
  </Types>
  <Prerequisites>Any one metamagical feat.</Prerequisites>
  <Benefit>Any spell with a casting time of a normal action or less now has a casting time of a full round. The benefit is that the spell takes up a spell slot one level lower than normal. A spell can never become less than it's original level through this feat, but the level modification for this feat can be used to offset the level increase from other metamagical feats.</Benefit>
  <Notes>A sorcerer or bard can use this feat, turning a full-action metmagical spell casting into a full round casting time spell (not the same thing).</Notes>
  <Source ID="0"/>
</Feat>
<Feat ID="300" Author="" Copyright="COPYRIGHT 2001, Eric D. Harry" Reference="Net Book of Feats">
  <Name>Solidify Inertial Armor</Name>
  <Types Types="">
  </Types>
  <Prerequisites>Inertial Armor, Strengthen Inertial Armor, reserve power points 3+, base attack bonus +4 or higher.</Prerequisites>
  <Benefit>As a move equivalent action you can increase the strength of your inertial armor, causing the normally invisible armor to take form and solidify around you.  This costs 5 power points and provides damage reduction equal to 5/+1 for a number of rounds equal to 1 plus your strength modifier.</Benefit>
  <Source ID="0"/>
</Feat>
<Feat ID="301" Author="" Copyright="COPYRIGHT 2000, Bradley H. Bemis Jr." Reference="Net Book of Feats">
  <Name>Soul Sacrifice</Name>
  <Types Types="">
  </Types>
  <Prerequisites>Charisma 14+, Toughness</Prerequisites>
  <Benefit>The sorcerer may permanently sacrifice a number of hit points to gain additional spell learning levels (Table 3-17, Sorcerer Spells Known).  The sorcerer may sacrifice as many hit points as he or she desires.  Spells are learned on a direct 1 to 1, hit point to spell level ratio.  A cantrip still counts as 1 spell point.  The spells learned must be determined at the time of the sacrifice.  Once this decision is made, it can never be undone.</Benefit>
  <Special>This feat may be taken multiple times.  Each time taken, the sorcerer must determine the number of hit points to be converted and the specific spells to be learned.</Special>
  <Source ID="0"/>
</Feat>
<Feat ID="302" Author="" Copyright="COPYRIGHT 2001, Carl Cramér" Reference="Net Book of Feats">
  <Name>Spear And Shield</Name>
  <Types Types="">
  </Types>
  <Prerequisites>Shield Proficiency.</Prerequisites>
  <Benefit>You can use a halfspear or shortspear two-handed together with a large shield, despite the fact that such weapons normally can't be used together.</Benefit>
  <Notes>This feat is right at home in ancient Greece, where hoplites used it. The shield is slung over the shoulder and maneuvered with the offhand that simultaneously holds the spear.</Notes>
  <Source ID="0"/>
</Feat>
<Feat ID="303" Author="" Copyright="COPYRIGHT 2001, Eric D. Harry" Reference="Net Book of Feats">
  <Name>Spell Affinity</Name>
  <Types Types="">
  </Types>
  <Prerequisites>Intelligence 13+, Ability to cast 1st level Arcane spells without preparation.</Prerequisites>
  <Benefit>If a Bard or Sorcerer, you gain bonus spells based on your Intelligence attribute.  These spells are added to your number of spells known; this feat does not increase the number of spells that you can cast per day.</Benefit>
  <Special>The bonus spells provided by this feat cannot be combined with the bonus spells provided by any other feat (based on ability score) except Cantrip.</Special>
  <Source ID="0"/>
</Feat>
<Feat ID="304" Author="" Copyright="COPYRIGHT 2000, System Reference Document" Reference="System Reference Document">
  <Name>Spell Focus</Name>
  <Types Types="">
  </Types>
  <Benefit>Add +2 to the Difficulty Class for all saving throws against spells from the school of magic the character selects to focus on.</Benefit>
  <Special>The character can gain this feat multiple times. Its effects do not stack. Each time the character takes the feat, it applies to a new school of magic.</Special>
  <Source ID="0"/>
</Feat>
<Feat ID="305" Author="" Copyright="COPYRIGHT 2000, Bradley H. Bemis Jr." Reference="Net Book of Feats">
  <Name>Spell Learning Combination</Name>
  <Types Types="">
  </Types>
  <Prerequisites>Primary ability score 13+, Concentration, 10+ ranks in Knowledge (Arcana), Special Training</Prerequisites>
  <Benefit>Primarily used by Bards and Sorcerers, this feat allows the character to mix his number of spells learnable in any combination.  When a class level is gained, each new spell-learning slot is converted to a number of spell-learning points (each spell level of the slot counts as one point).  The points are then added to a 'learning pool'.  The character learns spells by spending the appropriate number of spell-learning points for the spell desired.  In the case of 0 level spells, each 0-level spell counts as 1/2 of a spell level (i.e. 2 0-level spells equal one spell level).</Benefit>
  <Special>Once a number of spell-learning points have been spent on learning a particular spell, those spell-learning points are forever removed from that character's learning pool.</Special>
  <Notes>This feat is only taught at special academies and should require special training on the part of the PC.</Notes>
  <Source ID="0"/>
</Feat>
<Feat ID="306" Author="" Copyright="COPYRIGHT 2000, Bradley H. Bemis Jr." Reference="Net Book of Feats">
  <Name>Spell Level Combination</Name>
  <Types Types="">
  </Types>
  <Prerequisites>Primary ability score 13+, Concentration, 10+ ranks in Knowledge (Arcana), Special Training</Prerequisites>
  <Benefit>When determining the spells that will be prepared for the day (wizard, cleric, druid, paladin, ranger) or when actually casting the spells (sorcerer, bard), the spellcaster has the ability to mix his spell levels in any combination, so long as the total spell levels prepared/cast do not exceed his prepared /casting capacity or number of spells castable per day.  The number of points gained is based on the level of the spell.  It is a strait one spell point per spell level exchange.  In the case of 0 level spells, each 0-level spell counts as 1/2 of a spell level (i.e. 2 0-level spells equal one spell level).  Always round down.  The preparation/casting capacity for a single spell level is based on the spellcasters prime requisite divided by two - the spell level.   A number of spell points may be spent to cast spells of a specific level up to the preparation /casting capacity for that level.  There is a marked difference between the number of spell points and the preparation/casting capacity.</Benefit>
  <Special>This feat does not grant access to higher spell levels than the spellcaster already had access to.
Example: Morlock is a 17th level sorcerer with a 24 charisma.  He can cast 9/7/7/6/5/5/4/4/2 spells per day.  Morlock has 156 spell points.  He can cast any spell he knows of any level he can cast by subtracting the number of spell levels needed to cast the spell (and whatever metagmagic requirements might need to be met) from his spell point total.  Morlock's casting capacity (regardless of the number of spell points he has) is:  12/11/10/9/8/7/6/5/4.</Special>
  <Notes>This feat is only taught at special academies and should require special training on the part of the PC.</Notes>
  <Source ID="0"/>
</Feat>
<Feat ID="307" Author="" Copyright="COPYRIGHT 2000, System Reference Document" Reference="System Reference Document">
  <Name>Spell Mastery</Name>
  <Types Types="">
  </Types>
  <Prerequisites>Spell Mastery is available only to wizards.</Prerequisites>
  <Benefit>Each time the wizard takes this feat, choose a number of spells equal to the wizard's Intelligence modifier (they must be spells that the wizard already knows). From that point on, the wizard can prepare those spells without referring to a spellbook.</Benefit>
  <Source ID="0"/>
</Feat>
<Feat ID="308" Author="" Copyright="COPYRIGHT 2000, System Reference Document" Reference="System Reference Document">
  <Name>Spell Penetration</Name>
  <Types Types="">
  </Types>
  <Benefit>The character gets a +2 bonus to caster level checks (1d20+caster level) to beat a creature's spell resistance.</Benefit>
  <Source ID="0"/>
</Feat>
<Feat ID="310" Author="" Copyright="COPYRIGHT 2000, Michael J. Kletch" Reference="Net Book of Feats">
  <Name>Spell Toughness</Name>
  <Types Types="">
  </Types>
  <Prerequisites>Base Will save bonus +4 or higher</Prerequisites>
  <Benefit>Against spells from the chosen school, you get a +2 bonus to all saving throws.</Benefit>
  <Special>You can take this feat multiple times.  Its effects do not stack.  Each time you take the feat, it applies to a new school of magic.</Special>
  <Source ID="0"/>
</Feat>
<Feat ID="311" Author="" Copyright="COPYRIGHT 2001, Sigfried Trent" Reference="Net Book of Feats">
  <Name>Spirit Of Vengeance</Name>
  <Types Types="">
  </Types>
  <Benefit>Whenever an opponent wounds you in combat (deals damage to you), your next melee attack against that foe gets a +1 morale bonus to hit and damage.  Once you receive this bonus to an attack, the foe must wound you again for you to gain the bonus again.  If a foe wounds you multiple times before you attack them, you only gain the bonus once, and to a single attack.</Benefit>
  <Notes>One of many attack bonus feats, it has more flavor than others, but requires a little book keeping from the player.</Notes>
  <Source ID="0"/>
</Feat>
<Feat ID="312" Author="" Copyright="COPYRIGHT 2000, System Reference Document" Reference="System Reference Document">
  <Name>Spirited Charge</Name>
  <Types Types="">
  </Types>
  <Prerequisites>Ride skill, Mounted Combat, Ride-By Attack.</Prerequisites>
  <Benefit>When mounted and using the charge action, the character deals double damage with a melee weapon (or triple damage with a lance).</Benefit>
  <Source ID="0"/>
</Feat>
<Feat ID="313" Author="" Copyright="COPYRIGHT 2001, Eric D. Harry" Reference="Net Book of Feats">
  <Name>Spirited Dive</Name>
  <Types Types="">
  </Types>
  <Prerequisites>Fly speed, Flyby Attack.</Prerequisites>
  <Benefit>When flying down, the creature can make a special charge action, dealing double damage on a successful claw or weapon strike (or triple damage if the creature normally inflicts double damage on a dive attack).  The creature gains a +2 attack bonus but suffers a -2 penalty to AC when making this attack.  The creature can still use its Flyby Attack feat when making a Spirited Dive.</Benefit>
  <Source ID="0"/>
</Feat>
<Feat ID="314" Author="" Copyright="COPYRIGHT 2001, Eric D. Harry" Reference="Net Book of Feats">
  <Name>Spontaneous Metacasting</Name>
  <Types Types="">
  </Types>
  <Prerequisites>Ability to spontaneously cast cure or inflict spells, metamagic feat used to augment your spell.</Prerequisites>
  <Benefit>You can spontaneously cast a metamagically enhanced cure spell (or inflict spell as appropriate) in 1-action.</Benefit>
  <Normal>Trading in divine energy to spontaneously cast a 1-action metamagic spell normally requires a full-round action, while spontaneously casting a metamagic spell with a longer casting time requires one extra full-round action to cast.</Normal>
  <Source ID="0"/>
</Feat>
<Feat ID="316" Author="" Copyright="COPYRIGHT 2000, System Reference Document" Reference="System Reference Document">
  <Name>Spring Attack</Name>
  <Types Types="">
  </Types>
  <Prerequisites>Dex 13+, Dodge, Mobility, base attack bonus +4 or higher.</Prerequisites>
  <Benefit>When using the attack action with a melee weapon, the character can move both before and after the attack, provided that the character's total distance moved is not greater than the character's speed. Moving in this way does not provoke an attack of opportunity from the defender the character attacks. The character can't use this feat if the character is in heavy armor.</Benefit>
  <Source ID="0"/>
</Feat>
<Feat ID="317" Author="" Copyright="COPYRIGHT 2001, Carl Cramér" Reference="Net Book of Feats">
  <Name>Stable Spell</Name>
  <Types Types="">
  </Types>
  <Benefit>A stable spell does not need concentration. Any (C) note in the duration field is replaced with a (D) note instead, which allows you to end the spell at will. A Stable Spell uses up a spell slot two levels higher than the spell's actual level.</Benefit>
  <Special>If you want to control aspects of the spell, such as controlling the movement of an illusion, you must still concentrate while in control. If you don't concentrate, the spell effect will still remain, without changing in any way.</Special>
  <Source ID="0"/>
</Feat>
<Feat ID="318" Author="" Copyright="COPYRIGHT 2001, Eric D. Harry" Reference="Net Book of Feats">
  <Name>Stalwart Defender</Name>
  <Types Types="">
  </Types>
  <Prerequisites>Dwarf, Defensive Stance class ability, base attack bonus +9 or higher.</Prerequisites>
  <Benefit>You can use your Defensive Stance class ability one more time per day.</Benefit>
  <Normal>Defensive Stance is a class ability of the Dwarven Defender prestige class (Chapter 3, DMG).</Normal>
  <Source ID="0"/>
</Feat>
<Feat ID="319" Author="" Copyright="COPYRIGHT 2001, Bradley H. Bemis Jr." Reference="Net Book of Feats">
  <Name>Stand Against Spell</Name>
  <Types Types="">
  </Types>
  <Prerequisites>Great Fortitude</Prerequisites>
  <Benefit>Gain an additional +2 to fortitude saves.</Benefit>
  <Special>This feat stacks with Great Fortitude.</Special>
  <Source ID="0"/>
</Feat>
<Feat ID="320" Author="" Copyright="COPYRIGHT 2000, System Reference Document" Reference="System Reference Document">
  <Name>Still Spell</Name>
  <Types Types="">
  </Types>
  <Benefit>A still spell can be cast with no somatic components. Spells without somatic components are not affected. A still spell uses up a spell slot one level higher than the spell's actual level.</Benefit>
  <Source ID="0"/>
</Feat>
<Feat ID="321" Author="" Copyright="COPYRIGHT 2001, Sigfried Trent" Reference="Net Book of Feats">
  <Name>Stone Thrower</Name>
  <Types Types="">
  </Types>
  <Benefit>You treat normal stones between 1 and 5 pounds as a simple ranged weapon.  A typical stone deals 1D6 damage, has a threat of 20 X2, and has a range increment of 20.  A poor stone has the same stats but deals only 1D4 damage.  You may find a typical stone in some outdoor environments (DM's discretion) as a full round action, or a poor stone as a move equivalent action.  You may take all the usual weapon feats using stone as a weapon of choice.</Benefit>
  <Normal>A stone is considered an improvised weapon and deals small amounts of subdual damage.</Normal>
  <Notes>This feat is not just about throwing rocks fairly well, but treats throwing rocks as a martial proficiency like a monks use of his hands.  You have a throwing technique that you constantly practice and perfect like a baseball pitcher or the like.  Your skill makes up for the irregularity of the weapon itself.</Notes>
  <Source ID="0"/>
</Feat>
<Feat ID="322" Author="" Copyright="COPYRIGHT 2001, Eric D. Harry" Reference="Net Book of Feats">
  <Name>Strengthen Inertial Armor</Name>
  <Types Types="">
  </Types>
  <Prerequisites>Inertial Armor, reserve power points 1+, base attack bonus +3 or higher.</Prerequisites>
  <Benefit>As a move equivalent action you can increase the strength of your inertial armor.  This costs 3 power points and increases the armor bonus provided by your Inertial Armor to +7.  The armor can remain strengthened for a number of rounds equal to 1 plus your strength modifier.  Like Inertial Armor, the armor bonus provided by Solidify Inertial Armor does not stack with the armor bonus provided by mundane or enchanted armor and shields and is fully effective against ethereal and incorporeal beings.</Benefit>
  <Source ID="0"/>
</Feat>
<Feat ID="323" Author="" Copyright="COPYRIGHT 2001, Eric D. Harry" Reference="Net Book of Feats">
  <Name>Strike Favored Enemy</Name>
  <Types Types="">
  </Types>
  <Prerequisites>Favored Enemy class ability, base attack bonus +3 or higher.</Prerequisites>
  <Benefit>You may add your favored enemy bonus to all weapon attack rolls made in melee combat and ranged combat against targets within 30 feet when attacking any of your favored enemies.</Benefit>
  <Normal>You may add your favored enemy bonus to Bluff, Listen, Sense Motive, Spot and Wilderness Lore checks as well as weapon damage rolls in melee combat and ranged combat against targets within 30 feet.</Normal>
  <Special>This bonus does not apply to creatures that are immune to critical hits.</Special>
  <Source ID="0"/>
</Feat>
<Feat ID="324" Author="" Copyright="COPYRIGHT 2000, System Reference Document" Reference="System Reference Document">
  <Name>Stunning Fist</Name>
  <Types Types="">
  </Types>
  <Prerequisites>Dex 13+, Improved Unarmed Strike, Wis 13+, base attack bonus +8 or higher.</Prerequisites>
  <Benefit>Declare that the character is using the feat before making an attack roll (thus, a missed attack roll ruins the attempt). It forces a foe damaged by the character's unarmed attack to make a Fortitude saving throw (DC 10 + one-half the character's level + Wis modifier), in addition to dealing damage normally. If the defender fails his saving throw, he is stunned for 1 round (until just before the character's next action). A stunned character can't act and loses any Dexterity bonus to Armor Class. Attackers get a +2 bonus on attack rolls against a stunned opponent. The character may attempt a stunning attack once per day for every four levels attained, and no more than once per round.</Benefit>
  <Source ID="0"/>
</Feat>
<Feat ID="325" Author="" Copyright="COPYRIGHT 2001, Sigfried Trent" Reference="Net Book of Feats">
  <Name>Stylize Spell</Name>
  <Types Types="">
  </Types>
  <Prerequisites>Access to the illusion school (or a lack of prohibition against using it)</Prerequisites>
  <Benefit>You can subtly change the appearance, sound, taste or smell of spells you cast.  The changes to the spell must not have any appreciable game effect outside of making the caster seem impressive.  For instance, making a wall of fire appear as something that isn't hot and dangerous would be out of the question, but having it whisper your name would be acceptable.  The effects of this spell should never make something dangerous seem less so or something safe seem dangerous.  It should never change the apparent area of effect of the spell, disguise the spell in any way, or simulate the appearance of another spell.</Benefit>
  <Notes>The DM should be careful not to allow the caster to gain a practical benefit from this feat aside from personal reactions of spectators.</Notes>
  <Source ID="0"/>
</Feat>
<Feat ID="326" Author="" Copyright="COPYRIGHT 2001, Scott Metzger" Reference="Net Book of Feats">
  <Name>Subtle Spell</Name>
  <Types Types="">
  </Types>
  <Prerequisites>Spellcraft skill.</Prerequisites>
  <Benefit>When you cast a subtle spell those who could observe you must make a Spot check opposed by your Spellcraft check to identify that you are casting a spell.  A subtle spell uses up a spell slot one level higher than the spell's actual level.</Benefit>
  <Normal>Without this feat spell casting is automatically recognized as spell casting.</Normal>
  <Notes>Casting a subtle spell still draws an attack of opportunity.  If the person taking the attack of opportunity fails the opposed Spot check they still get the attack of opportunity but do not know why you let your guard down.</Notes>
  <Source ID="0"/>
</Feat>
<Feat ID="327" Author="" Copyright="COPYRIGHT 2000, Michael J. Kletch" Reference="Net Book of Feats">
  <Name>Sudden Action</Name>
  <Types Types="">
  </Types>
  <Prerequisites>Improved Initiative, Mobility, Quick Draw, Combat Reflexes</Prerequisites>
  <Benefit>If a combat begins with a surprise round and you are not surprised, you may draw your weapon (a free action) and take a partial action before initiative is rolled.  This partial action may only be used to attack a surprised opponent, but a 5-foot step is allowed before or after the attack.
You may also make draw your weapon and make a surprise attack in a non-combat situation with the use of this feat; the target of the attack is considered surprised.</Benefit>
  <Source ID="0"/>
</Feat>
<Feat ID="328" Author="" Copyright="COPYRIGHT 2001, Carl Cramér" Reference="Net Book of Feats">
  <Name>Summoning Concentration</Name>
  <Types Types="">
  </Types>
  <Benefit>You can maintain the duration of a summon spell (such as summon monster or summon nature's ally) through concentration.  As long as you concentrate on the spell, do not count time off it's duration.  After you stop concentrating, the normal duration resumes and then terminates as normal.  You cannot resume concentration.</Benefit>
  <Source ID="0"/>
</Feat>
<Feat ID="329" Author="" Copyright="COPYRIGHT 2000, System Reference Document" Reference="System Reference Document">
  <Name>Sunder</Name>
  <Types Types="">
  </Types>
  <Prerequisites>Str 13+, Power Attack.</Prerequisites>
  <Benefit>When the character strikes at an opponent's weapon, the character does not provoke an attack of opportunity.</Benefit>
  <Source ID="0"/>
</Feat>
<Feat ID="330" Author="" Copyright="COPYRIGHT 2001, Eric D. Harry" Reference="Net Book of Feats">
  <Name>Supernatural Resistance</Name>
  <Types Types="">
  </Types>
  <Benefit>Any supernatural ability that directly effects the creature must beat the creature's SR or PR to have any effect.  If the attacking creature cannot beat the SR or PR of the defender on a level check (1d20 + CR creature), the supernatural ability is negated exactly as if it were a spell or spell-like ability.</Benefit>
  <Normal>Supernatural abilities are not normally subject to SR or PR.</Normal>
  <Special>Characters that gain SR or PR by race (like drow, githyanki and githzerai) can choose this feat as a Special feat.  Characters with PR can only choose this feat if the default Psionics-Magic Transparency option.</Special>
  <Source ID="0"/>
</Feat>
<Feat ID="331" Author="" Copyright="COPYRIGHT 2000, Michael J. Kletch" Reference="Net Book of Feats">
  <Name>Tap Item</Name>
  <Types Types="">
  </Types>
  <Prerequisites>One or more of the following: Craft Magic Arms and Armor, Craft Rod, Craft Wondrous Item, Forge Ring.</Prerequisites>
  <Benefit>When creating a new magic item using one of the prerequisite feats, you may draw up to half of the XP cost from another, existing item of the same type.  The item from which the energy is taken is destroyed in the process.  The item tapped cannot be cursed, and this feat has no effect on minor or major artifacts.  The amount of XP that can be drawn from any item is equal to half of the XP that would be necessary to create that item.  If an item has charges, its original XP value is reduced by the fraction of charges used.</Benefit>
  <Source ID="0"/>
</Feat>
<Feat ID="332" Author="" Copyright="COPYRIGHT 2001, Scott Metzger" Reference="Net Book of Feats">
  <Name>Team Fighting</Name>
  <Types Types="">
  </Types>
  <Prerequisites>Base attack modifier of +1 or better.</Prerequisites>
  <Benefit>Two or more people can fight together as a team.  The team members block and parry blows for each other.  Team members also work together to open up opponent's weaknesses.  Team members need to be within each others threatened area and every team member needs to have the feat. Each person having Team Fighting gets a +1 to hit bonus and a +1 Armor Class bonus.  Also, if two people have Team Fighting they can switch carried items as a free action.  This would allow one person to reload a Heavy Crossbow or Repeating Crossbow while the other fires, thus one character could fire the Heavy Crossbow every round while the other guy is loading.</Benefit>
  <Source ID="0"/>
</Feat>
<Feat ID="241" Author="" Copyright="COPYRIGHT 2001, Eric D. Harry" Reference="Net Book of Feats">
  <Name>Telepathy</Name>
  <Types Types="">
  </Types>
  <Benefit>All psionic powers from the clairsentience and telepathy disciplines must beat the creature's PR in order to discover anything about it.</Benefit>
  <Normal>PR does not normally apply against most powers from the clairsentience discipline or against powers from the telepathy discipline that do not directly influence, control or effect the target creature.</Normal>
  <Special>Characters that gain PR by race (like githyanki or githzerai) can choose this feat as a Special feat.  If using the default Psionics-Magic Transparency option, this feat also extends your PR to resist all spells and spell-like abilities from the divination school of magic.</Special>
  <Source ID="0"/>
</Feat>
<Feat ID="333" Author="" Copyright="COPYRIGHT 2001, Eric D. Harry" Reference="Net Book of Feats">
  <Name>Third Eye</Name>
  <Types Types="">
  </Types>
  <Prerequisites>Wis 13+.</Prerequisites>
  <Benefit>You gain a +2 bonus on all Psicraft checks and a +2 bonus on all Will saves against illusion spells and spell-like effects.</Benefit>
  <Source ID="0"/>
</Feat>
<Feat ID="334" Author="" Copyright="COPYRIGHT 2001, Eric D. Harry" Reference="Net Book of Feats">
  <Name>Threatened Reach</Name>
  <Types Types="">
  </Types>
  <Prerequisites>Dex 13+, Dodge, Mobility, Spring Attack, Combat Reflexes, base attack bonus +6 or higher.</Prerequisites>
  <Benefit>Designate one opponent on your turn as a free action.  Against this opponent, you increase your threatened range by 5 feet, as long as you maintain a direct, unimpeded line of sight with your chosen opponent.  If this opponent provokes an attack of opportunity within this expanded range, you may take an immediate attack of opportunity against him.  You are free to select a new opponent once per round in initiative order on your turn.</Benefit>
  <Normal>Your threatened range is normally 5 feet unless larger than M-sized or armed with a reach weapon.</Normal>
  <Special>You may only use this feat when unarmored or in medium or lighter armor.</Special>
  <Source ID="0"/>
</Feat>
<Feat ID="335" Author="" Copyright="COPYRIGHT 2001, Eric D. Harry" Reference="Net Book of Feats">
  <Name>Tornado Attack</Name>
  <Types Types="">
  </Types>
  <Prerequisites>Int 13+, Dex 13+, Dodge, Mobility, Spring Attack, Whirlwind Attack (; Expertise) or Whirlwind Strike, base attack bonus +12 or higher.</Prerequisites>
  <Benefit>You can take a 5-foot step while making your Whirlwind attack, allowing you to attack all opponents within range before and after your 5-foot movement.  This requires a full-attack action, you can only strike at an individual opponent within range once and you are still limited to one 5-foot step per round.  All restrictions and benefits to your 5-foot movement apply normally.</Benefit>
  <Source ID="0"/>
</Feat>
<Feat ID="336" Author="" Copyright="COPYRIGHT 2000, Bradley H. Bemis Jr." Reference="Net Book of Feats">
  <Name>Touch Mastery</Name>
  <Types Types="">
  </Types>
  <Prerequisites>Knowledge (combat), Base Attack Bonus of +3 or better</Prerequisites>
  <Benefit>In addition to any other touch based attack bonuses, you may add your intelligence modifier to your attack roll when making touch attacks.</Benefit>
  <Special>To gain this benefit, you must be able to assess your opponent completely for at least three rounds of combat.  During this period of study you are only able to take a partial action each round.  The effect lasts until the end of the encounter.</Special>
  <Source ID="0"/>
</Feat>
<Feat ID="337" Author="" Copyright="COPYRIGHT 2001, Eric D. Harry" Reference="Net Book of Feats">
  <Name>Touch To Ray</Name>
  <Types Types="">
  </Types>
  <Benefit>Any touch spell can be prepared and/or cast as a ranged touch attack with a range of close (25 ft. + 5 ft. for every 2 full caster levels).  A touch spell prepared or cast in this manner uses up a spell slot two levels higher than the spell's actual level.</Benefit>
  <Source ID="0"/>
</Feat>
<Feat ID="338" Author="" Copyright="COPYRIGHT 2000, System Reference Document" Reference="System Reference Document">
  <Name>Toughness</Name>
  <Types Types="">
  </Types>
  <Benefit>The character gains +3 hit points.</Benefit>
  <Special>A character may gain this feat multiple times.</Special>
  <Source ID="0"/>
</Feat>
<Feat ID="339" Author="" Copyright="COPYRIGHT 2000, System Reference Document" Reference="System Reference Document">
  <Name>Track</Name>
  <Types Types="">
  </Types>
  <Benefit>To find tracks or to follow them for one mile requires a Wilderness Lore check. The character must make another Wilderness Lore check every time the tracks become difficult to follow, such as when other tracks cross them or when the tracks backtrack and diverge. 
The character moves at half normal speed (or at normal speed with a -5 penalty on the check). The DC depends on the surface and the prevailing conditions: 
&lt;pre&gt;
Surface        DC
-------        --
Very soft      5
Soft           10
Firm           15
Hard           20&lt;/pre&gt;
Very Soft Ground: Any surface (fresh snow, thick dust, wet mud) that holds deep, clear impressions of footprints. 
Soft Ground: Any surface soft enough to yield to pressure, but firmer than wet mud or fresh snow, in which the creature leaves frequent but shallow footprints. 
Firm Ground: Most normal outdoor surfaces (such as lawns, fields, woods, and the like) or exceptionally soft or dirty indoor surfaces (thick rugs, very dirty or dusty floors). The creature might leave some traces (broken branches, tufts of hair) but leaves only occasional or partial footprints. 
Hard Ground: Any surface that doesn't hold footprints at all, such as bare rock or indoor floors. Most streambeds fall into this category, since any footprints left behind are obscured or washed away. The creature leaves only traces (scuff marks, displaced pebbles). 
&lt;pre&gt;
Condition                                                            DC Modifier
---------                                                            -----------
Every three creatures in the group being tracked                     -1
Size of creature or creatures being tracked:*
  Fine                                                               +8
  Diminutive                                                         +4
  Tiny                                                               +2
  Small                                                              +1
  Medium-size                                                        0
  Large                                                              -1
  Huge                                                               -2
  Gargantuan                                                         -4
  Colossal                                                           -8
Every 24 hours since the trail was made                              +1
Every hour of rain since the trail was made                          +1
Fresh snow cover since the trail was made                            +10
Poor visibility:**
  Overcast or moonless night                                         +6
  Moonlight                                                          +3
  Fog or precipitation                                               +3
Tracked party hides trail (and moves at half speed)                  +5&lt;/pre&gt;
 *For a group of mixed sizes, apply only the modifier for the largest 
size category.
**Apply only the largest modifier from this category.
If the character fails a Wilderness Lore check, the character can retry after 1 hour (outdoors) or 10 minutes (indoors) of searching. </Benefit>
  <Normal>A character without this feat can use the Search skill to find tracks, but can only follow tracks if the DC is 10 or less.</Normal>
  <Source ID="0"/>
</Feat>
<Feat ID="340" Author="" Copyright="COPYRIGHT 2000, System Reference Document" Reference="System Reference Document">
  <Name>Trample</Name>
  <Types Types="">
  </Types>
  <Prerequisites>Ride skill, Mounted Combat.</Prerequisites>
  <Benefit>When the character attempts to overrun an opponent while mounted, the target may not choose to avoid the character. If the character knocks down the target, the character's mount may make one hoof attack against the target, gaining the standard +4 bonus on attack rolls against prone targets.</Benefit>
  <Source ID="0"/>
</Feat>
<Feat ID="341" Author="" Copyright="COPYRIGHT 2001, Rebecca Glenn (Becky)" Reference="Net Book of Feats">
  <Name>Transfer Spell</Name>
  <Types Types="">
  </Types>
  <Benefit>A Transferred spell has a range of Touch and is treated as a touch attack. In this way you can cast a spell with a range of Personal and use it on another person. This feat has no effect on spells with a range other than Personal. The target of the spell must accept the spell voluntarily. A Transferred spell takes up a spell slot one levels higher than the spell's actual level.
Example: Divine Favor (1st level) allows the caster to call upon the strength and wisdom of a deity for luck bonuses to his own hit and damage rolls. Transferred Divine Favor (3rd level) allows the caster to call upon the strength and wisdom of a deity for luck bonuses to hit and damage rolls and bestow them upon a touched target (probably of the same faith).</Benefit>
  <Source ID="0"/>
</Feat>
<Feat ID="342" Author="" Copyright="COPYRIGHT 2000, Bradley H. Bemis Jr." Reference="Net Book of Feats">
  <Name>Transference</Name>
  <Types Types="">
  </Types>
  <Prerequisites>Any item creation feat</Prerequisites>
  <Benefit>While touching another creature, use their XPs to fuel an item creation feat instead of your own.</Benefit>
  <Special>The creature touched must be a willing subject with an intelligence of 3 or greater.  Any magic used to control the creature will cause the effort to fail.</Special>
  <Notes>Under no circumstances can another creature ever be forced (even through a wish spell) to succumb to the effects of this feat.  It MUST be a voluntary action.</Notes>
  <Source ID="0"/>
</Feat>
<Feat ID="343" Author="" Copyright="COPYRIGHT 2000, Michael J. Kletch" Reference="Net Book of Feats">
  <Name>Trick Spell</Name>
  <Types Types="">
  </Types>
  <Prerequisites>Spell Focus</Prerequisites>
  <Benefit>The DC for others to identify the name or school of a Trick Spell is increased by +4.  Trick Spells cannot be counterspelled normally.  Dispel Magic can be used per its description to counterspell a spell prepared as a Trick Spell.
A spellcaster must have Spell Focus in the school of the spell that he or she wishes to prepare as a Trick Spell.  A Trick Spell uses up a spell slot one level higher than the spell's actual level.</Benefit>
  <Source ID="0"/>
</Feat>
<Feat ID="344" Author="" Copyright="COPYRIGHT 2001, Eric D. Harry" Reference="Net Book of Feats">
  <Name>Trigger Psionic Defense</Name>
  <Types Types="">
  </Types>
  <Prerequisites>Psychic Bastion, reserve power points (see below)</Prerequisites>
  <Benefit>This feat mimics the Trigger Power feat, except that it applies to one known psionic defense mode of your choice.  You can attempt to raise this defense mode for free, without spending power points, as a free action every time that you use it, though you must have at least enough power points in reserve to raise the defense mode normally.  On a successful Wisdom ability check (DC 12 + power points used to activate your defense mode), you can raise this psionic defense without spending power points.  On a failed check, you are forced to pay the normal power point cost to raise the defense mode.</Benefit>
  <Special>You can take this feat up to five times, each time applying the feat to one additional known psionic defense mode of your choice.  This feat only applies to previously known psionic defense modes and does not allow the character to discover additional defense modes.</Special>
  <Source ID="0"/>
</Feat>
<Feat ID="345" Author="" Copyright="COPYRIGHT 2001, Eric D. Harry" Reference="Net Book of Feats">
  <Name>True Power Of The Mind</Name>
  <Types Types="">
  </Types>
  <Benefit>Add +1 to the Difficulty Class for all saving throws against your psionic powers.</Benefit>
  <Source ID="0"/>
</Feat>
<Feat ID="346" Author="" Copyright="COPYRIGHT 2001, Brian A. Smith" Reference="Net Book of Feats">
  <Name>Tumbling Attack</Name>
  <Types Types="">
  </Types>
  <Prerequisites>Dex 15+, Dodge, Int 13+, Expertise, Mobility, Spring Attack, base attack +6, Tumble Skill, Skill Focus - tumble</Prerequisites>
  <Benefit>As a full attack action, you are able to tumble up to 20 feet, and, if you succeed at your tumble check (see Tumble skill, PHB), you suffer no attacks of opportunity and you may make your full number of attacks while you tumble.  However, you are able to attack no more than once from any single five foot square through which you move (including the squares in which you start and finish the tumble).  Even with this feat, the move is so difficult to execute that it adds +2 to the DC of your tumble check and all attacks suffer -2 penalty to hit.  If you fail your tumble check, you suffer attacks of opportunity normally and can make only a single attack.</Benefit>
  <Normal>You tumble as a move action and can make a single attack as a standard action.</Normal>
  <Special>This feat cannot be used with ranged attacks or reach weapons.  If you are using two weapons or a double weapon, you still may only attack once from each square, so that the maximum number of attacks you can execute is 5.</Special>
  <Source ID="0"/>
</Feat>
<Feat ID="348" Author="" Copyright="COPYRIGHT 2001, Eric D. Harry" Reference="Net Book of Feats">
  <Name>Twin Weapon Fighting</Name>
  <Types Types="">
  </Types>
  <Prerequisites>Ambidexterity, Two-Weapon Fighting, base attack bonus +6 or higher.</Prerequisites>
  <Benefit>Choose a one-handed weapon, based on your size.  When wielding one of the chosen weapons in each hand, you wield the weapon in your off-hand as if it were a light weapon.</Benefit>
  <Normal>With the Ambidexterity and Two-Weapon Fighting feats, you can normally wield a pair of one-handed weapons at a 4 attack penalty with your primary and secondary weapons.  This feat reduces the attack penalty to 2 with your primary and secondary weapons, the same penalties that you would have if you had a light weapon in your off-hand.</Normal>
  <Source ID="0"/>
</Feat>
<Feat ID="351" Author="" Copyright="COPYRIGHT 2001, Carl Cramér" Reference="Net Book of Feats">
  <Name>Ventriloquism</Name>
  <Types Types="">
  </Types>
  <Prerequisites>Perform (with training as a ventriloquist)</Prerequisites>
  <Benefit>As a standard action, you can use the Perform skill to make your voice appear to come from another location. You must decide where you want your voice to appear to come from; the difficulty is equal to the number of feet away you wish to throw your voice. If there is something there that moves in a manner suggestive of speech or of making the sounds you are throwing, reduce the difficulty by 10. Listeners can try to realize what you are doing with an opposed listen roll, but such a listen roll is subject to normal range penalties.</Benefit>
  <Normal>Any performer who has chosen this field (see PHB) can learn to do this on stage, using a puppet, but with this feat, you can do it in action and be convincing.</Normal>
  <Source ID="0"/>
</Feat>
<Feat ID="352" Author="" Copyright="COPYRIGHT 2001, Eric D. Harry" Reference="Net Book of Feats">
  <Name>Vigilant Psychic Defender</Name>
  <Types Types="">
  </Types>
  <Prerequisites>Psychic Bastion, reserve power points 2+</Prerequisites>
  <Benefit>You are able to react instantly to psionic attack and can raise a psionic defense mode even when caught flat-footed.  Raising a psionic defense mode in this manner requires you to pay power points equal to the cost of the defense + 1.</Benefit>
  <Normal>A psionic defender cannot normally raise a defense mode when caught flat-footed.</Normal>
  <Source ID="0"/>
</Feat>
<Feat ID="353" Author="" Copyright="COPYRIGHT 2000, Michael J. Kletch" Reference="Net Book of Feats">
  <Name>Vital Strike</Name>
  <Types Types="">
  </Types>
  <Prerequisites>Weapon Specialization with the weapon, Power Attack, base attack bonus +8 or higher</Prerequisites>
  <Benefit>Any threat roll that also is a successful attack with the weapon always results in a Critical Hit.</Benefit>
  <Special>You can take this feat multiple times.  Its effects do not stack.  Each time you take the feat, it applies to a new weapon.</Special>
  <Source ID="0"/>
</Feat>
<Feat ID="354" Author="" Copyright="COPYRIGHT 2001, Carl Cramér" Reference="Net Book of Feats">
  <Name>Ward</Name>
  <Types Types="">
  </Types>
  <Benefit>You create a magical trap, following the rules in Core rulebook II.  The cost of a first level trap created by a first level caster is 50 gp for one-use trap, 150 gp for a trap that recharges, but only works once a day, and 500 for a trap that operates repeatedly or continually.  As usual, multiply these costs by the spell level and caster level for more powerful traps.   As with most item creation feats, the XP cost is 1/25 of the base cost, creation takes one day of work for every 1,000 gp base price, and the cost in materials is half the base price of the enchantment.</Benefit>
  <Special>You must define the triggering circumstance and how the spell is to be cast when creating the ward.  The ward can only react to simple events within 5' per caster level in a programmed fashion.  It cannot react to how and why an action is done.  A ward with a continual detect spell (such as detect evil) can be used as a trigger for a second ward.  Common trigger events include 'after five days', 'when the door opens' or 'when a creature of size small or larger moves across'.  You can have up to three triggers.  You can set the ward to ignore certain species or specific creatures, give it a password, or provide other means of bypassing it safely.</Special>
  <Notes>The ward is imbued in an object, and destroying that object destroys the ward.  To counter this, a common trigger is 'if the ward is destroyed'.  Spellcasters usually pick sturdy objects, like statues or wall carvings, to hold wards.  The DM must watch out for 'traps' that repeatedly cast beneficial spells like cure light wounds.  An altar could indeed be enchanted so that it repeatedly heals those praying at it, but it would typically only heal each petitioner once per day.  It can not distinguish the faithful, but it can distinguish people by clothing or other gear (such as holy symbols) or by a prayer they recite.</Notes>
  <Source ID="0"/>
</Feat>
<Feat ID="355" Author="" Copyright="COPYRIGHT 2001, Michael J. Kletch" Reference="Net Book of Feats">
  <Name>Way Of The Gargoyle</Name>
  <Types Types="">
  </Types>
  <Prerequisites>Combat Reflexes, Psionic Focus (Psychometabolism), reserve power points 5+</Prerequisites>
  <Benefit>If you have three or more natural attacks, either through the use of claw- or bite-giving Psychometabolism powers, Polymorph Self, Shape Change or some other power or effect, you have act as if you have the Multi-attack feat as described on page 11 of Core Rulebook III.  Your primary attack suffers no attack penalty and all of your secondary attacks suffer only a -2 penalty.</Benefit>
  <Source ID="0"/>
</Feat>
<Feat ID="349" Author="" Copyright="COPYRIGHT 2001, Carl Cramér" Reference="Net Book of Feats">
  <Name>Weapon Combination</Name>
  <Types Types="">
  </Types>
  <Prerequisites>Dexterity 15+, proficient with both weapons.</Prerequisites>
  <Benefit>You gain the use of the Two-Weapon Fighting and Ambidexterity feats, but only with a specific combination of weapons.  The weapon combination must be specified when the feat is first bought and is limited to two specific light or one-handed weapons.  These can be two identical weapons.</Benefit>
  <Special>You can learn later feats for which Ambidexterity or Two-Weapon fighting are prerequisites based on the 'virtual' feats learned with Two-Weapon Combination, but you can then only use those feats with the specific weapon combination you have chosen.</Special>
  <Notes>You save up a feat, but you can only fight with one specific combination of two weapons.</Notes>
  <Source ID="0"/>
</Feat>
<Feat ID="175" Author="" Copyright="COPYRIGHT 2000, System Reference Document" Reference="System Reference Document">
  <Name>Weapon Fighting</Name>
  <Types Types="">
  </Types>
  <Prerequisites>Two-Weapon Fighting, Ambidexterity, base attack bonus +9 or higher.</Prerequisites>
  <Benefit>In addition to the standard single extra attack the character gets with an off-hand weapon, the character gets a second attack with the off-hand weapon, albeit at a -5 penalty.</Benefit>
  <Normal>Without this feat, the character can only get a single extra attack with an off-hand weapon.</Normal>
  <Special>A ranger who meets only the base attack bonus prerequisite can gain this feat, but can only use it when wearing light armor or no armor.</Special>
  <Source ID="0"/>
</Feat>
<Feat ID="350" Author="" Copyright="COPYRIGHT 2000, System Reference Document" Reference="System Reference Document">
  <Name>Weapon Fighting</Name>
  <Types Types="">
  </Types>
  <Benefit>The character's penalties for fighting with two weapons are reduced by 2.</Benefit>
  <Source ID="0"/>
</Feat>
<Feat ID="356" Author="" Copyright="COPYRIGHT 2000, System Reference Document" Reference="System Reference Document">
  <Name>Weapon Finesse</Name>
  <Types Types="">
  </Types>
  <Prerequisites>Proficient with weapon, base attack bonus +1 or higher.</Prerequisites>
  <Benefit>With the selected weapon, the character may use a Dexterity modifier instead of a Strength modifier on attack rolls. Since the character needs the second hand for balance, apply the armor check penalty of any shield worn to attack rolls.</Benefit>
  <Special>The character can gain this feat multiple times. Each time the character takes the feat, it applies to a new weapon.</Special>
  <Source ID="0"/>
</Feat>
<Feat ID="357" Author="" Copyright="COPYRIGHT 2000, System Reference Document" Reference="System Reference Document">
  <Name>Weapon Focus</Name>
  <Types Types="">
  </Types>
  <Prerequisites>Proficient with weapon, base attack bonus +1 or higher.</Prerequisites>
  <Benefit>The character adds +1 to all attack rolls the character makes using the selected weapon.</Benefit>
  <Special>The character can gain this feat multiple times. Its effects do not stack. Each time the character takes the feat, it applies to a new weapon.</Special>
  <Source ID="0"/>
</Feat>
<Feat ID="358" Author="" Copyright="COPYRIGHT 2001, Carl Cramér" Reference="Net Book of Feats">
  <Name>Weapon Juggle</Name>
  <Types Types="">
  </Types>
  <Prerequisites>Dexterity 13+, Fast Draw, perform skill with juggle ability.</Prerequisites>
  <Benefit>You can juggle weapons and similarly sized objects during combat. You can draw, sheathe, or shift them from hand to hand as a free action. You can even pick them up from the ground as a free action, as long as you can kick at them. You can do this at the start and end of your turn, but not on somebody else's turn or in the middle of an attack sequence. These actions never trigger attacks of opportunity.</Benefit>
  <Source ID="0"/>
</Feat>
<Feat ID="359" Author="" Copyright="COPYRIGHT 2000, System Reference Document" Reference="System Reference Document">
  <Name>Weapon Specialization</Name>
  <Types Types="">
  </Types>
  <Prerequisites>Fighter 4th+.</Prerequisites>
  <Benefit>The character adds +2 to all damage inflicted with the weapon the character has specialized with. If the weapon is a ranged weapon, the target must be within 30 feet.</Benefit>
  <Special>The character can gain this feat multiple times. Its effects do not stack. Each time the character takes the feat, it applies to a new weapon.</Special>
  <Source ID="0"/>
</Feat>
<Feat ID="360" Author="" Copyright="COPYRIGHT 2001, Carl Cramér" Reference="Net Book of Feats">
  <Name>Weapon Tricks</Name>
  <Types Types="">
  </Types>
  <Benefit>Many types of melee weapons can conceivably do two different types of damage. Examples are swords (could do slashing or piercing), picks (could do bludgeoning or piercing) and single-edged or bludgeon-backed axes (could do slashing and bludgeoning). When wielding such a weapon, you can opt to do either of the two types of damage.</Benefit>
  <Notes>The DM is the final arbiter on what types of damage a weapon can do, based on the illustration, common sense and his knowledge on how these weapons are used in real life. If in doubt, go with your gut feeling.</Notes>
  <Source ID="0"/>
</Feat>
<Feat ID="361" Author="" Copyright="COPYRIGHT 2000, System Reference Document" Reference="System Reference Document">
  <Name>Whirlwind Attack</Name>
  <Types Types="">
  </Types>
  <Prerequisites>Int 13+, Expertise, Dex 13+, Dodge, Mobility, base attack bonus +4 or higher, Spring Attack.</Prerequisites>
  <Benefit>When the character performs the full attack action, he or she can give up all regular attacks and instead make one melee attack at the full base attack bonus against each opponent within 5 feet.</Benefit>
  <Source ID="0"/>
</Feat>
<Feat ID="362" Author="" Copyright="COPYRIGHT 2001, Eric D. Harry" Reference="Net Book of Feats">
  <Name>Whirlwind Defense</Name>
  <Types Types="">
  </Types>
  <Prerequisites>Dex 13+, Dodge, Mobility, Spring Attack, base attack bonus +4 or higher.</Prerequisites>
  <Benefit>When flanked in melee combat, your opponents subtract 2 from their flanking bonus to attack rolls and can only make sneak attacks against you if their character level is higher than yours.</Benefit>
  <Normal>Attackers in flanking position gain a +2 bonus on attack rolls and can make sneak attacks against you.</Normal>
  <Source ID="0"/>
</Feat>
<Feat ID="363" Author="" Copyright="COPYRIGHT 2001, Eric D. Harry" Reference="Net Book of Feats">
  <Name>Whirlwind Strike</Name>
  <Types Types="">
  </Types>
  <Prerequisites>Wis 13+, Dex 13+, Dodge, Mobility, Spring Attack, Improved Unarmed Strike, base attack bonus +4 or higher.</Prerequisites>
  <Benefit>When performing the full attack action, you give up all of your attacks and can instead make one unarmed attack against each opponent within 5 feet at your full base attack bonus.</Benefit>
  <Special>Monks may use this feat when unarmed or when armed with a kama, nunchaku or siangham.</Special>
  <Notes>This is a modified form of the standard Whirlwind Attack feat adjusted for use by Monks and characters adept in unarmed combat.  Characters cannot combine this feat with use of any weapon except as outlined above.</Notes>
  <Source ID="0"/>
</Feat>
<Feat ID="364" Author="" Copyright="COPYRIGHT 2001, Carl Cramér" Reference="Net Book of Feats">
  <Name>Wild Rider</Name>
  <Types Types="">
  </Types>
  <Prerequisites>Ride skill.</Prerequisites>
  <Benefit>You suffer no penalty to your ride skill when riding bareback. Nor is your ride skill rank reduced when you ride different types of animals.</Benefit>
  <Normal>The normal penalty for riding bareback is -5. When your ride a mount other than the one your initially learned the ride skill for, your skill rank is reduced by two or five depending on how different they are.</Normal>
  <Source ID="0"/>
</Feat>
<Feat ID="365" Author="" Copyright="COPYRIGHT 2001, Eric D. Harry" Reference="Net Book of Feats">
  <Name>Zealous Smite</Name>
  <Types Types="">
  </Types>
  <Prerequisites>Smite class ability (Smite Evil, Smite Good, Smite Infidel, etc.).</Prerequisites>
  <Benefit>You can use your Smite class ability one additional time per day, but you can only Smite a specific opponent once per day.</Benefit>
  <Special>A character can choose this feat multiple times, gaining one additional Smite attack each time that this feat is chosen.</Special>
  <Source ID="0"/>
</Feat>

</feats>